[wind blowing]
[man] It's Halloween.
You know what that means.
Old Sawtooth Jack is gonna
rise from the cornfields
and try to make its way to
the church before midnight.
It's gotta be stopped.
Kill or be killed.
[leaves rustling]
'Cause see,
out here,
where the wind
blows fierce
and the dust
rolls in...
you gotta give something
to get something back.
It's what has to be done.
What's always been done.
But you already
know about this.
After all,
you grew up here.
You know the story
as well as I do.
[ominous music playing]
[boy panting]
[sneezing]
[sniffles]
[eerie music playing]
[boys shouting]
[boy 1] Over there.
Okay. Look, look, look.
-[boy screaming in distance]
-[boy 2] Come on. Come on.
[boy 3] I think
I saw something.
[faint growling]
[boy breathing heavily]
[wheezing]
[gasps]
-[wheezing]
-[whimpers, grunts]
[panting]
[growling]
[boy screaming]
[ominous music playing]
[creature growling]
There!
[boys shouting]
[boy] Let's go!
-[blade slices]
-[boy chokes]
[tense music playing]
[church bell tolling]
[boy] Over there!
It's Jim! It's Jim!
-[boys shouting]
-[boy] Come on, Jim!
[boys yelling]
[boys cheering]
-[flesh squelching]
-Get him! Get him! Get him!
Whoo!
[panting]
[grunts]
[boys grunting]
[Jim] Whoo!
[boys howling]
[boys chanting]
Jim's the winner!
Yeah!
[boys]
Jim's the winner!
Whoo!
[boys]
Jim's the winner!
[man] We,
the Harvester's Guild,
present to you,
the Shepard family,
a fresh start.
A brand new beginning
in a new model home.
[cheering and applauding]
Thanks to
your brave service,
we can now move beyond
the darkness of this...
[sighs]
...unfortunate night.
And move optimistically
into another long
and fruitful year
of peace,
prosperity,
and prize crops.
[laughs]
[crowd cheering and applauding]
With you, Jim,
as our emissary
to the larger world,
riding high
in a brand new,
shiny...
-[keys jingle]
-Corvette.
[crowd cheering]
Well, let the midnight dance
begin!
["Teenage Heaven" playing]
♪ I want a house with a pool ♪
♪ Shorter hours in school ♪
♪ And a room
With my own private phone ♪
♪ I wanna stay up
All night... ♪
[Jim] I'll write soon.
Take me with you.
♪ No more troubles... ♪
Come here.
♪ ...Or worries at home ♪
I love you, Baby B.
♪ Mmm, just gimme
Some time on my hands ♪
[crowd cheering]
♪ I wanna make
My own private plans ♪
[crowd cheering]
♪ ...My own Coupe de Ville ♪
♪ Make my dad pay the bill ♪
♪ Yeah, man
That's heaven to me ♪
There ain't no stop signs
on the black road!
-[Jim laughs]
-[car engine revs]
["Watusi Zombie" playing
on car radio]
[radio static]
[radio channels glitching]
["Weird" playing]
-[firecrackers exploding]
-[woman screams]
[boy chuckling]
Oh, fuck, dude!
Damn these kids!
[Ricks] The reaper
that grows in the field.
The trick
with a heart
made of treats.
[school bell rings]
[students chattering]
The butchering nightmare
with the saw teeth...
And he's gonna get you.
That's what they always
told you.
He's gonna get you...
So, you know
you've been got.
[all laughing]
[Ricks] Laugh it up.
No, get it all out
now 'cause,
this is not
a fucking game!
One of your classmates
will certainly die.
That thing grows
all year long in our fields,
only to rise up
every Halloween night
with a single,
solitary purpose.
To destroy
our way of life.
Hey, we're gonna
win this thing.
Get the slide.
[projector clicks]
You've all heard
the stories
about that one time
we failed at our duties.
And that black duster
rolled in and destroyed
our crops, our lives.
It must die,
so we can live.
Your sacred duty,
is to take down
Sawtooth Jack
before that church bell
rings at midnight.
And to get you
fat little nancies ready,
we make you
hungry for it.
Three days.
No food, no mommy,
no nothing.
Locked up alone
in your bedrooms
to sit and think long and hard
about what you have to do.
And on
the night of the Run,
when one of you
fulfills your duty,
you all will fill
your bellies full.
Now the fun stuff.
Thank you, Officer Ricks.
So...
Who wants
to be the coolest kid
with the hottest car
in town?
Chevrolet Corvette, 1964.
-Next year's model.
- [students exclaim]
[man] Winner
of this year's Run
gets the keys
to this beautiful tank of gas,
and some traveling
around money.
A gift from
the Harvester's Guild.
Jim Shepard,
last year's winner,
he, uh...
he's out in California.
Seeing the world. Now...
[boy 1] The fuck
is he doing here?
Oh.
His big brother won,
and now he thinks
he's Mr. Westside.
Gets a chickenshit waiver.
-I'm doing it.
-[chuckles mockingly]
Who fucking volunteers
to do the Run?
Huh? We all...
We don't have a choice.
[boy 2] Some of us do.
They can force us
to do the Run,
but no one can force me
to kill anything.
Shut up, pinko.
[boy 3] This whole thing
is horseshit.
It's rigged.
Sawtooth, too.
You really think
that's friggin' real?
Officer Friendly there?
He buses in
a boogie inmate
from the Dixie Springs
Correctional.
I heard this, too.
He stuffs his britches
full of candy,
puts on a big fat pumpkin,
on his woolly head...
and boo.
[boys chuckle]
[boy 4] I saw it.
It's real.
When was this?
When I was nine.
[sighs] My mom, she, uh,
told me not to look outside,
no matter what I heard.
But... [sighs]
I looked outside
my window anyway.
He was there.
Who?
[wheezing]
-Sawtooth Jack.
-[growls]
I saw it.
On my neighbor's porch,
in the old Partridge place,
before they moved
to the Westside...
[boy 1] Shut the fuck up.
Beaner.
[all laughing]
What do you know about
doin' the Run?
Mexicans ain't even
allowed to win.
-Fuck you.
-Bullshit, says who?
Whoa, Westside Boy
getting mad now.
Get bent.
-[groans]
-[Ricks] Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
[all clamoring]
You don't belong here.
Come on.
Out!
[rock music playing]
[panting]
[Kelly] The movie
already started.
[Richie] No, I know.
I, uh...
You hiding?
What?
No.
I, uh, wanted a snack.
Most kids go to Waltons.
Waltons doesn't
have jujubes.
We don't have jujubes.
Right.
[hesitates] You know...
Can I just have a small
buttered popcorn?
Riley Blaike
is a real asshole.
Who?
On the house.
Really?
Why not?
Betcha.
You're Jim Shepard's brother.
You're the new girl.
I know a lot
about your brother, but...
I don't know anything
about you.
I'm hard to pin down.
[chuckles]
Sure. [chuckles]
Could I get me a pop, too?
You know what?
I've never met someone
from somewhere else before.
Where you from?
[sighs]
Another small town.
[Richie scoffs]
You're not going
on a trip, are you?
One day.
Are you going
to the midnight dance?
I'm not invited.
Why not?
Well, after I win the Run,
I'll make sure
you get invited.
You can duck into the movie,
if you want. It just started.
Nah. I should really...
Dig you later.
[Kelly sighs]
[Kelly]
Be careful out there.
-That girl is trouble.
-Who?
The betty
you're makin' eyes at.
She's fuckin' bad news.
Burned down
Old Man Bagley's barn.
The one we used
to throw rocks at?
-Where'd you hear that?
-Pat Shanley.
Says she lit up that old
mine shaft, too,
over on Route 12.
Hey, you better
watch yourself, man.
She's got an axe to grind.
This way.
[doorbell tinkling]
Oh.
Hear your brother's
up in Santa Clara.
What's he doin' up there?
Seeing the world, I guess.
[storeowner] Well,
they got a great
varsity team.
When are you gonna
play ball, aye?
Not my thing.
[storeowner] Well,
if you have half
the arm your brother has,
we'd be in good shape. Hey.
You oughta think about it.
You know,
maybe he
is up in Santa
whatever, I dunno,
who fucking cares?
[bell tolling]
I don't wanna go home.
-Let's breeze outta here.
-Hey, so...
What?
It's curfew.
Don't be such
a pantywaist, Bud.
Come on,
come smoke with us.
But it's curfew.
[scoffs] What?
See you guys tomorrow?
[Richie] So that's
your big idea?
Come on, man.
You should do it.
You know I'm not allowed.
Fuck it. Just 'cause
your brother won
the Run last year?
Look, Jim's
a great guy and all...
-but you're faster.
-I know that.
-Tougher.
-You know...
Try telling that to my folks,
all right?
They worship the ground
my brother walks on.
It's embarrassing. [spits]
If I was to make a bet...
Scout's honor?
I'd pick you
over your brother
to win the Run any day.
You really mean that?
Really?
Shit, I say we
do it together, man,
You and me, let's do it.
You know, and then
I can move into
your neighborhood again.
We can live next door
to each other,
just like before.
Like nothing's changed,
you know?
[bell tolling in distance]
We better get going.
[chains rattling]
[sign board creaking]
[wind blowing]
[Donna singing along to radio]
♪ Gonna build me a daydream♪
♪ With a little hope ♪
♪ Gonna push that daydream
Up the mountain slope ♪
Dear Lord, bless this food
and grant that we may
thankful for thy mercies be.
Amen.
-Amen.
-[Donna sighs]
Oh.
This came for you today.
[Richie] This is it?
No letter, no nothing?
I saw Annie last night.
At... At Bible study.
Poor gal. She still holds
a flame for Jimmy.
And who can
blame her, really?
It's not her fault.
She doesn't have the same kind
of opportunities that we do.
You're very lucky.
So I've heard.
-Watch your tone, boy.
-[boy] What?
She talks like we weren't
living on the East Side
just a year ago.
When he comes home
for Christmas,
Jimmy will have
to set Annie straight.
I'd hate to see that girl
get her heart broken,
but...
Been doing a lot
of thinking lately.
Thinking about what?
Doing the Run, maybe.
Why would you say that?
Jim got to do it.
Why can't I?
Because your brother won.
So?
Richie, listen to me.
Everything you see,
all this,
the house, the car...
We already have it.
You can't win it again, son.
It's not... It's not fair
to the other boys,
-and the other families.
-Donna. Donna.
What you want,
it doesn't matter.
And you know this.
You know this.
So I need to
hear you tell me
why it does not matter
what you want?
Tell me right now
because why?
-[loudly] Because why?
-Because it's against the--
Because it's against
the rules, that's right.
Fuck the rules.
-[slaps]
-[Donna gasps]
[Dan exhales] I...
I'm the bad kid?
-Sorry.
-Is that it?
I'm the bad kid,
and Jim's the good kid?
I'm just supposed to be
thankful and lucky
for the rest of my life?
For what?
This big house
and your shitty Cadillac?
I'm good at things, too,
you know.
Please sit down.
I'm smart.
You're my baby boy.
[breathing heavily]
Richie, please.
I'm doing the Run.
You can't stop me.
[Dan] Richie.
["Since I Don't Have You"
playing]
♪ I don't have anything♪
-[increases volume]
-♪ Since I don't have you♪
♪ I don't have fond desires♪
♪ And I don't have
Happy hours♪
♪ I don't have anything♪
♪ Since I don't have you♪
[Annie] Hi, Richie.
You're homesick
for the East Side?
[Richie] Annie.
♪ I never will again♪
[Annie]
Got a postcard today.
♪ When you walked out on me♪
♪ In walked old misery♪
♪ And he's been here
Since then♪
I've always wanted
to go to New Orleans.
♪ I...♪
[song ends]
[crickets chirping]
[eerie music playing]
[dogs barking in a distance]
[rustling]
[birds chirping]
[Riley] Hey, asshole.
-[grunts]
-[Richie groaning]
You think you're better
than me, huh?
[Richie groans]
You think you're special,
smart guy, huh?
[Riley grunts]
[Riley exclaims]
What's this? What's this?
I'll be taking this.
[Richie] No. No. No.
Give it back.
You don't have
the stones.
[both grunting]
[Richie groaning]
-[Riley punching]
-[Richie groaning]
[Richie grunts]
Whoo! [panting]
How are you
Jim Shepard's brother?
[spits]
-[both laugh]
-[Riley] Whoo!
[slow pensive music playing]
[Jim] " I looked
up one day and...
saw it was one year later
and I thought,
'Hey, Baby B
must be 18 by now.'
Happy belated.
So, you're probably
sore at me
for not writing
a proper letter sooner,
and I'm sorry about that.
I can't have you come out
right now, not just yet.
All this traveling
and seeing the country
can get pretty lonely.
I think about coming
back home sometimes.
Maybe get hitched
to good old Annie,
if she'd take me back.
Get a job at the mill.
Settle down for good.
Ah, but heck,
I can't come home now
with everyone thinking
I'm some hero or something.
I know every dumbass kid
wants to be tough
and prove himself, but...
if I were you,
I'd just stay put."
[breathes heavily]
"Winning the Run
ain't everything."
[applause]
"I'll be home soon,
I promise you that,
okay?
Just be good for now
and watch after
Mom and Dad.
They need you."
There ain't no stop signs
on the black road!
-[Jim laughs]
-[car engine revs]
[crushing can]
[tires screeching]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Ricks on speaker]
Where do you think
you're going?
Get out of the car, Richie.
[sighs]
Shit.
[suspenseful music continues]
[Richie grunting]
-[whacks]
-[Richie groans]
[whacks]
[Ricks exhales]
[woman singing on TV]
♪ Lately when I'm in my room♪
♪ All by myself♪
♪ In the solitary gloom♪
♪ I call to myself♪
♪ Hey, there♪
♪ You with the stars
In your eyes♪
♪ Love never made a fool...♪
-[banging on door]
-[Bud] Mom.
♪ You used to be too wise... ♪
[banging on door]
[boy 1] Let me out!
Let me out!
[boy 2]
Open the fucking door!
I don't wanna do the Run!
♪ Though he won't throw
a crumb to you♪
[growls]
♪ You think some day
He'll come to you...♪
Let me out
of this fucking room!
-Open the fucking door!
-Let me out!
I'm fucking starving!
[boy 3] I know
you fucking hear me!
[boy 4] I fucking hate you!
I fucking hate you!
[Bud] Mom! Dad!
[panting]
I'm so fucking hungry.
Just a slice of bread.
A glass of water.
Anything!
-Please!
-Let me out!
Let me out! [screaming]
Let me out!
[boys grunting and growling]
Open the fucking door!
I said open
the fucking door!
I'm so fucking hungry!
[boys screaming hysterically]
[eerie music playing]
[creature wheezing]
[locks and doors unlocking]
[rock music playing]
[exhales]
[all clamoring]
Think he'll make it?
He'll make it.
You got yourself a pretty bad
bump on the head, boy.
How long was I out?
Three days.
Whoa, whoa. Easy.
Listen. Joe Grant,
I spoke to him...
And I got a job for you
over at the Perry Mill
right after you graduate.
And then you can
start working there
full time.
I'm doing the Run.
Just...
You're not hearing me, son.
You're gonna listen to me.
-[groans]
-Come here, son. No.
No, no, no. Richie.
[grunting]
Richie!
[Donna] Your favorite.
I just made them.
Pray with me.
Let me go.
Let. Me. Go.
[church bell tolling]
-[rock music playing]
-[boys screaming wildly]
[bells continue tolling]
You guys have
anything to eat?
My old man
found my stash.
I'd cut my fuckin' nuts off
for a Twinkie, man.
[boys] Whoo!
[Dillon] Shit!
-[brakes screech]
-[Dillon] Fuck!
Crenshaw
and his rattletrap.
[Larry] Hey,
that ain't playing fair.
He can't drive a friggin'
truck, can he?
[Dillon]
You're not allowed
to do that.
Says who,
ya fuckin' square?
[Dillon] Says me!
-Get out!
-[Dillon] We'll see.
[boy 1] Run!
[boy 2] Run!
-Try it again.
-[engine sputtering]
[Richie] You're giving
it too much gas.
There he is.
[boy 1] Come on!
-You made it.
-Who do you think
you're dealin' with?
[boy 2] Where'd it go?
[banging]
The fuck hell
you doin', huh?
[Dillon] You think
you're tough?
Huh?
-[Dillon] Oh, yeah.
-Y'all just pissed off
you didn't think of it
yourselves, losers.
Give it a little gas,
not a lot.
[engine starts]
There we go.
Hey, back off!
All of youse!
[indistinct shouting]
[boys growling hungrily]
See ya at
the dance, fuckos.
Hey, screw you, Crenshaw,
you cheat!
Hey, get your ass
out of that truck
and on the street!
[Mitch whooping]
[boys] Whoo!
[mimicking pig squealing]
[mimicking goat bleating]
[boys clamoring]
Here. These are for you.
You guys ready?
Come on...
Come on
to the violent world
with me.
[menacing music playing]
-[distant explosion]
-[indistinct shouting]
[Bud] My mom
gave me a sleeping pill.
With warm milk.
And honey.
[Mitch] What the hell
are you talking about?
I was wide awake.
I could hear
the older boys outside,
hunting for it like dogs.
[Richie] You okay, Bud?
I saw it.
Saw Sawtooth rise up,
floating over some kid,
some older kid,
and I was waving at him,
yelling.
Trying to warn him, but...
[Richie] What's the matter
with you?
It was too late.
He turned around and...
-[thud]
-[Mitch] Shit!
[tires screeching]
-[all breathing heavily]
-[Richie] Fuck!
[engine stalling]
-[Mitch] Shit!
-[Richie] Where'd it go?
[Bud] Could be... Could be
the whole thing's over.
Could be, right?
[Mitch] It ain't over.
Come on.
[Richie] I'm good.
[all panting]
[Mitch]
Skid marks start here.
[panting]
[Mitch] See if there's
any more footprints
down in that ditch.
[Richie] Shine the light
up there.
[Charlie panting]
[Mitch] Hey, don't!
[Mitch] Kill first.
Eat later.
Remember?
[Charlie]
I'm so fucking hungry.
You must've hit him, Mitch.
Busted him open
like a pinata.
-[boys chuckle]
-You won.
[Richie] Where's the body?
-Hey, hey. [shushes]
-[growling in distance]
[breathing heavily]
[Bud] What?
[shushes]
[leaves rustling]
[eerie music playing]
There!
[tense music playing]
[Charlie screams]
[Sawtooth Jack wheezing]
-[blade slices]
-[Charlie screams]
[Richie] Charlie?
Charlie?
[shouts] Charlie?
-[Charlie breathing heavily]
-[Richie] Charlie!
[breathing heavily]
[Richie] Charlie?
Bud, no!
-[rustling]
-[Sawtooth Jack wheezing]
[Charlie screams]
[squelching]
[Richie panting]
[Richie] Charlie!
-[blade slices]
-[Charlie screaming]
-[Richie gasps]
-[body thuds]
[Richie breathing shakily]
[Richie] There!
[both panting]
-[Sawtooth Jack snarls]
-[blood spurting]
Richie...
[body thuds]
[Sawtooth Jack wheezing]
[wind blowing]
[ominous music playing]
[breath trembling]
[screeches]
-[tense music playing]
-[panting heavily]
[breathing heavily]
[groans]
[exhales]
[rustling]
[shushes]
Let's go.
Bud?
[Bud breathing heavily]
Bud, where you going?
God.
You saw it?
Did you kill it?
Then let's go kill it.
Hey, hey.
Don't go that way.
You're gonna want
a better weapon
than that, trust me.
-Like what?
-Like a fucking gun.
Do you have a gun?
Here.
Hey.
-You can't win this alone.
-[scoffs]
What? You want
the prize money
when I win it?
-Is that it?
-No.
I don't give a shit
about the prize money.
Then why are you
doing this?
Girls aren't even allowed
to do the Run.
[Kelly] Neither are you.
Fuck the rules.
Fuck 'em.
I got an idea.
[Sawtooth Jack growling]
[breathing heavily]
[sobbing]
-Mommy, please. Let me in.
-[boys whooping]
Mommy, please.
Mom, let me in. Please.
Do us proud. Now.
I don't wanna die, Mom.
-Do us proud. Go.
-Mommy.
Mommy, please.
We need this.
Okay, honey?
[Bud's dad] Hey, hey.
Be a man!
[Bud crying]
-Do me proud.
-Mommy.
[door closes and locks]
[sobbing]
[child muffled] Bud!
Bud! Bud!
Bud!
Watch out!
Look out!
Bud!
Look out behind you!
Look out behind you, Bud!
Sawtooth is behind you!
[faded, echoing voice]
Please! Please!
Sawtooth's behind you!
Sawtooth is behind
you, Bud! Look out!
-[Sawtooth Jack wheezing]
-[breath trembling]
[tense music playing]
[panting]
It's Bud. Let me in.
-Let me in!
-[boy] There's no room.
I'm not big, come on.
-Let me in.
-[boy] Twenty bucks.
I don't have 20 bucks.
That's what everyone
else paid, so...
I'll pay you back tomorrow,
first thing, promise.
-Just... Just...
-Cash up front, man.
-That's the deal.
-Please.
Look, it wouldn't be fair
to everyone if...
[Sawtooth Jack wheezing]
-[gasps]
-No, no. Let me in.
Let me in!
Open the door!
-Open the door!
-Turn off the lights.
-[Bud] Open the door!
Turn off the lights!
[banging on door]
[banging stops]
[boys whimpering]
[banging on door]
[Bud] Help me! Help me!
Let me in!
Please, let me in!
[boys murmuring]
Don't open it.
He... He's hurt.
Shouldn't we...
-I'm not opening it.
-[Bud] Please... help me.
-We can't just let him die.
-I'm not opening it!
-We have to help him.
-No. Don't.
-We gotta get him
outta there.
-No fuckin' way.
-[Bud] Please! Please!
-[boy] Stop!
[growls]
[Bud screaming]
[boys screaming]
[tense music playing]
[imperceptible]
[boy panting]
I wanna go home.
What are we doing here?
[windchimes tinkling]
Keep an eye out.
[Kelly sighs]
[gasps]
[tires screech]
[banging on door]
[panting]
Jesus!
Take this.
This is why
we stopped here?
[tires screech]
That's my dad.
Your dad?
Why did your dad
come here?
Come on.
-Whose house is that?
-[knocking on door]
[Richie] Officer...
Dick's.
[banging on door]
You wanna go for a ride?
[car engine starts]
Get your pansy ass out here!
You thought
I wouldn't find out, huh?
I got eyes and ears
everywhere, Chief.
I know every single
goddamn thing
-that's going on this here--
-[car door closes]
Do not!
[engine revving]
[gunshots]
Fuck!
[Richie laughs]
[car horn honking]
Where did you learn
how to do that?
I know things.
Okay.
So...
What's the plan?
That was my plan.
Get a gun.
[woman over radio]
Jer, you there? Over.
Jerry, the burglar alarm
at Jarrett's
is ringing like crazy.
There's some big commotion
going on over there
on Main Street.
Someone said
they spotted Sawtooth.
[indistinct shouting]
[glass shattering]
[alarm ringing]
What the fuck? Get back!
Get... Hey.
Get back. Get back.
[boy 1] Give us
a fucking sandwich.
[shotgun fires]
[boys howling]
Get back!
-[shotgun fires]
-[groans]
[growls] Is that all
ya got, savages?
-[boys barking]
-Back!
[boy yells]
[whack]
[groans]
[body thuds]
Oh. Oh.
Oh, fuck off.
[squelching]
[boy] My dad's
gonna kill me.
Jesus Christ.
[Kelly] We better move.
-[Riley] A girl?
-[gasps]
The fuck is all this?
[struggling]
Hey...
What are you doing,
Shepard?
Let her go.
Wait...
[chuckles] Wait
a pick-a-ninny minute here.
Are you making it
with a Negro?
[struggling]
Let her go...
now.
Uh...
Why don't you fight
me for her?
[Kelly grunting]
[boy screams]
Ugh! You little bitch!
-[groans]
-[Richie grunts]
-[Richie grunting]
-[nose cracks]
My nose. My nose.
[Kelly winces]
You got a gun?
I got a gun.
That's not fair.
That's a gun.
And she's a girl.
And I'm a Negro.
With a club.
[grunting]
That fair enough for you?
I'll be taking this.
[Richie] Let's go.
[boys] Whoo!
You're looking at
this year's winner
of the Run.
Any of youse doubt it?
[boy] Yeah! Yeah!
What about you, copper?
Think you got what it takes?
Come and get it.
-[squelch]
-[all exclaiming]
[boys laughing]
[howling]
Front for a rock band
in Jersey?
Where'd you hear that?
It's what
everyone's saying.
No. No one is saying that.
I heard he got an album
coming out.
[chuckling]
Teenagers From Mars.
Jim Shepard
is not in a rock band,
okay?
He couldn't carry a tune
even if he...
[Sawtooth Jack wheezing]
[thuds]
[growling]
[Richie] "HG."
What is that, like,
"The Harvester's Guild,"
maybe?
[Kelly] They own
the movie theater.
[Richie]
They own everything.
If you wanna leave town,
even for a vacation,
I heard you have to ask
for the Guild's permission.
[Kelly scoffs]
That can't be true.
You're not like
other girls around here,
that's for sure.
Let's try this.
What do you know about me?
What have you heard?
[Richie clicks tongue]
People say you're...
[scoffs] Uh...
What?
I don't know.
Pat Shanley says
you burned down
Old Man Bagley's barn.
Why would I do that?
I don't know.
That's stupid.
Forget it.
It doesn't matter.
What else have you heard?
Pat Shanley also said
you burned down
the old mine shaft, too.
Who is this Pat Shanley?
He's got a big mouth.
I mean, is that what
people are saying,
that I'm some
kind of pyromaniac?
It doesn't matter.
They're lying.
Okay.
Hey, look,
I didn't believe him, okay?
And it doesn't matter,
either.
I mean, who cares, right?
This town?
People talk. They like to run their mouths
about things they know nothing about.
I know.
Like my brother?
Everybody's got
their own opinion
about where he's at,
what he's doing.
Like he's some sort of...
hero.
But Jim,
he was just my brother,
you know?
He's just a normal kid
like me. Nothing special.
I mean, he played baseball
real good. Sure.
But even after some big game,
he still found time
to hang out with me.
Work on cars.
We really liked
to work on cars.
We were more like
best friends.
Where is he now?
I don't know.
He doesn't want
to be found, I guess.
I get that.
[sighs heavily]
My parents are dead.
Car accident.
Last summer.
My dad, he lived here
long before I was born.
He never talked
about this place,
except how he never
wanted to come back.
So...
After the war,
he settled
somewhere else.
Met my mom,
had me.
That's why
I was sent here.
I live with
my auntie now and...
[sighs] She don't like me
all that much, you know?
She thinks I'm wild.
Wild?
I burned down
Old Man Bagley's barn.
Oh.
He called me
a nasty name.
He had it coming.
What about
the old mine shaft?
That was just for fun.
-Bitchin'.
-[both laugh]
[woman over radio]
Jer, are you there? Over.
Jerry, I just got a call.
Sawtooth was spotted alone,
hiding over on Oak Street
in front of the Guild's
Country Club.
It's getting
close to midnight,
so you might want to tip off
some of the boys
to his location. Over.
Good work, Edith.
I owe you one.
[chuckles] You betcha.
[owl hooting]
[wind howling]
[suspenseful music playing]
Jesus.
[wind howling]
[Sawtooth Jack growling]
-[snarls]
-[gun cocks]
[inaudible dialog]
[growling]
-[screams]
-[Sawtooth Jack screeches]
[smack]
[Kelly groans]
[man] The hell's
going on out here?
[groans]
You get your ass
back out there. Now!
[Kelly groaning]
[exhales] What the hell
happened to you back there?
Stupid.
I'm so fucking stupid.
Why didn't you...
All these boys...
-[gun cocking]
-[Ricks] Don't fucking move.
Out of the car now.
[Richie] You know
somethin', Ricks?
I don't think I care much
for this Podunk town anymore.
[Ricks yells] Out!
[softly] Of the car.
[sighs] This guy's
stuck in one gear.
You.
[laughs]
Kelly Haines.
I know you.
I knew your mommy
and your daddy, too.
Ooh, he had a lip on him,
your dad.
He tried to get away
by jumping the line, but...
I caught up with him. Hmm?
They thought they
could get away, too.
See how that turned out.
[both grunting]
-[gun fires]
-[ears ringing]
-[Ricks yells]
-[Kelly groans]
[both grunting]
-Go, go!
-[Ricks screaming in pain]
You mother...
Fuck!
[Donna]
♪ S tarlight lies♪
Richie, you came home.
Who's your friend?
Get some ice and towels.
[Kelly groans]
Do it!
Here.
[Donna singing softly]
♪ Starlight lies♪
♪ With sweet dream eyes♪
♪ Gonna build me a daydream♪
[Donna sniffles]
[Richie] Who won the Run
the year before Jimmy?
Curtis Johnson, of course.
Where is he now?
Somewhere East.
East of Eden,
was the name of the book
he wrote, I think.
He's a famous writer now.
That can't be right.
[chuckles softly]
And the year before that?
Bobby Rokos.
What happened to him?
-[growling]
-[Donna] He died
in a terrible car accident.
You know that.
[Richie] And the year
before that?
[Donna] Doug Steckles.
You remember.
[Richie] What happened
to Doug Steckles?
[Donna] Richie,
I don't understand.
Why all the questions?
[Jim] There ain't
no stop signs
on the black road!
[boys chanting]
Jim's the winner!
[growling]
[chanting continues]
I need you
to be honest with me.
Okay.
Don't lie.
Lie?
Did you write the letter?
What letters?
The letter from the other day,
did you write that?
The postcards?
Did you pretend you were Jim
to get me to stay home?
Mom, please.
[chuckles]
No. I...
Honey, why would I do that?
Please. Come on. Tell me.
-[laughs]
-Mom.
[Donna] Are you sure you
don't want another cupcake?
Mom.
Let me get you some milk.
[sighs]
[Donna singing]
♪ Starlight lies ♪
♪ With sweet dream eyes...♪
Mom!
Tell me the truth.
Please.
It has to end.
Mom?
Put an end to it, Richie.
-[stabs knife]
-[tense music playing]
Mom? What the fuck!
[screeching]
[Ricks] What now?
[Dan] I'm not doing it.
I've had enough.
There's only so much
a man can take before...
Yeah, you're gonna do
what needs to be done.
And that's that.
[Dan sighs]
[Ricks scoffs]
This fucking night.
You and your wife,
you like living in that
big house you're living in?
Hmm?
It's...
not worth it.
Casey.
You remember
my brother Casey?
When Casey went missing,
my old man,
he marched straight out
into that dust storm
to go look for him.
For hours, me and my sister
were alone in that house,
the wind rattling at
the walls, the windows...
And when that black duster
finally passed, days later...
I found my big brother.
He was a hundred yards
from the front door, just...
lying there,
bloated...
An arm reaching out
for our house.
And when my old man
fell to his knees
and lifted his eldest
into his arms...
Casey's body,
it split open
and sand poured
out of his belly.
That freak
made it to the church
before midnight
one goddamn time...
and for nine
long fuckin' years
this town went
a little mad,
and all because of some
panty waisted daddy
who didn't have the stones
to do what needed to be done.
[Dan groans]
-Are you that guy, Dan?
-[groaning]
-Huh?
-[crying]
If that thing isn't dead
by midnight,
this whole goddamn town
is going straight to Hell,
and your wife and that
piece of shit son of yours
-are gonna find themselves...
-[groans loudly]
...buried in a cornfield
somewhere.
[Dan breathing heavily]
[crying]
-He's your responsibility.
-[sighs]
Huh?
Get it done.
[taps car]
[Kelly sighs]
[Kelly] We could sneak out.
While everyone is preoccupied
with the Run,
we could leave.
Get out. Just...
Run away.
Let's run away, Richie.
No.
Why not? Let's just go.
Get out of this
fucking place now.
If he gets to the church
in time, then...
There will be no winner...
To sacrifice.
[Kelly sighs]
I'm ending this.
Tonight.
I'm coming with you.
[Edith over radio]
Jer, we got a call on a fire
over on Maple Avenue.
The old Shepard house,
I think. Over.
I'm on my way.
Over and out.
[boys growling and shouting]
[brakes screeching]
[boys whooping]
-Whoa, hey.
-[Ricks] Relax.
The hell do you want?
-[breathing heavily] Sawtooth.
-Huh?
I just saw him. He's...
He's a couple blocks over,
-in front of the Healy place.
-[distant explosion]
[chaotic shouting]
Everything's gone
nuts tonight.
-Get in the car.
-What?
Get in the car!
Where are we going?
Congratulations, kid.
You're this year's
big winner.
[boy 1] What the...
[boy 2] Come on.
Let's go look.
[Richie] Where'd everyone go?
Do you see anything?
[Kelly] No.
Let's check inside.
[door opens]
[door closes]
Dad?
What are you doing here?
[Dan] Just doing
what has to be done.
I know the truth.
Not all of it.
I'm going to save him.
Richie, I need you
to listen to--
I'm going to end
all of it.
Listen!
There's no winning
this thing, son.
If that...
thing...
walks through the church door
before midnight, I--
Say his name.
I came here to stop...
Say his name!
I...
[ominous music playing]
[growls]
[Richie] Say his name!
Say. His. Name.
Jim.
Your brother.
My son.
I came here to...
To stop my own son.
He has to lose. Again...
Knowing what you knew...
Richie, I swear to you,
I didn't know
anything at first.
When Jim won the Run,
your mother and I...
We were thrilled.
Then we were brought
into the Guild
and we were
told the truth.
And we were
sworn to secrecy
and that was that.
That was that.
I never had a say
in any of this, Richie.
None of us did.
-Not me. Not your mother--
-Why didn't we just leave?
Because they
would have killed us!
If you're born in this town,
you're cursed.
They would have
murdered us.
-No one can ever leave, son.
-Who?
-They'll...
[Kelly] Ricks.
The Harvester's Guild.
[Dan] Richie, look at me.
Look at me, son.
Tonight, some other boy
will win the Run
and we will move on.
You understand me?
We will move on.
And our family will no longer
have to suffer--
But somebody has to die.
Yes.
But not you.
Someone who's
not in my family.
Mom's dead.
Tell me.
What could be worse
than losing your own son?
-Your wife?
-[crying]
All for what?
A big house?
Is that it?
Is that all
you care about?
You all were willing to
sacrifice your own sons
for a fucking Cadillac?
[Dan crying]
You disgust me.
[bell tolling]
Richie, Richie.
No. Richie.
Richie. Richie!
Wait!
[suspenseful music playing]
[GROWLS]
It's okay.
Jim, it's okay.
-It's okay, Jim.
-[growls]
Come on.
It's me.
It's okay.
Come on.
-[gun fires]
-[screeches]
No!
[wheezing]
-[Kelly grunting]
-[groans]
Goddamn it.
[Richie]
Come on. Come on.
[Ricks] Get up.
-Get it done.
-[grunts]
[Richie] Come on.
Come on. Come on!
-Come on. Come on. Come on.
-[wheezing]
Let's go. Come on.
Come on.
-[gunshot]
-[shrieks loudly]
No. No, no, no, no.
[wheezing]
Me. Who? Me.
I've never thought
I'd win the Run.
[Sawtooth Jack wheezing]
No, I can't.
I'll do it!
You don't fucking
touch him.
-[trembling]
-[Sawtooth Jack wheezing]
[bell tolling]
No. No, no, no.
[sobbing]
I'm sorry.
[gunshot echoes]
[imperceptible cheering]
[all cheering]
Well, I'll be...
Congratulations, kid.
[boy 1] Richie. Richie!
-[boy 2] Damn, Richie!
-I'll be taking that.
[boys chanting]
Richie's the winner!
[chanting continues faintly]
["Since I Don't Have You"
playing]
[chorus vocalizing]
[Ricks sniffles]
[Ricks] Ugh.
♪ I don't...♪
[Ricks]
I gotta hand it to you.
I didn't think you
had it in you.
[laughs]
♪ And I don't have
Hopes and dreams♪
You're gonna be remembered
for a long, long time, Richie.
Future generations
of young boys with big dreams
will look up to you.
You're a hero.
♪ I don't have happiness ♪
♪ And I guess ♪
♪ I never will again♪
♪ When you walked out on me♪
♪ In walked old misery ♪
♪ And he's been here
Since then ♪
♪ I don't have plans
And schemes ♪
♪ And I don't have ♪
♪ Hopes and dreams ♪
♪ I don't have anything♪
♪ Since I don't have you ♪
♪ I don't have love to share♪
♪ And I... ♪
[whispers] Pack your
things and wait for me
at the crossing.
You wanna run away with me?
♪ I don't have anything...♪
Say it.
I want to run away with you.
Where would we go? You and me?
Anywhere.
You just pick a place
in that little book
of yours and we'll go.
Anywhere you want.
They're gonna
come after us.
I know.
We probably won't
make it out.
Maybe not.
I won't stay here
any longer.
No.
Hold me.
♪ I don't have love to share ♪
♪ And I don't have♪
♪ One who cares♪
♪ I don't have anything♪
♪ Since ♪
♪ I don't have ♪
♪ You ♪
[cheering and applauding]
[camera shutter clicking]
[man] Thanks
to your brave service,
we can now move
beyond the darkness
of this unfortunate night.
And move optimistically
into another long
and fruitful year
of peace,
prosperity,
and prize crops.
[cheering and applauding]
[camera shutter clicking]
With you, Richie,
as our emissary
to the larger world,
riding high,
in a brand-new, shiny,
Corvette.
[crowd gasping and exclaiming]
Take it for a spin.
[cheering and applauding]
Take me with you.
Please.
I'll do anything you want.
Richie, please.
There ain't no stop signs
on the black road.
-[car engine starts]
-[all cheering]
[indistinct chatter]
Just doing
what has to be done.
What's always been done.
I've been hearing
that line of bullshit
from you all year long.
You got a backbone
all of a sudden?
I let one son down.
I'm not about to let
another one down.
Oh, boo-fucking-hoo, Dan.
Stand back.
All you had to do
was keep your kid
locked up for one
friggin' night.
[laughs] One night!
But you couldn't even
manage that,
could you now?
I said stand back!
No, your piece of shit son
had to go and prove himself
and win the goddamn Run.
And now I have to put
the little fucker
-into the ground.
-[yells]
[gun fires]
Hey, you weren't followed?
-Not yet.
-[laughs]
-[engine revving]
-[Kelly screams]
[Richie] Whoo!
-Oh, Rich.
-[both laugh]
[Richie sighs]
We're gonna make it.
-[siren blaring]
-Get down.
-Get down. Get down.
-Okay.
[siren continues blaring]
[suspenseful music playing]
-Shit!
-[tires screeching]
What are we gonna do?
[Ricks] Hands up where
I can see 'em!
If I'm not back
in 10 minutes...
leave without me.
Richie, no.
Hands up.
Where I can see 'em!
[grunts]
Let me see 'em!
Whoo.
Walk towards me now.
Walk!
Slowly!
Slowly.
[laughs gleefully]
Huh?
Your old man
tried to save you.
Get your ass over there.
I said get it!
Go on. Move.
You know, you and me,
we never really did
get along, did we?
Hmm.
And yet,
in spite of it all...
I do respect you, Richie.
[clicks tongue]
I ain't a hard guy.
And that's why this is going
to be especially hard--
-[gun fires]
-[groans]
You piece of shit.
It's over.
[laughing]
[groaning]
You killed my brother
and all those boys.
And for what?
[groaning] I was just doing
-what had to be done.
-For who?
That's what's
always been done!
For who?
How does it even
fucking matter anymore?
Huh? Huh?
[gunshot]
[gun thuds]
-[shovel clanks]
-[grunts]
[wind blowing]
[breathing heavily]
[whimpering]
Please.
[screams]
[shoveling dirt]
Please. Stop! Stop!
No. [crying]
[spits]
No!
[tractor engine revving]
[Kelly gasps]
[crying]
[car approaching]
[car door opens, closes]
[breath trembling]
[crying]
-[Dan] Go.
-[gasping]
Get out of here, now.
-[car engine revs]
-Go on.
Please.
Before someone sees you.
Richie.
[crying]
Please.
Fuck you,
and fuck this town.
-[tires screech]
-[car engine revs]
[crying]
[somber music playing]
[rustling]
[ominous music playing]
[wind blowing]
[Dan] Richie.
[breathing heavily]
[Farmer]
What are you doing?
-[squelch]
-[farmer groans]
[thud]
[growling]
Burn it down.
[wheezing]
[growls]
Burn it all down!
[screeching loudly]
[ominous, eerie music playing]