That's how we kill it.
The book of vishanti!
Defender strange:
We can't let it take your power.
Hold on!
Girl: No, no, no!
Defender strange:
It's too strong.
I'm so sorry.
This is the only way.
What're you doing?
But I can.
But in the grand calculus
of the multiverse,
your sacrifice
is worth more than your...
Excuse me. May I?
Thanks.
Doctor west.
I lost both my cats...
And my brother.
I, uh...
did it have to happen that way?
Was there any other path?
No, I made the only play we had.
Well, of course you did.
The best surgeon and the best superhero.
- Ah.
- Little too on the nose?
Congratulations.
Mm. There's Charlie.
I have to introduce you
because he's kind of...
It's embarrassing,
but he's a big fan, so...
I wish I'd have been different.
I never stopped caring about us.
But I had to make sacrifices
I'm sorry.
It was never gonna work out
between us.
Why not?
Because, Stephen,
you have to be the one
holding the knife.
And I always respected you for it,
but I couldn't love you for it.
How long you had that one
in the barrel?
Long time.
Look, um...
Truly, I'm just glad that you're happy.
Christine: Mm.
I am.
I really, really am.
Good.
Are you?
You deserve it.
Dude!
Doctor strange: Thank you.
Wow!
No, no.
Look out!
You're welcome.
You know it's ancient custom
Whoa.
That's incredible.
Christine: Yeah.
Oh, god!
Who's this?
Yeah, I was gonna ask the same question.
Hey, kid.
We'll take her back to the sanc...
She took your slingie.
Woman: Yeah, it was crazy, man.
but what bothers me is that last night,
you were in my dream.
That wasn't a dream.
It was another universe.
How much experience do you guys have
with the multiverse?
We have experience of the multiverse.
Most recently, there was
an incident with spider-man.
What man?
- Hence the name.
- Gross.
Climbs walls, shoots webs.
Well, maybe, I don't know.
Honestly, I hope not.
Girl: Super weird.
You're gonna get a stomach ache.
I'm from another universe.
How do you know my stomach
works the same as yours?
I don't.
which is why I'm still sitting here,
waiting for you
to enlighten us.
You're not my favourite.
Look, I left a very nice wedding
- Do you mind?
- Yes, I do.
No, I didn't. Yes.
You need to explain to me
what's going on.
Why was that octopus trying to eat you?
That thing was trying to kidnap me.
What power?
I can travel the multiverse.
What?
You can physically move
from one universe to another?
Can't control it.
Only happens when
I'm really, really afraid.
Okay. And did other me know
how to defeat this demon?
of this magical book of pure good
The book of vishanti?
Actually, it does.
I found out in the secret book you get
when you become sorcerer supreme.
Doctor strange: Unbelievable.
You're not the sorcerer supreme?
Other you was sorcerer supreme
of his universe.
Doctor strange: Right. Yeah.
Although it does exist,
the book of vishanti
is said to be unreachable.
It is. Except...
Then the demon caught up with us.
I thought you'd protect me...
But you didn't.
That was the fight in my dream.
Prove it.
It wasn't a dream.
That means...
Dreams are windows into the lives
of our multiversal selves.
That was his theory.
Somewhere out there I had a ponytail.
The power is dangerous enough
in the hands of a kid.
America Chavez.
Miss Chavez, will you come
with us to kamar-taj?
You'll be safe there.
How do I know you won't
betray me like he did?
I guess you're just
gonna have to trust me.
That's gotta violate an ordinance.
The creature that killed him, did...
Did it have the same markings
as the octopus?
Runes.
This isn't sorcery.
It's witchcraft.
Do we know anyone
who's faced such a thing?
But we couldn't wait.
Oh!
Oh, okay.
You can tuck me in, mom.
We could never truly leave each other,
even if we tried.
You can come tuck me in if you want.
Apples, right?
- Eventually.
- Hmm.
Oh, it's all very real, thanks.
I've put the magic behind me.
wanting to discuss
what happened at westview.
But you put things right in the end,
and that was never in doubt.
Then what are you here for?
With what?
What do you know about the multiverse?
Wanda: The multiverse.
He believed it was real,
and dangerous.
We found a girl
who can somehow travel across it,
but she's being pursued.
There are other avengers.
Yeah, but given the choice
between the Archer with the mohawk
and several bug-themed crime fighters,
It's an easy call.
Come to kamar-taj.
It'll get you back on the lunch box.
Here?
Yeah. I know what it's like
to be on your own,
and I can protect her.
You never told me her name, did you?
- Mm.
- No, I didn't.
You know, the hex was the easy part.
The lying, not so much.
The darkhold.
I know it's the book of the damned,
and that it corrupts everything
and everyone that it touches.
I wonder what it's done to you.
The darkhold only showed me the truth.
Everything I lost can be mine again.
What do you want with america?
I'm going to leave this reality
and go to one where I can be
with my children.
Wanda, your children aren't real.
You created them using magic.
there was a universe
wouldn't you want to go there?
I am happy.
I don't relish hurting anyone, Stephen.
She's a supernatural being.
Such raw power could wreak havoc on this
Her sacrifice
Is it the one you used
when you gave Thanos the time stone?
You break the rules and become a hero.
I do it, and I become the enemy.
That doesn't seem fair.
What happens now?
Return to kamar-taj
and prepare to hand over
america Chavez by sundown.
After that...
And if we don't?
It will be the Scarlet witch.
The Scarlet witch.
Wanda's gone.
She's got the darkhold,
and the darkhold has her.
The Scarlet witch is
a being of unfathomable magic.
She can rewrite reality as she chooses,
and is prophesised to either rule
or annihilate the cosmos.
She took over a whole town
using her mind.
If she gets america's power,
she could enslave the entire multiverse.
So, the person you went to ask for help,
is the person that's trying to kill me?
Yeah.
Suspend teaching at once
and arm the students.
Kamar-taj must now become a fortress.
It's an honour to court death
alongside you once again.
The honour is ours.
Whatever the
sorcerer supreme asks of us,
it shall be done.
Sorcerer: Extra duty men,
follow me.
It's ancient custom.
Got it.
No pressure, then.
All this for a child you met yesterday.
You had to make terrible sacrifices.
Do not speak to me of sacrifice,
Stephen strange.
I'll send you to a world where
you can be with Christine.
The full might of kamar-taj
stands against you.
Defensive positions, now!
You have no idea
just how reasonable I have been.
Doctor strange: Yeah.
Book of the damned,
calling yourself a witch,
I don't exactly call that
being reasonable.
Sending those creatures
after her instead of myself
was mercy.
And in spite of your hypocrisies,
and insults,
You have exhausted my Patience,
but I do hope you understand
that even now,
what's about to happen,
Wong: Hold!
Hold!
Reinforce the shield.
Sorcerer 1: Reinforce the shield!
Sorcerer 2: Reinforce the shield!
She's trying to get in their heads.
Sorcerers, fortify your mind!
Wong: The shield is down!
Fire!
Fire at will!
Wong!
Get out of here!
Go, go.
Scarlet witch: America...
You want the girl,
you'll have to go through me.
Fine.
America: Wong, what happened?
Wong: Kamar-taj has fallen.
Reflections.
She's using the reflections.
Cover them.
just to keep me from my children.
You took those lives.
You cannot be allowed
to cross into the multiverse.
I'm a mother.
Wanda, you have no children.
They don't exist.
Scarlet witch: Oh, but they do.
In every other universe.
Billy: We're gonna show it.
All right, go on back, go on back.
Tommy: All right, yeah. Don't...
Scarlet witch: Of my boys.
Tommy: Billy, don't you dare! No!
Of our life together.
838 Wanda: Here.
Billy and Tommy: Yes!
838 Wanda: And then back to front.
Back to front.
Billy: Can I have some?
Please?
- Are you guys ready?
- Tommy: It's okay.
Scarlet witch: Every night...
The same dream.
The same nightmare.
What happens to the other you?
What happens to their mother?
You okay?
You saved me.
I hope so.
So, this is New York
in the multi...
There it is.
Crap.
Cut it out.
Yeah, you got pretty dinged up.
We'll get you fixed.
All right, america.
You gotta open a portal
and get us back there right now.
I don't know how.
You just did it.
Not on purpose.
Wong is back there alone with Wanda,
and I'm the only hope he has.
I can't control my powers...
You must be able to control it somehow.
Sorry.
Well, what about this
universe's version of you?
Maybe she could
control her powers.
This universe doesn't have a me.
- What?
- None of them do.
But how do you know that?
And 'cause I never dream.
What about the book of vishanti?
What about it?
Other you thought it could stop
whoever was after me.
Yeah, well, good for other me.
He's not here, is he?
I don't know where it is,
so unless there's another other me...
We need to go find...
We go on red?
Rule number one of multiversal travel,
you don't know anything.
Right.
It's red.
America!
Rule number two,
find food.
Preferably pizza. Pizza balls.
America: It was free.
Food's free
in most universes, actually.
Crap.
Maybe it's not free here.
Pizza poppa always gets paid.
- She was hungry.
- Relax yourself, there,
Doctor strange.
Where'd you get
this cape from, anyway?
Oh, that feels authentic.
It's not a cape, it's a cloak,
and I suggest you let go.
You took this whole suit
from the strange museum, didn't you?
- Strange museum?
- You're a taker.
Why don't you take some mustard, huh?
Come on. It's not permanent.
Like he'll stop in a few minutes?
were we paint in one of them?
Yeah, you don't wanna
get stuck in there.
It's really hard to eat.
How many universes have you been to?
Seventy-two.
Seventy-three, counting this one.
That's...
Replay your significant memories,
We remember so you don't forget.
Christine: This is pretty fancy.
Did you have to take out
another student loan?
So, um, got you a little something.
What is it?
Christine: Open it and see.
Automated voice: Memory Lane.
Replay your significant memories,
now at a discounted price.
We remember so you don't forget.
Doctor strange: Where's this?
Home.
My moms.
Son mis madres.
Gpara mi? Ay, qué Linda.
Gracias.
A ver, te la pongo.
Mm. Tan hermosa.
You know, you were right.
This is just a waste of time.
Hey, kid.
America: Doesn't matter.
I didn't lose them.
I killed them.
and sent them to a random,
probably deadly universe,
- with no way to escape.
- Listen,
if your moms are
anything like their daughter,
they survived.
Not bad.
Thanks.
That woman in your memory bank thing,
that was Christine, right?
- How do you know her?
- From other you.
Were they together?
He blew it.
Of course.
Did you blow it with your Christine?
Yes, I guess I did.
Complicated.
More complicated
than being chased by a witch
through the multiverse?
Yes, actually, it is.
"Gave his life defeating Thanos"?
Yeah. See? We're not all bad.
If other you's dead,
who's master of the sanctum?
Oh, shit.
- You know him?
- Yeah. Mordo.
He was actually the first guy
who let me into kamar-taj.
and dedicated his life
to trying to kill me.
Great.
You did?
Yes.
Because you always suspected
this day would come.
My brother.
All right.
838 mordo: Come in,
You go on red.
838 mordo: And you're quite
formidable too, it seems.
A multiversal traveller.
Well, thank the stars
you brought doctor strange to safety.
to attack america in other universes.
So she has the darkhold?
Oh, you know of the darkhold?
Oh, yes. We have a darkhold
in this universe, too.
falling into the wrong hands.
Damn right.
But if your darkhold
is anything like ours,
I'm afraid she can do far worse
What do you mean?
There is a spell contained
within those pages...
Corrosive to the soul,
a desecration of reality itself.
Dreamwalking.
A dreamwalking sorcerer
projects their own consciousness
possessing the body
of an alternate self.
They may puppeteer
this unholy doppelganger
and pursue their enemies from afar.
The possession is not a permanent link
But in the fleeting time they dreamwalk,
they can do irreparable damage
to the universe they invade.
It may be the Scarlet witch.
Doctor strange: Because that
was her being reasonable.
The darkhold's antithesis?
It can give a sorcerer
whatever power they need
to vanquish their enemy.
I need your help
to get me to it.
But I hope you,
of all people, understand
It's the two of you.
- Doctor strange: Oh, god.
- What was in that tea?
You son of a bitch.
The sands of nisanti.
I'm only acting as you would.
She's coming.
Billy: Can we have
a little more ice cream?
Tommy: Please.
Billy: Please, please, please!
A little more, please!
838 Wanda: Hey, don't make mom
out to be the bad guy.
Billy: You know who's the best?
Tommy: Who? Billy: 2003 tigers.
Tommy: They suck.
They're so bad they suck egg.
Billy: No, they don't.
They're the best.
Tommy: Doofus. Billy: Doofus 2.
Tommy: Triple infinity doofus.
Billy: Infinity infinity
googolplex quadruple doofus.
Tommy: Quintuple infinity...
Crazy doofus.
Billy: Googolplex doofus.
Billy: Mom?
Billy: Where are you going?
Just to take out the trash.
Billy: Can we show you something?
Tommy: Mom, hurry, come on!
Billy: Come on, it's important.
Billy: You'll like it.
Tommy: Come on. Hurry up.
Billy: It's important.
Okay, so, mom, listen to this...
- I want to start!
- No, I want to start!
- No! I want to start.
- I want to start.
Why don't you both start it,
whatever it is, together?
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Three, two, one, go.
and if we get some ice cream
we promise to be good
Yes.
But so many others were lost.
Set me free.
I need to destroy the book.
No. It cannot be you.
Sara. No, no!
- What?
- Are you okay?
Okay. Billy, Tommy.
What?
No, no, no.
You are the sorcerer supreme.
Tell me what you know.
Not you.
Them.
A copy?
with the wretched spells you seek
carved into its walls.
Wundagore?
America: Hey!
Hey!
This universe sucks.
Cloak?
Hey, lab coat.
Where the hell are we?
Look, I don't know who you are,
or what you think
you're trying to do here,
but these situations don't usually
work out well
for the nameless scientists, so just...
Christine?
Miss Chavez.
you are in a highly secure
research facility.
The two of you,
along with your sentient cloak,
are here for surveillance and testing.
Uh... uh, testing?
Your magnetic signatures
could be radioactive,
Hence, these amazing
polycarbonate fish bowls.
I assume I have you
to thank for these, then?
One of 838 Stephen's magical relics.
838 Stephen?
Is that some kind of cyborg me, or...
Our universe is 838,
and we've designated yours 616.
Oh. You guys sure must know
a lot about the multiverse
if you got someone
going around naming realities.
Yes.
I'm a senior fellow
with the Baxter foundation,
and I specialise
in multiversal research.
Doctor strange: So,
how'd you end up working here?
At your funeral.
Thank you for going.
Your injuries, they're similar,
What were we to each other
in this universe?
Yeah?
Well, that's something we got in common.
Christine, you gotta let us out of here.
Everyone's in real danger.
Look, I know you don't know me...
And I don't want to.
Whatever I was to you in your universe
Why not?
Because you're dangerous, Stephen.
and she's gonna rip this place
apart atom-by-atom
until she gets what she wants.
So I don't care
if you're from the avengers
or S.H.I.E.L.D...
838 mordo: We're neither.
Well, what then?
Hydra?
The illuminati will see you now.
The illumi-what-y?
It's gonna be okay.
My magic can only take us so far.
upon the forbidden grounds of wundagore.
Wong: Eons ago, the first demon, chthon,
These same spells were later transcribed
into the darkhold.
There's no telling
what soulless monstrosities lie within.
It's a throne.
838 mordo: Stephen strange,
you are now called
before the illuminati.
I, baron Karl mordo,
838 mordo: Captain Carter.
The first avenger.
Blackagar boltagon.
Keeper of the terrigen mists,
the inhuman king.
Blackagar boltagard? Huh.
Captain marvel.
Defender of the cosmos.
And the smartest man alive,
"Fantastic four".
Didn't you guys chart in the '60s?
I'm sorry, is this a joke to you?
Well, there's a guy over there
with a fork on his head,
This strange is even
more arrogant than ours.
confuses and destabilises reality.
The larger the footprint
you leave behind,
the greater the risk of an incursion.
Incursion?
Reed: An lncursion occurs
when the boundary
between two universes erodes
and they collide,
destroying one or both entirely.
to make difficult decisions
that no one else could.
Today, we're here to determine
what to do with you and the child.
Captain marvel: So, before we vote,
if you got anything serious to say,
now's the time.
Doctor strange: Yeah, I do.
If it's lncursions you're worried about,
do you seriously think I'm a bigger
threat than the Scarlet witch?
Oh, we can handle your little witch
if she decides to dreamwalk.
We appreciate your concern, Stephen,
but it's not the Scarlet witch
that we fear.
From our experience, the greatest danger
to the multiverse, it turns out,
Earth's mightiest hero
who died defeating Thanos?
838 mordo: Our final member,
That's not how our strange died.
But I do wonder
when you could force america
to send you to any universe you want,
why take her power for your own?
You know it would kill her.
For Billy and Tommy, to protect them.
What if they get sick?
I won't lose them again.
Try as you might, Wanda,
you cannot control everything.
But I can.
Look around you.
I was meant to rule everything.
Is there no peace in knowing
that even though you can't be
with the ones you love,
Is that not enough?
No.
Our strange did not die
defeating Thanos.
We were at war.
Stephen, as always,
chose to go it alone.
838 mordo: He turned to the darkhold,
in hopes that our salvation
might lie in the multiverse.
Captain marvel: And guess what?
It didn't.
But he kept doing it anyway.
confessed that
you had been dreamwalking,
and in your words,
"things had gotten out of hand."
an incursion.
Everyone in that reality died.
Prof Charles Xavier:
Stephen renounced the darkhold's evil
a weapon we did use together
to defeat Thanos.
But one final threat remained.
I shall miss you, my friend.
I'm ready.
I'm sorry.
You built a statue.
The world needs heroes.
What, perhaps,
The building's been breached.
No shit, genius.
Ultron sentry 1:
Stop where you...
Ultron sentry 2: Get back!
Ultron sentry 3:
Stop where you are...
She's heading for the child.
Watch him.
We'll vote on our return.
you must guide america Chavez.
What the hell are you saying?
Save the girl
and get to the book ofvishanti.
What? You have the book here?
Prof Charles Xavier:
Yes. You built a waypoint.
Charles, we cannot trust him.
Just because someone stumbles
and loses their way
doesn't mean they're lost forever.
We will see what kind
of doctor strange you are.
Thank you.
All sentries engage.
Everybody out.
- Intruder approaching.
- 838 Christine: Now!
Ultron commands...
Hurry, hurry! She's coming!
Reed: Wanda, stop.
You've possessed an innocent woman,
but you can still do the right thing.
Let her go.
Please.
I have children of my own.
I understand your pain.
Is their mother still alive?
Yes.
Good. There will be
someone left to raise them.
Take me to the book ofvishanti,
so that we can fight her together.
You are in no position to give orders.
My vote will conclude these proceedings
when they return.
Haven't you had enough?
Oh, I could do this all day.
Get the hell out of my universe!
They're not coming back.
And you just cast your vote now
to kill your friends.
Not that that ever bothered you before.
You know, you hated me
where I came from.
And I bet secretly, my brother,
you hated me here.
I bet you were thrilled
when you heard I'd been corrupted.
I know that killing Stephen strange
was your ticket to getting the sanctum,
to becoming sorcerer supreme,
and to joining
your little circus of clowns,
the illuminati.
I'm ready...
To cast my vote now.
I think I'm beginning to understand
why your mordo
didn't like you very much!
You're sealed shut!
- Whoa.
Prof Charles Xavier: Enough!
Help me. Please.
Wanda maximoff,
your mind is being held hostage
Grab my hand.
Perhaps, if I can pull you
from under the rubble,
the spell will break.
Hey! You all right?
You okay?
Hey.
- You all right?
- America: Yeah.
Hey.
She fixed him.
- Doctor strange: Thank you.
- Yeah.
Xavier said I built a waypoint
to the book of vishanti.
How am I supposed to trust you?
I know what happened,
and I'm sorry for what he did,
838 Christine: Yeah. Your way.
You sound a lot
like my Stephen right now.
He had to be the one holding the knife,
and then that knife
killed a trillion people.
America: This Stephen is different.
He is.
You're not like them.
Give me your hand.
Do not make me regret this.
I won't.
- Okay, can we go now?
- Yeah, follow me.
Under the river.
Go, go, go, go, go!
Where did she go?
I warned you.
Other Wanda, if you're in there,
hold your breath.
An enchantment
that's specific to me,
something only I would know.
- Wait. Stephen.
- Doctor strange: Come on.
Stephen.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Doctor strange: Open sesame.
Come on, kid.
You got this.
You all right?
Yeah.
This is the gap junction,
the space between universes.
Give me what I need.
My boys.
This isn't what your children
would want.
They'll never know.
Maybe not.
Oh, no.
Oh, crap.
838 Christine: It's like this reality
collapsed in on itself.
Doctor strange: Yeah.
838 Christine: So where are we going?
Doctor strange: Well,
if there's still a sanctum
then there might be
another other other me,
Well, I can see why you guys
were so worried about incursions.
of stopping it.
Hello?
How did you get here?
By accident.
Who are you?
From the multiverse?
That's right.
We had a sister.
Donna.
But she, um...
She died when we were kids.
How?
We were playing
on a frozen lake and, uh...
She fell through the ice.
No, we don't.
Suppose your reality
wasn't always like this.
Sinister strange: I suspect it was
somewhat like yours until...
Doctor strange: Until?
Until I lost.
To whom?
I just want to get home.
Yeah? Believe me,
You guard the darkhold in this universe?
That's a start.
I could use it.
It could help me to communicate
with my universe.
The darkhold exacts a heavy toll.
I don't mean to be callous,
Not just on its reality.
Look, I'm sorry you couldn't
save your universe,
but maybe you could help
to save mine.
What?
Are you happy, Stephen?
I said, "yes, of course I'm happy.
"I'm a sorcerer with the power of gods.
"What man wouldn't be happy?"
And then I came back
to this goddamn haunted house,
and wondered why I'd lied.
But I didn't find it.
All I found were more of us.
So I did those Stephens a favour.
You ever had that dream
where you're falling
as if you've been pushed off
a tall building?
The darkhold exacts a heavy toll.
I'll let you use the darkhold
if you give me your Christine.
Yeah.
I don't think she's gonna go for that.
Didn't think so.
What are you doing with the darkhold?
Are you going to dreamwalk?
All you stranges, you're the same.
We are all the same.
But right now, that kid needs me.
And I can't do any of this
without your help.
While I'm under,
I need you to protect my body
in case they attack me for trespassing.
The souls of the damned.
Okay.
so that you can dreamwalk into them?
Who said they had to be living?
possessing a dead body is forbidden.
Trespasser!
Male soul: Trespasser!
838 Christine: Stephen!
They're pulling me down.
Hang on, hang on, hang on.
Where are you?
The brazier of bom'galiath.
Go back to hell.
Stephen.
I've got you.
They're spirits.
Use them.
Female soul: No!
Come on!
Uh-oh.
This time, it's gonna take
more than killing me
to kill me.
Female soul: Murderer! Murderer!
Soul 1: No!
- Soul 2: No!
- Soul 3: No!
She's breaking free!
Strange, take america's power!
There's no other way.
It's me in other me's body.
You're here to take my power,
aren't you?
Before Wanda can.
I understand now.
No, america.
I've come here to tell you
to trust yourself.
Trust your power.
That's how we stop her.
I can't control it. I...
Yes, you can.
You have been all along.
Every time you opened a portal,
you sent us
exactly where we needed to go.
What about the first time?
Even that led you to this moment...
When you're gonna kick that witch's ass.
I've got you.
Mm-mm-mm.
I can't beat you.
Billy. Tommy.
- Mom!
- Mommy!
Wait! Boys!
It's okay, it's okay. It's okay.
I'm your mother!
Get away from them.
Billy: Mom!
Dead strange: No.
Not yet.
Billy: You're not our mom!
Tommy: Get out!
Please don't hurt us.
Please.
I would never hurt you.
Never.
I would never hurt anyone.
I'm a...
I'm sorry.
Mom!
- Are you okay?
- 838 Wanda: Hi.
I'm okay.
- Mom, don't go. Don't go.
- No, mom. Don't.
- It's okay.
- Mom.
Know that they'll be loved.
What now?
I'll find you.
We have to go. Now!
I opened the darkhold.
You all right?
- Is it over?
- Yeah.
She's on her way here to get us.
Wanda?
So she destroyed the darkhold
in every universe.
She did the right thing.
Yeah, she did.
838 Christine:
What's your universe like?
- It's very beautiful.
- Hmm.
I wish I could show you.
I'd really like that.
- But I have to go.
- Yeah.
It's too bad, though.
I love you.
I love you in every universe.
It's not that
I don't wanna care for someone
or have someone care for me.
It's just...
I get scared.
Yeah.
Face your fears...
Ay! How is this so much harder
than a multiversal portal?
She needs to slow down
and be more patient.
How you feeling?
Why do you ask?
Fine.
But I do wanna ask you something.
Are you happy?
That's a, um,
interesting question.
You'd think that saving the world
would get you there,
but it doesn't.
Sometimes, I do wonder
about my other lives.
Yet I remain grateful in this one.
At least we don't have to
go through it alone, huh?
No, we don't.
Hmm.
Wait.
'Sup.
Made some sparks.
Great.
Your parents would be proud.
I'm glad I fell into your universe.
So am I, kid.
Hmm.
Clea: Doctor strange?
Can I help you?
You caused an incursion,
Not in the least.
It's over!