-Hello.
-Hot, isn't it?
I'm home.
Thanks.
You don't need a bag just for milk!
They put it in one.
Just say no! Pour me some, too.
Dad, want some barley tea?
Please... I'll come over.
-Thanks. Is the word processor open?
-I'm still printing.
I should buy an electronic notebook.
You smoke too much.
You could've gone to your aunt's, too.
No. Shiho wears me out.
Oh, I've got work tomorrow.
Do you need lunch?
No, I'll eat out.
The library's busy updating
to a barcode system.
I like the checkout cards better.
Me, too.
Hey, this isn't right...
What?
Did you leave out a line?
You're right!
Let me go first. I have to get this right
or my professor will complain.
SEIJI AMASAWA - JULY 5TH
This guy...
You can read, but don't stay up too late.
Good night.
I thought I'd seen that name before...
Here, too...
LIBRARY WITHDRAWAL CARD
SEIJI AMASAWA - JULY 27TH
SEIJI AMASAWA - JULY 28TH
SEIJI AMASAWA - JULY 5TH
He's taken all these books out before me.
Seiji Amasawa... What's he like?
Wonder if he's nice.
SEIJI AMASAWA
Shizuku! Get up!
I'm leaving!
Did you sleep in your clothes?
Put the rice on.
Bye!
Oh, no! I've got to meet Yuko!
My purse...
You ran back upstairs again?
Yeah.
That's funny...
Try by the phone...
Yes!
where you left it.
I'm late! Lock the door!
Clumsy!
It's flying so low!
Today's a lucky day!
It's a hot day!
How's it going?
Hit it!
Hi, Shizuku!
Hi! Keep it up!
Miss Kosaka?
Tsukishima? What are you doing here?
Could I ask a favor?
Nothing weird, I hope...
Let me in the library!
What?
Can't you wait till school starts?
I've read all my books,
and the public library's closed.
I'm reading 20 before school starts.
20? Don't forget you've got
high school entrance exams.
Hurry up!
Here it is!
Bring it here.
Give me your library card
and the book's checkout card.
Yes, ma'am.
No one's ever borrowed this book!
It's rare. They don't even have it
at the public library.
DONATED
AMASAWA'S COLLECTION
"Amasawa"... Miss!
Do you know who this "Amasawa" is?
Look what you made me do!
Someone gave it to us.
I wouldn't know him.
Ask an older teacher.
Shizuku!
What are you doing here?
I've been at the front gate since 11!
If I have to stand in the sun
I get more freckles!
Sorry!
Relax, Harada. You take freckles
much too seriously.
They're a serious problem, Miss!
Yeah, yeah... all right, out of here,
both of you.
Move up! Move up!
I tried, but it's not going to work.
Why not just sing it in English?
White clouds spreading up over a hill
A road winds up to the town
An old house with small windows
An old dog waits for me to come home
Country road leading far away
The road to my old home town
West Virginia, my mother the mountain
My good old home town
-That's not bad.
-Yes, it is.
It's trite.
Yeah?
I wrote another one.
Concrete roads, everywhere
Cut down all the trees
Filled in the valleys
Western Tokyo
Tama Mountain
My home town is concrete roads
What is this?
But what's this "problem?"
You don't need the lyrics yet...
No... are you in love with anyone?
What?
Studying for these exams
would be easier if I had someone.
We could support each other.
Yuko! You're in love!
You got a love letter?
Shh!
When? Who? Is he handsome?
He's in another class. He's not bad.
Meet him, then! If you don't like him,
just say no!
Yeah, but...
So there's someone else you like!
You can't hide it from me! Spit it out!
It's Su... Su...
Tsukishima!
Bring me my bag, will you?
Sugimura!
That blue sports bag.
Come on, Tsukishima!
Throw it over here.
Shut up and go back to the bench!
I'm a starter, and we're
going to the playoffs!
Yuko?
You're in love with Sugimura?
What am I going to do?
The way I reacted, he might know!
Don't worry. He's too dense.
What about the guy who wrote you a letter?
I'll think about it for a while.
I see.
At least your parents
aren't always pushing you to study.
Silence isn't always great.
I wonder...
-Oh, no!
-What?
I forgot my book! I need to go back.
You can ride my bike.
No. You'll be late for cram school.
I'll call you.
That book...
Oh, is it yours?
Here, "Shizuku Tsukishima".
How do you know my name?
Guess!
My library card...
I'd forget about "Concrete Roads", though.
You read it!
Jerk! Jerk! Jerk!
Jerk!
"I'd forget about 'Concrete Road'..."
Get lost!
DONATED
AMASAWA'S COLLECTION
Did you see?
They were swimming like this!
I'm home.
Shiho? You're already back?
I'm beat!
I got a ride with someone
who was coming this way.
Where's Mom?
Summer Intensive Seminar. Dad's at work.
You could clean up a little...
What about dinner?
I'm going to wash the rice.
Shizuku! The breakfast things
are still out!
I'm on it!
Mom's busy! We've got to help!
Do the rice and put away the laundry.
I'll take a shower and make dinner.
Auntie says to come and see her
when you get into high school.
Are you studying?
Don't think you can take it easy
just because Mom and Dad don't bug you.
I know!
She even wanted me
to bring home some soy sauce!
That's your aunt, all right.
It was the same thing last year.
Yes! It was miso! Boy, was it heavy!
Two kilos of it!
Shizuku! Get up and vacuum by your desk!
I'm washing the sheets.
And airing the bedding.
Where's Mom?
Long gone.
Put that stuff away
and go and bring Dad his lunch.
Me?
Why not? You're going to the library.
Shall I go instead?
Are you gonna clean the toilet, the tub
and the balcony and go to the store?
Don't forget to turn the bedding
and fix dinner.
I'm going!
Shizuku!
Mail these, will you?
What?
M-A-I-L!
You don't have to read them!
Take the paper-clip off.
Your boyfriend?
Idiot!
MUKAIHARA STATION
NO BIKE PARKING
-Will you be there?
-Yeah.
Next stop, Suginomiya.
The exit will be on the left-hand side.
Hey kitty, are you alone?
Where are you going?
What's out there?
Hey! Answer me!
I'm getting off here. What about you?
See you.
Hey! A cat!
KODAMA LINE
SUGINOMIYA STATION
The library's that way!
And it felt
just like the start of a story...
There he is!
AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY
NO ENTRY
What a hill! How far up is he going?
Kitty?
Does he live around here?
Hey, kitty! Where are you going?
Do you live around here?
I never knew there was
a place like this way up here...
SUZUKI
That's not nice!
Going around teasing dogs!
Maybe you're teasing me, too.
WORLD EMPORIUM
SHIRO NISHI, PROP
I never would've guessed there was
a store like this one up here either...
Cool!
Are you that cat?
Oh, hello...
-Um...
-That's all right.
Look around all you want.
Baron gets bored.
Baron?
Is that the name of this statue?
Yep. Baron Humbert von Gikkingen.
Quite the name...
Sorry.
Thanks. I'm fine now.
That's a great clock.
It was sitting in some castle,
all rusted out.
Look...
It's beautiful. What is it?
Wait and see.
What great dwarfs!
So you're a young lady
who knows about dwarfs, aren't you?
Watch the clockface... if it works.
A fairy!
The light shines on the glass.
Come up here.
All right.
A princess?
That's right.
Are they in love?
But they live in different worlds.
He's the king of the dwarfs.
She's a fairy when the clock strikes 12.
Then she turns back into a sheep.
But he appears every hour...
and waits for her.
The artisan who made this
must have been disappointed in love.
That's why they both look so sad...
This clock's fast, isn't it?
Only about five minutes, though.
Oh, no!
I've got to be at the library!
Can I come back sometime?
Sure... but go left to get to the library!
I'm right above it!
TENSHU HILL
What a find! A place where stories start!
Fantastic!
Tsukishima!
Shizuku Tsukishima!
Isn't this yours?
You're forgetful, aren't you?
Thanks... but how...
Guess!
The cat! Is that your cat?
You sure eat a big lunch!
No!
Concrete roads, everywhere
It's not mine! Hey!
Oh, here you are...
What's wrong with you?
It's hard to explain.
I felt like I'd found
a treasure hidden in a cave.
Then what someone said buried me alive.
Sounds complicated.
Getting more books?
Seven more to go.
Still at it? What about lunch?
I'll buy something.
You will? Thanks, then.
June 16th...
Wow! Amasawa's read this one, too!
What's he like?
Concrete road
No! He's not you!
POE OF HAMBURG
Shizuku! Hurry!
I'm late!
Pass my umbrella.
Rain every day this term!
At least you're studying
because you want to.
Sorry.
Study hard!
Don't you worry!
Shizuku!
Hi!
Hurry! We'll be late!
I hate all these tests!
One every day!
Did you answer the letter?
No.
Did he say anything?
I'm going to say no.
Yeah? Maybe that's best.
Sugimura!
Better hurry!
I know!
Time's up. Gather the papers.
See you this afternoon.
Come over here, let's eat!
Let's go see Miss Kosaka.
Let me go to the teachers' room first.
Sure.
-Tsukishima!
-What?
I lucked out on the test!
Isn't that nice?
Everything I studied was on it!
So you're not just a baseball goof...
Yuko's good at guessing, too.
Why not study with her?
With Harada?
-Hey, Sugimura!
-What?
Did you see this?
Come on!
Stop trying to hook me up!
Was it obvious?
I never just guess!
Sorry!
TEACHER'S ROOM
Excuse me...
A library-book donor? Gee, I don't know...
Sorry to bother you at lunch-time.
There's this stamp in it.
Oh...
FAIRYTALE
DONATED
AMASAWA'S COLLECTION
That's Dr. Amasawa.
I've read it. It's a good book!
Yes, very.
What kind of person is he?
He was chairman of the PTA
a few years ago.
The PTA? Would you know his given name?
His given name?
Mr. Kimura, do you remember
Dr. Amasawa's first name?
Dr. Amasawa? It was Koichi.
Koichi Amasawa...
His youngest son, Tsukishima,
is in your year. Don't you know him?
He is?
Thank you very much!
Excuse us!
Sorry!
Shizuku, where are you going?
What a surprise!
Tell me about it!
What's up with you?
Sorry!
Hey, where are you going?
He ignored me! The nerve of this guy!
Who is he? Where are you going?
He's a jerk! He won't make me avoid him!
Oh, you're so cute!
I've been carrying her lunch
all over town!
Tsukishima with a boyfriend?
Looks like springtime has come
for Shizuku at last!
It isn't true!
You met a prince from one of your books?
Is he handsome?
I just want to find out what he's like!
Come on, Yuko, you heard his name.
Tell us!
Yuko!
It happened too fast.
"Ma", something, "Masaki", maybe...
Hmm?
Hmm...
But it's just like Tsukishima to run out
without hearing the end of something.
You want to know, but you don't...
Your heart beats in misery and ecstasy!
How terribly romantic!
Should you really tease a girl
who has just written your lyrics?
-You've finished them?
-Let's see!
O Shizuku! O great poet!
We shall not transgress again!
All right, then.
I'm not sure...
I don't know about old home towns,
so I wrote about what I feel.
This is great!
Country road, this old road
If I go right to the end
Got a feeling it'll take me
To that town, country road
This is good, Shizuku. I like it.
It's not hard to sing?
We'll manage.
We can give this to the juniors
and sing it to the teachers!
There, too?
Slow down!
I like this part.
"I left because I was alone
and I had nothing...
"Pushed away my sadness
and pretended I was strong..."
-Ladies, the bell.
-Yes.
The sun's come out!
Shizuku!
Come to the choir room!
We'll show them your lyrics.
No, I'm going to the library.
There's another test tomorrow...
I'll study there.
Bookworm!
-Bye.
-Bye-bye.
Harada...
Can I talk to you for a minute?
It's closed.
Have these flowers been watered?
Baron's gone...
Maybe someone bought him.
WORLD EMPORIUM
SHIRO NISHI, PROP
"Shiro Nishi"...
Maybe that jerk's name is "Nishi", too.
Shizuku! Shizuku!
Yuko's on the phone!
You'll go deaf, Shizuku.
Yuko?
What? I can't hear you.
I'll be there in a minute.
Bye.
-Where are you going?
-Not far.
What's wrong?
Shizuku!
What's the matter?
What am I going to do?
The guy who wrote the letter
got Sugimura to ask me to answer it!
Uh-oh...
Why you, of all people?
Hey!
That guy is so dense!
But he doesn't know
how you feel about him...
I'll apologize to him. But I can't go
to school tomorrow looking like this.
And miss the test?
Yeah.
Oh.
DEVELOPMENT
Idiot!
What?
It was easy.
The library again, Shizuku?
I'm going to Yuko's.
Say hello.
-Bye.
Tsukishima!
Wait up!
About Harada...
And then she started crying.
Did I say something wrong?
She said, "Why you, of all people,"
didn't she?
Yeah. A guy on the baseball team asked me.
No!
She didn't want to hear something
like that from you!
Don't you understand?
No, I don't!
Tell me!
You really are dense, you know!
She likes you!
What? No way! I don't need this!
You don't? How do you think Yuko feels?
She stayed home sick today!
But... I like you!
What?
Don't make jokes at a time like this!
It's not a joke!
I've liked you for a long time!
Not me! You can't!
You don't like me?
Or do you have a boyfriend?
I don't have a boyfriend...
But...
-I'm sorry!
-Wait!
Tell me the truth!
But we've always been friends...
I like you, but not...
I'm sorry. I can't say what I mean.
Just friends?
Forever?
I see...
I'm the one who's dense!
The parcel delivery guy left this with me.
Thank you... again!
You don't have to do this!
We couldn't eat all these ourselves.
Oh, you're home...
Shizuku?
Hi.
Have you been shut out, too?
Do you live here? Are you hungry?
You're not very nice. Just like me.
Why do we change, I wonder?
I was always so sweet...
Books don't even excite me
like they used to.
There's always someone inside me
saying, "Things aren't that easy!"
I'm not very nice.
Hey! Tsukishima!
Moon lets you pet him?
Moon, you're not coming in?
Is that his name?
He's like a full moon.
That's why I call him that.
Isn't he yours?
He won't stay in one house.
I heard some neighbors named him "Ball."
I'm sure he has other names.
So he does the rounds...
Yes! He commutes, on the train!
The train?
Yes, by himself! That's how
I found this place. I followed him.
And he brought me to a neat store,
just like out of a story.
I insulted him.
I said he wasn't very nice. Just like me.
You're not like Moon at all!
He's half-devil, he is.
-Um...
-Would you...
Is your grandfather sick?
The store's been closed and I thought...
He's fine. It's a weird store.
He doesn't open very often.
I'm glad he's all right.
I can't see Baron through the window.
Did he sell him?
That cat statue? You want to see it?
Come on.
Close the door.
It's like we're in the sky!
Afraid of heights?
No, I like high places. This is great.
This is the time it looks best.
In here.
Perfect timing.
Sit there.
The clock's gone!
The one that was there?
Grandpa's delivering it today.
Did he sell it?
It was just here for a repair job.
I wanted to see it again.
It took three years. He finished it
the day you forgot your lunch.
That lunch!
I know it wasn't yours.
Look into the cat's eyes.
Quick, before the sun sets.
Engelzimmer... "angel's room".
The artisan accidentally scratched it.
It's beautiful.
Baron won't go anywhere.
He's a treasure.
A treasure?
It means something to him.
He won't say what, though.
Look as long as you like.
I'll be downstairs.
Turn on the light if you want.
It's weird.
I feel as if I've known you for years.
Sometimes I really want to see you...
You look sad today, somehow...
Had enough?
Yeah. Thanks.
Are you making a violin?
Uh, yeah.
Can I see?
It fits like this.
You made all that? By hand?
Sure!
Amazing!
The shape hasn't changed in 300 years.
The sound comes
from the craftsman's skill.
You made all those?
No way! There's a violin-making
class here.
But one of them is yours?
Yeah.
Which one?
That one.
This one?
Wow! You made this? It's like magic!
How can you say this with a straight face?
Why? It's what I think.
Anyone can do that.
I've got a long way to go.
You can play, can't you?
A little.
Play for me, okay? Please!
Listen...
Please, please, please!
You have to sing, too.
Me? I'm tone-deaf!
Perfect!
Sing. You know this song.
Had a dream of living on my own
With no fear of being all alone
Pushed my sadness down inside of me
And pretended I was strong as I could be
Country road, this old road
If you go right to the end
Got a feeling it'll take me
To that town, country road
It doesn't matter to me how sad I might be
I will never ever let
A tear show in my eye
If my feet are moving faster
That's because
I only want to push away memories
Country road, this old road
Could go right to my home town
I won't go there, I can't go there
Can't go down that country road
Country road, when tomorrow comes
I'll be like I always am
Want to go back there
Can't go back there
Fare thee well
Country road
That was fun!
I'm Shizuku Tsukishima.
We met the other day.
I was hoping you'd come back again.
These are my musical friends.
Nice singing. You're the lucky one
who was there when he fixed the clock...
Seiji has some pretty friends.
"Seiji"? Are you Seiji Amasawa?
Yeah... didn't I tell you my name?
No! It says "Nishi" outside.
That's Grandpa's name. I'm Amasawa.
Oh, no! First I was buried alive,
and now the sky's fallen!
What difference does it make
what my name is?
A lot! You've been calling me
by my full name!
You never asked me mine!
I never had the chance!
My image of Seiji Amasawa...
What?
was someone quiet and gentle.
You read too many books.
So do you!
That was fun. They're nice people.
Come back. They'll like that.
Just to listen, then. Singing's too hard.
But you're a good violinist.
Is that what you want to do?
Lots of people are as good as I am.
What I want to do is make violins.
Yeah... you're good at that.
There's a school for it in Cremona, Italy.
I want to go there.
And not go to high school?
My parents are dead against it.
Grandpa's my only ally.
It must be great to know
what you want to do.
I've got no idea at all.
I just go from one day to the next.
I don't know if I can go or not.
I fight with my parents every day.
Even if I go, I won't know
if I have the talent until I try.
I'll see you home.
No, it's not far. See you.
Tsukishima...
Yeah?
You've got a talent for poetry.
What you sang back there was fine,
but I liked "Concrete Roads", too.
You told me to forget that!
Did I say that?
Yes!
I did?
Thanks for everything. Good night.
Don't fall asleep with the light on again.
When did you decide on your future?
What?
Your future!
Isn't yours Suginomiya High?
I don't mean that!
I'm in college trying to figure it out.
Good night.
Mom's class is canceled
so now she sleeps in!
-Morning!
Run faster!
You go ahead!
HOUR 1: SPARE PERIOD
Great!
Shizuku!
You look awful!
You sure got better quickly!
I hear you were out with a boy last night.
Who told you that?
A little bird... who said
you were like lovers.
We are not!
Harada... I'll tell my friend
the answer's no. Sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
That's okay.
Did you see Ninja Warrior on TV
last night? It was great!
This formula will be on the mid-term,
so remember it!
-What?
-Are you serious?
That's all.
-I'm not surprised.
-I heard he rushed to get it.
Is Tsukishima here?
Amasawa? What do you want?
Is Tsukishima in this class?
Tsukishima? Yeah, she's here.
Tsukishima! You've got a visitor!
A boy!
There she is.
Seiji?
Can I talk to you?
Yes!
Tsukishima's got a boyfriend!
Boyfriend! Boyfriend!
No, I don't!
What is it?
I'm going to Italy.
What?
Come with me.
-Where are we going?
-The roof!
Wow!
We can't talk
with all those people around.
Sorry. I wanted to tell you first.
Let them think what they want.
My dad finally gave in. On one condition.
What's that?
I apprentice in a workshop there
for two months.
Apprentice?
The guy who runs it is very strict.
He'll see if I have the talent or not...
and if I have the patience
to stick it out.
Otherwise I'll go to high school.
I hate that they're leaving
an escape route...
but it's a good opportunity.
When are you leaving?
As soon as I get my passport.
Dad will be talking to the school today.
Soon, then...
Great! Your dream's coming true.
Well, I'll do the best I can.
-Um...
-Well...
The rain's stopping.
Yeah...
Look over there.
There might be a rainbow...
What's Cremona like? I hope it's nice.
It's an old town,
with lots of violin makers.
It's great. You're on your way.
I feel like a fool.
I was hoping we'd go
to the same high school...
What a stupid thing to think...
Found them!
I saw your name on the library cards
a long time ago.
We passed each other all the time
in the library.
I even sat next to you.
I read all kinds of books so my name
would be on the cards before yours.
I...
I'll sing your song to myself in Italy.
Me too.
Don't push!
Hey!
Look out, she's mad!
So scary!
Run!
-Here.
-Thanks.
Excuse me.
Finished already?
I'm meeting Yuko.
If you're by the station, get some milk.
What?
You're the one who drinks it all!
She's slacking off these days.
-Did I make you skip cram school?
-It's all right.
My head's in a whirl.
Hello, Shizuku.
Hello.
Hi.
-I'll make some tea.
-Okay.
Dad and I aren't speaking.
Boys are so lucky!
When he comes back to graduate,
he'll leave again for ten years!
That's like forever!
But it's like fate
brought you together! Cool!
It was too good to last.
Two people who read the same books...
except one's moving forward
while the other stays behind.
Yeah...
Kinuyo was in his class for a year.
She said he was hard to get to know,
but good-looking and smart.
Don't tell me that, will you!
I just feel worse!
Why? He likes you, doesn't he?
He told you so!
Now I'm not so sure...
I don't get it. I'd write every day...
We'd support each other...
You can't say "go for it" to someone
who's more ambitious than you.
Maybe...
But I don't understand what you want.
Can't you be in love
without your future planned out?
You're talented.
All the juniors liked
your translation of "Country Roads".
You can express yourself, too...
Unlike me.
-"Lots of people are as good as I am."
-What?
That's what he said.
He's going to find out
if he's talented enough. Well, so will I!
I'll write a story!
There's one I want to write.
If he can do it, so can I.
But it's exam time...
I don't care. Thanks, Yuko.
I feel empowered.
-You going?
-Yeah.
Good night.
-Say "hi" to your mother.
-Yes.
You go for it, too.
I'm sure Sugimura will realize
how great you are.
-Bye.
It's so easy!
I just have to do something, too!
Moon?
Muta?
Mom! Muta's gone again!
Muta!
"Muta"...
"WHISPER OF THE HEART"
LISTEN TO THE VOICE OF THE WOODS
LISTEN TO THE FOREST'S VOICE...
Baron as the hero?
Would you mind?
I ask because Seiji says
you treasure him...
You didn't have to ask!
Of course you can. But on one condition.
Yes?
That you let me be the first person
to read your story.
Um...
All right?
Do I have to? I don't know
if I can write it or not...
It's the same for a craftsman.
Don't expect perfection at first.
Here, let me show you something.
This.
Look at it.
It's called "mica slate".
Look at the seam.
Like that...
It's beautiful!
It's called "beryl".
You find it in emerald ore.
-Emerald? The gem?
-Yes.
You and Seiji are like this stone.
Rough, unpolished, still natural.
I like stones that way.
But making violins and writing stories
is different.
The rough stone is inside you.
You have to find it and then polish it.
It takes time and effort.
You see the ore that makes up
most of that stone?
Yes.
You could polish that,
but what you'd get would be worthless.
The smaller part inside is purer.
There might even be a better stone
deep inside where we can't see.
I'm sorry. Old people like to preach.
I'm scared. What if there isn't
a beautiful crystal in me?
But I want to write. And you'll be
the first one to see it.
Thank you. I'll look forward to it.
A rough stone... Lapis lazuli...
Let us go forth together...
in search of the treasure
of lapis lazuli!
Have no fear. Space is deformed
on the night of the new moon.
Faraway things loom large,
nearby things look small.
Fly! We will rise on the updraft.
Make haste! The planetoids are converging!
Good! We're riding the wind!
Straight up to that castle!
It's so high!
It's not so high once you're there!
Go! When the air currents mingle
in the afternoon, you can touch the stars!
ARCHITECTURE
MANUFACTURING
Huh?
NATURE
FOLKLORE
That's unusual!
Shizuku looking at non-fiction.
PYRITE
AGATE
JADE
LEAD
CAT FOLKLORE
HISTORY OF EASTERN EUROPE
WHEN HE WAS IMPRISONED
(FRANCESCO FERIO)
He's making a violin in his cell...
Seiji!
I thought you were gone!
Grandpa said I might find you here.
I leave tomorrow.
Tomorrow...
Don't worry. I'll wait here
till you're done.
Sorry I can't walk you home.
That's okay. I'm glad you came.
I can't come to the airport,
but I'll wait for you.
It's only two months.
I'm sorry I'm always so depressing.
I'll do my best while you're gone.
I'll see you, then.
Have a good trip!
Luisa, my betrothed, and I
were born in a distant land.
In that town, magic still lived...
and in the veins of its artisans
flowed the blood of sorcerers.
It was a doll maker's apprentice
who fashioned us...
but Luisa and I were happy...
because he had made us
so we could love others.
But then...
Shizuku...
Shizuku!
What's going on? Tsukishima!
I'm sorry. I wasn't listening.
Pay attention! This is important!
Sorry, sir.
Harada, you read.
Yes.
You were up until four again?
It's okay. I'm not sleepy at all.
But you're spaced out all the time!
Like just now...
I was thinking. I've got to organize
what I want to write.
I'm not hungry.
TUESDAY, OCTOBER 18TH
Shizuku? So you are home...
Turn on the lights!
At least you could bring in the laundry!
Shizuku! Come here!
Shizuku's here, isn't she?
She's not hungry.
-Thank you for coming.
-Sorry to trouble you.
This way... Is anyone
in the guidance office?
Yeah.
Please.
I'm back!
Hello.
You're home early, Shiho.
I'm beat!
Want some coffee?
Yes, please.
Mom, can I talk to you?
What?
I'm thinking of moving out.
I've found a place.
But can you afford it?
I've saved from my job.
I found another one
at a cram school. I'll get by.
I guess I've made you help me out
too much around here.
I'll talk to your father.
You will? Great!
Money's tight till I graduate
in the spring and get working...
but I'll help you out then.
Sounds good.
I'm sorry I'm doing this now
during your master's thesis...
Thanks.
You helped me enough with the data.
And Shizuku will be able to concentrate
in her own room. She's acting weird.
You think so too?
The school called me. Look at this.
What is it?
She's gone down a hundred spots!
She's at her desk all the time...
what's she doing?
Good evening.
Hello.
Excuse me.
What high school will take you
with grades like this?
I'm not going to high school!
Use your head! You think
a junior high education is enough?
I can decide my own future!
Watch your mouth!
Face the facts! The school will write
the report after the second term!
You're a fine one to talk!
You didn't study!
You just work part-time jobs!
I do what I have to!
You're the one who isn't doing that!
Don't you understand?
I've got something more important to do!
Like what? Tell me.
Shiho, Shizuku... that's enough.
But Dad... listen to this girl!
Both of you come out here
and tell me about it.
Shizuku, change out of your uniform.
Come on.
MID-TERM TEST RESULTS
3RD YEAR, CLASS 5, SHIZUKU TSUKISHIMA
I see. Is it true what Shiho says?
I do care about my grades!
You just said you weren't going
to high school.
You said I wouldn't get into one!
Shiho... can Shizuku and I talk
alone for a bit?
Yes.
Where's your mother?
At the Tanakas.
I'm back.
Hi, Mom.
-Is your dad back?
-Yeah.
Could you come here, Asako?
I've been hearing about Shizuku.
Coming.
All right, Shizuku...
Is what you're doing now
more important than studying?
Can you tell me what it is?
When it's time.
Is this something
you have to do right away?
I've only got three weeks left to do it!
I'm challenging myself.
I have to.
Challenging yourself? How?
How will we know if you won't tell us?
Is it something you can't even tell us?
Seiya!
Oh... sorry.
Whatever you're doing at the library,
I admire how hard you're working.
Let's let her do what she wants.
Not everyone has to be the same.
I should know that more than anyone...
Okay, Shizuku, do what you believe in.
But it's not easy
when you walk your own road.
You've only got yourself to blame.
And join us at mealtimes, all right?
Yeah. We're a family.
Yes.
Call Shiho.
I'll make some tea.
Shizuku...
I know what Dad said, but what
he really wants is for you to study.
I know. It's written on his face.
I'm moving out next Sunday.
You'll have your own room.
You're leaving home?
Yep. So smarten up!
Hurry!
Only one is real.
Which one is the real one?
Hurry!
Luisa... you've finally come...
but I've grown so old...
Shizuku...
Come in... I was fast asleep.
I'm sorry to bother you.
I've brought my story.
It's finished?
I promised you'd be the first to read it.
It's a novel!
"WHISPER OF THE HEART"
Can you read it now?
I'll wait as long as it takes.
But you've worked so hard on it...
shouldn't I take my time?
You can stop if you don't like it.
I hate to ask, but...
My heart's pounding...
I see. I'll read it right now.
Come sit by the fire. It's cold.
Now we won't be bothered.
Can I wait downstairs?
It's okay. I'm not cold at all.
Of course... but...
Are you sleeping?
Shizuku... I'm finished.
Thank you. It's very good.
It's not!
Say what you really think!
I couldn't write what I wanted!
The last half doesn't make sense.
I know that!
Yes... it's rough, blunt, unfinished...
just like Seiji's violin.
You've shown me the rough stone
you've just cut out of the rock.
You've worked hard. You're wonderful.
There's no need to rush now.
Take your time and polish it.
It's cold out here. Come inside.
Now...
Now that I've written it I get it.
Wanting isn't enough.
I have to learn more...
but Seiji's getting
further and further ahead.
I felt that I had to force myself
to write, and I was so scared...
You like Seiji, don't you?
How does it taste?
It's very good.
When Seiji finished his first violin,
we had ramen noodles.
Jumbo size.
Thank you.
Now, where was I?
You found Baron in a coffee shop...
Yes, in Germany...
I was a student.
He looked so melancholic...
I asked the owner to sell him to me.
But he wouldn't.
Baron had a lover,
and he wouldn't separate them.
He was waiting for her to come back
while she was being repaired...
at the doll maker's shop.
Just like in my story!
Yes... quite the coincidence!
I had to go back to Japan,
so I'd just about given up.
Then a lady friend of mine...
told me that when the other doll
came back, she would pick it up...
so the two dolls could be reunited.
So the owner gave in.
I ended up leaving Germany
with just Baron.
I promised her I'd come back,
and asked her to keep the other doll.
The day the dolls met again...
would be the day we'd be reunited.
But then the war started,
and I couldn't keep my promise.
When I was finally able to go back,
I looked all over for her.
But there was no trace of her,
or the Baron's lover.
She must have been very dear to you...
Your story brought the Baron
out of my memory and back to life.
Oh, yes...
Hold out your hand.
But...
That stone suits you perfectly.
I'll give it to you.
Now, finish up your story.
Yes.
Thank you!
Goodbye!
I'm home.
Hi.
Where's Dad?
In his bath. Where were you at this hour?
I'm sorry I worried you. Today I'm back
to studying for my entrance exams.
So your challenge is over?
For now.
Did you eat? There's curry...
I'm fine!
"For now"...
Shizuku, the bathroom's free.
Ah, the warrior rests.
There we go.
No!
Wait there!
It's a miracle! You're here!
We're not dreaming?
I got an earlier flight. Hop on.
Wait... you'll be cold.
Climb on.
I'll get a coat.
No time! Get on.
Hang on tight.
I was out there calling you in my head.
"Shizuku!"
And then you appeared!
What a team!
Me, too... it's like I'm still dreaming!
How was Cremona?
A lot different than I thought.
But I'm going to do it.
It's getting light!
Shall I get off?
It's all right.
I made up my mind I was going
to take you all the way up this hill!
That's not fair!
I'm no man's burden!
I want to be useful!
Okay! Push!
Almost there!
Shizuku! Hop on!
We made it!
-I'll hold the coat.
-I'm fine.
Here...
Wow! In the mist, it looks
just like the sea!
This is my secret spot. It's almost time.
I wanted you to see this.
Grandpa told me everything.
I didn't do anything to help...
I was just thinking of myself.
No... you were the reason I did it.
I'm glad I pushed myself.
I understand myself better now.
I'm going to study hard
and go on to high school.
Listen, Shizuku...
I can't say how soon it'll be, but...
would you marry me?
I'm going to be a violin maker...
and then...
You mean it?
That's exactly what I wanted.
Yeah? Great!
Wait... it's cold...
Shizuku... I love you!
Had a dream of living on my own
With no fear of being all alone
Pushed my sadness down inside of me
And pretended I was strong as I could be
Country road, this old road
If you go right to the end
Got a feeling it'll take me
To that town, country road
Tired of walking, I stop and stand
Thinking back on my hometown
But that road leading up the hill
Is telling me to move on
Country road, this old road
If you go right to the end
Got a feeling it'll take me
To that town
Country road
It doesn't matter to me how sad I might be
I'll never ever let a tear show in my eye
If my feet are moving faster
That's because
I only want to push away memories
Country road, this old road
Could go right to my home town
I won't go there, I can't go there
Can't go down that country road
Country road, when tomorrow comes
I'll be like I always am
Want to go back there, can't go back there
Fare thee well
Country road