THE BEGINNING
Our blue home
Where the sea lilies sway
I was speaking
With my countless
Brothers and sisters
In the language of bubbles
Do you remember ?
Long, long ago
You and I were living
In the blue sea together
The jellyfish, the sea urchin
The fish, and the crabs
They were all
Your siblings
Sosuke, come right back!
Okay.
A goldfish.
It's stuck.
That was weird.
Ow!
Is it dead?
It licked my finger. It's alive!
Sosuke, we're leaving!
Lisa, I caught a goldfish!
This wind feels strange.
Sosuke, I'm starting the car!
Did you find her?
What? Captured by a human?
This is bad, very bad.
Is it dead?
It's alive!
Sosuke! I'm going to be late!
Lisa! I caught a goldfish.
A goldfish?
Down by the rocks.
I'm sorry, but you can't use
weed killer here.
Heavens, no! This is pure sea water.
It keeps me humidified.
Just as long as it's not weed killer!
Good day!
This is very bad.
What a creepy guy.
But don't you say that
about strangers, Sosuke.
I won't.
Are you taking that to school?
Yes.
Won't the teacher complain?
It'll be fine. I'll look after her.
She's cute.
They're using the dry dock.
Here, eat this before we get there.
Maybe she's hungry.
Want some?
Hey, my cut is gone!
I'm going to call her Ponyo.
She's really special. She can do magic.
Ponyo fixed my cut.
Want some ham?
Lisa, Ponyo likes ham!
That makes two of us.
Oh no!
Disgusting!
Hurry, Lisa!
Such filth! It's intolerable!
Good morning!
Look, Ponyo. There's our house.
I'll drop you here, okay?
Okay.
-Have fun.
-See you!
Morning! Sorry I'm late.
-Could you get Noriko's wheelchair?
-Yeah.
Morning, Sosuke.
I'm busy, Yoshie. Talk to you later.
Oh my!
Hello, Sosuke.
Can't talk now, Toki.
Well, well...
Maybe the teacher will get mad.
I know!
Wait here. I'll be back soon.
What if a cat comes?
Stay here, I'll be right back.
See you later.
It's all right. She'll be just fine.
Okay, thanks. Bye-bye.
Good morning, teacher.
Hello, Sosuke.
How are you?
-Sosuke!
-Kumiko.
Like my dress? My mommy got it for me.
Let's play, Sosuke.
Not now. I'm busy.
How come?
I told you, I'm busy.
You're no fun.
No fun.
Ponyo!
Sosuke?
Kumiko.
What's that?
You're not supposed to bring stuff in.
But these trees aren't on school grounds.
Show me!
Oh, a goldfish.
It's not a goldfish. It's Ponyo.
Ponyo? I want to see!
Promise not to tell?
Promise!
There! Cute, isn't she?
It looks fat. My goldfish is much cuter.
It was Kumiko's fault.
She was mean to you.
I'll give you some more water.
Ponyo!
You scared me.
Why, how odd. That was Sosuke's voice.
But he's supposed to be in school.
I must be hearing things.
Here I am, Yoshie.
I knew I heard your voice.
Do I have a secret?
-Yes!
-Bingo!
Okay, what color is my secret?
-Red!
Good guess.
How did you know?
Show us.
Okay.
Oh, how pretty.
Very cute.
Her name is Ponyo.
She loves ham, and she can do magic.
I cut my thumb, but she fixed it.
I wonder if she'd fix our legs.
Then we could run around just like you.
Well, I'd have to ask Ponyo first.
Can I have a look?
Sure, Toki.
Heavens, it has a face!
Quickly, throw it back in the sea,
otherwise there'll be a tsunami!
You're so superstitious, Toki.
Fish like that bring bad luck.
Everyone knows that!
The tsunami! It's here!
The tsunami's here!
Tsunami!
What's wrong, Toki?
Just look at my clothes.
Sosuke!
Come back here, and apologize to Toki!
Don't worry, I'll protect you.
Sosuke.
Ponyo!
Ponyo. Sosuke.
Ponyo... loves... Sosuke!
I love you too.
Ponyo loves Sosuke!
Ponyo!
Sosuke!
Listen, Sosuke. Maybe it was fate.
You can't change fate.
Ponyo was born in the sea.
She went back home, that's all.
Anyway, let's hope that creepy guy's gone.
Give me a lick?
Hurry, it's melting!
Not bad!
Cheer up. Koichi will be home tonight.
He'll be disappointed
if you're feeling down.
No more going in the ocean today, okay?
Okay.
Sosuke?
Time to come inside.
Do you think this bucket
will help Ponyo find us?
There's only one way to find out.
Can you get that, Sosuke?
It must be Koichi.
Hello?
Yes, it's me.
KOGANEIMARU
I can't get back tonight.
I'll signal when I'm offshore.
Okay. Here's Lisa.
Koichi? Yes. What?
Can't you get out of it?
Fine! Just leave your wife
and son up on the cliff!
I give up!
Sosuke, let's go out to eat tonight.
I want to eat at home.
There he is! Turn off the lights, Lisa.
It's Sosuke! He's a genius.
Only five years old.
Your wife must be upset.
He says he's sorry, Lisa.
I-D-I-O-T.
He says he loves you!
Lots and lots!
IDIOT
Wow, that's cool!
HAVE A SAFE JOURNEY
THANK YOU
GOOD NIGHT
Don't cry, Lisa.
I won't cry.
I promised Ponyo
that I'd take care of her.
I hope she isn't crying.
Okay, let's cheer up!
I'm happy as can be
Ow!
Don't worry, Sosuke.
I'm sure Ponyo is fine too.
Now, let's eat.
We'll eat Koichi's dinner too!
This is all my fault.
Bringing you along
to watch me was a mistake.
How often have I warned you about humans?
Their very breath is polluted.
Come, you must eat.
Can't you hear me, Brunhilde?
I want ham.
Ham?
What on earth have you been doing?
Answer me, Brunhilde!
My name's not Brunhilde. It's Ponyo.
Ponyo?
Ponyo loves Sosuke.
I'm going to become human.
Human?
How could you love
such disgusting creatures?
They rob the sea of life.
I was human myself... once.
I finally escaped that awful heritage.
I want hands.
I don't like these feet.
I want feet like Sosuke.
Of all the nonsense!
Look at me! Hands and feet!
Look!
-Don't tell me you tasted human blood?
-Look!
I want to see Sosuke!
No! His blood has deranged your DNA!
Revert... Revert...
Go back... Go back!
It's not working. I need more power.
I want to go! I want to go!
I want to go!
Let me out!
Be still, you evil blood.
Revert, revert!
Just like her mother, so strong.
If I hold her like this,
she should be fine.
My powers can only hold her for a while.
Looks like only her mother can do it.
No! My elixir is too strong for you!
Shoo! Go away!
My crab shields are weakening.
It might disrupt the balance of nature.
Calm down, calm down!
I get a bad feeling
every time I have to meet her.
This batch should be ready.
No leaks down here.
This door is loose.
I'll have to fix it later.
I can't let any creatures in,
or there'll be big trouble.
Superb!
I feel the ocean's power in my very DNA.
When this well is full,
the Era of the Ocean will begin.
An explosion of life to match
the Cambrian Era!
This revolting era of Man will be over.
Close up, close up.
Teeth!
Oh my!
I'm going back to Sosuke!
Sosuke!
Captain, look there!
It's a tsunami! Turn her into the waves!
What is that?
Captain, the radio's out, the radar too!
A little girl? She must be Sosuke's age.
Bye-bye. See you tomorrow.
Thanks.
Take care.
Do you want to wait here for Lisa?
It's okay, I'll take the shortcut.
Goodbye.
Be careful out there.
Sorry, Sosuke. The power's out.
The door wouldn't open, would it?
-Was school okay?
-Yeah.
Go on home, Lisa. We'll be fine.
What about Grandma Kaneko?
She'll be fine, she'll be here soon.
We're spending the night anyway.
You should go while you can.
Wait for me, Sosuke.
Okay.
Yoshie.
Oh, it's you, Sosuke!
I can't see well in the dark.
This is for you.
My, what is it?
One for you, too, Noriko.
Thank you.
I can't see a thing.
Such a heavy storm,
worse with a blackout.
I don't want to spend the night here.
Oh, good, the power's on.
It's a goldfish!
Maybe Sosuke's magic
made the lights go on?
...an extremely powerful storm tonight.
Ships should exercise caution...
This TV's useless.
Those idiots couldn't forecast
their way out of a paper bag.
You should go home, Sosuke.
Your goldfish will bring us luck.
We're not afraid now.
Okay.
Here's yours, Toki.
It's all wrinkled. What is it?
Like this.
I know! It's a grasshopper.
No, it's a ship.
It's your father's ship, isn't it?
Yes.
Still looks like a grasshopper.
We're leaving, Sosuke.
Say goodbye to everyone.
Yeah.
Goodbye, everybody.
Goodbye.
Don't let the wind blow you away!
Climb in here.
The phone lines are down too.
The sea's swelling up!
Will the ships sink?
They're safe out at sea.
I'm sure that's where Koichi is.
I see fish, Lisa.
Fasten your seat belt!
THE 12TH OHAMA
You've got to turn back, Lisa!
People are going to the shelters.
But there are people
at the old folks home!
They'll be alright.
They're on the leeward side.
I've just got to get home.
-No way through here.
-Go around the mountain.
-Here we go, Sosuke.
-Okay.
-No! Stop!
-Look out for that wave!
Here it comes!
Run for it, Lisa!
The fish are following us.
Seat belt, Sosuke!
Hold on tight!
That wave's unstoppable!
-A little girl fell in.
-What?
She was riding a fish.
Where?
The sea keeps rising.
Sosuke, where did you see her?
Out there, running on top of a fish.
On a fish?
Come on, Sosuke.
Hang on, Sosuke. We're almost home.
There's a little girl!
It's dangerous! Better come with us!
Stay there, Sosuke.
Sosuke, do you know her?
Ponyo?
Yes, it's me!
It's Ponyo!
Ponyo's a little girl now, Lisa!
I'm back!
Now, listen, children.
No matter how strange everything seems,
we have to stay calm.
Okay.
Now, be good.
Take off your raincoat, Sosuke.
Here, Ponyo, you hold the light.
I'll get you something to dry yourself.
In here, Ponyo!
It smells just like you!
Ponyo!
Gotcha! Let's get you dried off.
Such pretty red hair.
But your clothes are dry.
Ponyo was a fish.
Water doesn't make her wet.
I like this.
All right, who wants some tea?
Ponyo, help me with the light.
Coming!
I wonder if there's any water...
-Sure!
-Water!
We have a tank outside.
What about the gas?
Presto!
-All right!
It's propane.
Okay, take your seats.
Okay!
Over here, Ponyo.
Sit down, like this.
Put your stuff down.
You need your hands.
I can use my feet!
Wow!
What are you two doing?
Her feet are like hands.
There you go.
This is the best!
That hit the spot.
What shall we do now?
I want ham.
She's crazy about ham.
Then, let's eat.
But first, let's start the generator.
We need electricity to talk to Koichi.
Koichi is my father.
Is he an evil magician?
No, silly.
He's a ship captain.
What about your father, Ponyo?
Fujimoto! He keeps me prisoner.
I ran away.
What about your mother?
I love my mother!
She's really scary.
Sounds like Lisa.
Can you help me, Ponyo?
Maybe the fuel's too old?
Is it clogged up?
Clogged up.
It's clogged up there.
Success!
All bright!
Wow, Ponyo!
Antenna! Antenna!
Did all the ships sink, Lisa?
I can't see a single light.
Too loud!
What's wrong?
Even the radio's out of whack.
This is JA4-LL, JA4-LL.
Do you read me, Koichi?
Lisa, Sosuke, and Ponyo here.
We're all fine.
We're about to have dinner.
Ham!
Ready? Careful, it's hot.
It's not ready yet.
It takes three minutes.
Close your eyes.
Not yet.
No peeking, Ponyo.
Okay, you can look now.
And... presto!
-Ham!
-Good for you, Ponyo.
Ponyo's fallen asleep.
Ponyo must've come from far away.
I guess so.
Look, Sosuke. The sea's calmer.
Is that because Ponyo's asleep?
Look over there.
It's moving. Someone's up there.
People from the home?
It's gone.
That's the peak road.
Sosuke, stay there with Ponyo.
Maybe I could get through
on the mountain road.
I'm going to the old folks home.
I'll go with you too.
Stay here with Ponyo.
I'm going too. Let's take Ponyo with us.
I'm going with you!
Sosuke, our house is a lighthouse
in the storm.
It brings light and hope
to those in the dark.
So, someone has to stay here.
Lots of things are happening
that I don't understand.
But right now, I'm worried about
the residents of the old folks home.
Just knowing you're here will help me.
Don't worry. I promise to come back.
Promise?
I promise.
You promised!
I love you, Sosuke.
I see the lights of the town!
Finally. Now we can navigate.
I've never seen that town before.
Did the storm blow us to America?
That's not a mountain.
And that's no harbor.
Those are all ships!
Carried by the wave,
gathered as a mountain here.
It's a ship graveyard. What's going on?
We've lost power!
Heave to! Drop the sea anchor!
Aye-aye!
Something's coming!
A sea goddess?
-We're moving!
-We're saved!
It was her, it was the goddess!
Protect us from harm...
Higher, higher...
A barrier spell.
Where did she learn that?
Good heavens, she's human!
Hey, watch out! What are you doing?
Stop it, you lot! It's unsafe!
Stop that at once!
I'm simply trying to save your sister.
She's here. She answered my call.
Fujimoto.
You came, my beloved.
Such a beautiful sea.
Full of magic.
As if I'm back in the big ocean.
It's Ponyo, she tasted human blood
and plundered all of my elixir.
Ponyo? What a lovely name.
It's all my fault.
She's totally beyond my control.
It's complete chaos.
She doesn't understand what she's done.
Now she's human
and run off to a boy's home.
If we don't stop her,
the planet is doomed!
No! The satellites are falling.
The earth's gravitational field...
Be still.
Sosuke... That's his name, yes?
You love your sister, don't you?
Listen, dear.
What if Ponyo really became human?
Use the old magic.
If Sosuke's love is real,
she'll lose her powers forever.
But if it's not, she'll turn to sea foam!
That's where we all came from, dear.
But he's only five!
Sleep well, little children.
Sosuke!
Morning, Ponyo.
Morning, Sosuke.
We almost got flooded.
Where's Lisa?
She must be stuck someplace.
If only we had a boat...
There's a boat!
We can't fit on it.
We can!
Awesome!
The candle's bigger too.
We can fit.
This is cool.
Cool!
Grab that end.
Okay.
Ready?
Ready!
She's seaworthy!
Awesome. No leaks!
Now we fill the boiler.
The water goes in here.
It goes in the boiler.
It goes like a rocket!
Everything's shipshape.
Shipshape!
Yes, it is.
-Shipshape?
-Shipshape!
Shipshape! Shipshape!
Hot?
Hot!
-It's hot.
-Hot!
The candle's burning.
It's burning!
Hot, hot, hot!
Hot, isn't it?
Awesome!
-It's all shipshape, Sosuke!
-Yeah.
-Great, isn't it?
This is so much fun.
It's burning, isn't it?
It's hot, isn't it?
Keep a lookout in front.
I'll steer the boat.
Okay, I'll be the lookout.
There's a road.
That's the road Lisa took.
Lisa's not there.
She will be. She gave me her promise.
Ancient fish from the Devonian Age.
There's Bothriolepis.
-And that one is...
-Dipnorhynchus.
Dipnorhynchus!
That one's really huge.
That's Devonynchus.
Devonynchus!
Ahoy!
There's a boat!
They're calling us.
Ahoy!
Over there!
Pretty good, huh?
Now, Ponyo.
-Hello.
What a wonderful boat.
Why, you're Lisa's little boy.
He's not little, he's Sosuke.
This is Ponyo.
I'm Ponyo. I used to be a fish.
A fish?
Ponyo, that's a nice name.
Yes.
Have you seen Lisa?
Lisa?
She's not with you?
She's at the old folks home.
The home?
This is my baby.
Oh my, what happened?
Are you giving it to us?
Pass the cup.
Thank you.
Let's try it.
It's delicious.
Lisa made it.
It's for the baby!
Oh, I'm sorry. He can't handle soup yet.
But this will help me make milk for him.
Lisa gave me her milk too.
Ponyo, may I have this soup?
Sure.
Thank you.
People from the town.
It's like a festival.
Ahoy! You there! Do you need assistance?
Thanks, we're okay for now!
Then, please follow us!
We're going to the hotel on the peak.
Okay! Will do.
The whole town's here.
I'm glad everyone's all right.
Careful, Ponyo.
Hold on a second.
Milk!
Oh my...
She ate all the ham.
Thanks. This will help me make good milk.
Can you use another candle
for your boat, Sosuke?
Thanks. Ponyo will make it bigger.
-Be careful!
-Thank you!
What is it, dear?
Don't cry.
Ponyo!
Sosuke!
It's Sosuke!
It is!
Where's Lisa?
Isn't she with you?
I'm going to pick her up.
So she survived that wave?
Sosuke, take me with you!
Later, Kumiko. I'm busy now.
Everyone from the home
was evacuated to the park.
-Keep safe!
-Good luck!
We'll send a boat for them later.
Good luck, Captain!
Time for a new candle, Ponyo.
Good job we just got a new candle.
Ow! It's still pretty hot.
Bye-bye.
Ponyo, can you make this candle bigger?
All right.
Are you sleepy, Ponyo?
Ponyo?
It's shallow enough to walk.
I can see the road.
The boat!
Ponyo!
Ponyo, wake up!
Sosuke...
Don't scare me.
I thought you were turning into a fish.
Lisa's car. Ponyo, that's her car!
Lisa!
Here's your boat.
Water's coming out of your eyes.
Let's look for Lisa.
Yes.
THE SUNFLOWER
-You forgot your wrap!
-Who needs it?
Look, it's a whale!
How wonderful!
My knees don't hurt anymore!
What were we so afraid of?
Is this the Other Side?
Who cares? It's wonderful.
Attention, please! Gather round.
Coming!
Shall we?
It feels great to run.
Meet you there!
The winner!
You're so fast, Kayo.
Quiet, everyone!
The moment of truth is at hand.
Sosuke and Ponyo are almost here.
Oh my!
Will love triumph?
I'm so excited!
How lovely!
Quiet!
You are all here as witnesses.
Please wait patiently.
Mr. Fujimoto, you're not going to do
something bad to Sosuke and Ponyo?
Nonsense, he's her father.
Of course not.
If they pass this test...
Excuse me.
What a lovely gentleman.
Where's Lisa gone to?
She's been talking
with Ponyo's mother for ages.
It must be hard for Lisa.
I wonder what they're talking about.
Let's find out. Lisa!
Lisa!
We're all rooting for Sosuke and Ponyo!
You must be worried.
Sosuke will be just fine.
He's a strong little boy.
Thanks, everyone. He'll need your support.
Of course!
Ponyo, it's a tunnel.
SANJO MUNICIPAL PARK
COMING UP
SINGLE LANE
REVERSIBLE LANE
STOP
YIELD
I've been through here before.
Ponyo?
I don't like it.
Don't let go of my hand.
Ponyo!
Ponyo, please don't die!
Wake up, Ponyo!
Shh! Don't wake her up.
I've been waiting for you, Sosuke.
Lisa and the old ladies are waiting too.
Lisa?
Won't you come with me, you and Ponyo?
Move quietly, let's not wake her.
Sosuke!
Don't listen to him!
He tricked everyone into going with him.
-Toki...
-But he couldn't fool me!
There's no time, I tell you!
Don't you see what's happening?
If the moon comes any closer,
we're finished!
Is that the best you can do?
-Sosuke, come here!
-Jeez!
Listen to me, Sosuke.
You're the planet's last hope.
Don't make me use force.
Ponyo!
Is this how you treat your father?
Run, Sosuke!
You don't understand!
You can make it!
Jump!
Now what?
Lisa!
Sousuke.
Ponyo!
Look over there.
Where are we?
So, you're Sosuke.
Hello. Are you Ponyo's mother?
Yes.
I want to thank you
for bringing my daughter back to me.
Ponyo has broken the magic seal
in order to become a human.
To become human,
she requires a man
that will understand and accept her.
Do you know that Ponyo was a fish?
Yes.
She turned into a mermaid
because she tasted your blood.
That's right!
Ponyo licked my cut and made it better.
So that's why she's half-fish, half-human.
Can you accept her as she is?
I'll always love Ponyo,
whether she's a fish, a human,
or in between.
Come, Ponyo.
Sosuke has promised
to accept you as you are.
But to become human,
you first must give up your powers.
Can you do that?
Yes.
Kiss this bubble when you return to land,
and Ponyo will transform
into a little five-year-old girl.
That's wonderful, Ponyo.
Thank you, Ponyo's mother!
Now the planet is safe again.
Splendid, Sosuke!
Sosuke!
I'm grateful, Lisa.
Thank you, Gran Mamare.
Is everyone all right?
Wait, I'll get the wheelchairs.
Don't bother, we'll walk.
It's all so exciting.
I believe this boat is yours.
Thanks.
I hope you'll forgive me. May I?
Take good care of Ponyo.
That's Koichi's boat.
Koichi!
It's Lisa! And there's Sosuke!
Look, Ponyo, it's Koichi's boat.
Ponyo, Ponyo, Ponyo, the little fish
Who came from the blue sea
Ponyo, Ponyo, Ponyo, the girl
With a big round tummy
Tap tap, jump jump
Feet are so nice, watch me run
Grip grip, swing swing
Hands are so nice, let’s hold each other’s
When I skip with her
My heart flutters too
Chew, kiss, hug
I love her
The little red
Ponyo, Ponyo, Ponyo, the little fish
Who came from the blue sea
Ponyo, Ponyo, Ponyo, the girl
With a big round tummy
THE END