Pirates!
We're under attack!
Hold them off! Get down on the floor.
Tear gas!
What are you waiting for? Break it down!
Where'd she go?
There she is!
She's getting away!
Well, get her!
Mama, don't drop me!
There's the stone. Quick, go next door!
Get that crystal!
There goes the crystal.
Two meatballs, please.
Working late?
We're finally busy again.
-Still working?
-Yeah.
What's that?
A person!
Pazu!
What are you up to? Where's my dinner?
Boss!
A girl fell from the sky.
Boss, she fell from the sky.
Darn old clunker.
Boss! A girl...
Close valve number two!
-Pazu, toss me a wrench.
-Sure.
I'm busy here. You take it.
-Don't make them wait.
-Yes!
-Keep a steady hand.
Brake!
Any luck?
No silver, no tin even.
All that wasted work.
Should we try the east vein?
That's riddled with old holes.
We'll have to start over.
That's enough for today.
Push!
Shut down the boiler. Call it a day.
I'll go under at this rate.
Oil the clunker, Pazu.
Yes!
Mama, we couldn't find her. It's too dark.
I hope you really looked!
All right. We'll wait for daylight.
Hi. How are you feeling?
Hey, come on guys...
I'm Pazu. I live here by myself.
They eat after I play.
So you are human after all.
I was afraid you were an angel.
Thanks for helping me.
I'm Sheeta.
Sheeta, nice name.
You fell from the sky. A bit scary.
That's right. Why am I still alive?
I fell from the airship...
-Have you forgotten?
-Yes.
Say, can I see that?
-This?
-Yes.
It's been in my family forever.
It's beautiful.
Wait...
Watch this!
Pazu!
So it wasn't the stone after all.
Oh, no! Pazu!
-Are you okay?
-Yeah. Are you?
I'm fine. Sorry, did it hurt?
No, my head's harder than my boss's fists.
The pot's still boiling.
Hungry? Let's eat.
Wash up over there.
-There's a towel.
-Thank you.
Laputa...
Sheeta! Where are you?
My father took that picture.
That's Laputa, an island in the sky.
An island in the sky?
They say it's only a myth.
But my father saw it.
He took it from an airship.
There's a Laputa in Gulliver's Travels,
but Swift made it up.
Dad drew this.
He said the abandoned palace
was full of treasure.
But nobody believed him.
Until he died, they called him a liar.
But my father never lied.
I'm building a real plane.
I'm going to find Laputa!
A real automobile...
They're pirates!
They attacked the airship.
-Are they after you?
-Yes.
Quick!
-Morning!
-Hey, wait!
We're in a rush.
Have you seen a girl?
Sure, yesterday...
The boss's kid, Madge...
Off you go!
They're looking for you.
Louis, a girl's dress!
What! She was disguised! Tell Mama!
All right!
Haven't seen her.
A cute little girl. Brown hair, braids...
Boss!
About that age.
Hey!
That's her!
Pirates! They're chasing her.
Pirates! Lemme see!
Not one step closer.
Hand her over.
-Pirates, eh?
-Dola's clan.
Go home. Just poor folk here.
-Ma'am?
-Scoot out the back.
I want to fight.
-They've got weapons!
-But...
What a pretty girl. Better protect her.
You refuse to step aside?
Use your fists.
Could be interesting.
Get him, brother.
Show your stuff.
Wow.
Who's going to mend that shirt?
You can beat him!
That's it, hit him!
Off you go!
Think you can fool me? After them!
Climb on!
There you go.
Playing hooky for a date?
Bad guys are after us.
-The Dola clan.
-Pirates?
Take us to the next town. To the police!
You're on. Stoke the fire.
Okay.
Mama!
You idiots! Hurry up and get on!
What? But the girl's...
She slipped out the back door. Get moving!
Brother!
Wait!
They're catching up, more steam!
Can't you go any faster?
She's an old-timer.
-Move over!
-Whoa!
Mama, I can't hang on!
More steam, they're gaining on us!
Here we go!
Sheeta, over here.
-Stoke the fire.
-Okay!
Don't give up!
Push! Push, I tell you!
Not so fast!
Don't let them escape!
Dump this over the side!
-That'll teach them!
-I'll do it.
No, let me.
Up we go! Up we go!
Wait!
It's them. What'll we do?
I refuse to give up. Move!
This is a surprise. If it isn't the army!
These kids need help!
They've got pirates after them.
Sheeta?
Goodbye. Wait!
Sheeta!
Halt or I'll shoot.
An armored train.
Who cares! Ram it!
What is it, Sheeta!
Stay away!
They're gonna fall!
Quiet. Watch closely.
We're floating!
Look! It's that crystal!
It was the stone after all! Amazing!
We'll float all the way down.
Amazing! I want it!
Fire!
I have to get that amazing stone!
-It's fading...
-Hey, wait!
It's just like when you landed.
The opening looks so tiny.
I hope the boss and the engineer
aren't in any trouble.
Aw, don't worry.
Miners aren't exactly wimps.
Come on, let's find the way out.
These mines are ancient.
Tunnels everywhere.
There.
I'm so happy. I was starving.
I've still got an apple and some candy.
It's like you have a magical bag
that holds everything.
Gondoa? That's so far north.
Yes. Both my parents died,
but they left me the house and the fields,
so I was getting by on my own.
Those guys with dark glasses
kidnapped you?
Yes.
That guy was one of them?
Who can they be, calling in the army?
Dola and the other guys,
they all want the stone.
But I had no idea
it had mysterious powers.
It was always in our family.
Mother left it to me when she died.
She warned me never to show it
or give it to anyone.
We're both orphans, aren't we?
I'm sorry I dragged you into all of this.
When you fell from the sky
my heart was racing.
I knew something wonderful had begun.
Little demons... Little demons.
Uncle Pom! He's really great.
Uncle Pom.
We've lost our way.
Now that little demon
sure looks like Pazu...
With a little girl demon beside him.
Pirates are after us.
And the army.
How very extraordinary.
Drink up.
Thank you.
Have you always lived underground?
Why, no, no.
The rocks have been stirring...
That's when I like to be down here.
The rocks were stirring?
Rocks speak very softly.
Wonderful...
Pazu, look at that!
They were ordinary rocks until...
How pretty...
Here, let me show you.
It's gone.
These rocks contain volucite.
Volucite?
As soon as it's exposed to the air,
it becomes ordinary stone.
It's glowing...
Oh, my gracious!
That's a volucite crystal, my dear.
I've never seen one before.
That's why the rocks were stirring.
This stone has mysterious powers.
I thought only Laputans
knew how to make volucite crystals.
Laputans?
They used Volucite to send
a magnificent island aloft...
Laputa did exist, Sheeta! It really did!
Does the island still exist?
Uncle Pom?
Dear, would you mind covering the stone?
Its power overwhelms me.
Yes.
What's wrong?
My grandfather told me...
the rocks stir
when Laputa floats overhead.
If you went up to the sky then,
you'd find Laputa!
Sheeta, my father was telling the truth!
Young lady...
-You see...
-Yes?
Your stone is most powerful...
I know that.
I've been speaking to rocks all my life.
A stone so powerful brings happiness,
but it also often brings misery.
I see.
What's more,
your stone is the work of men.
How on earth did you...
The stone's not dangerous!
It already saved Sheeta twice!
Amazing! Laputa really does exist!
It's gone.
Let's go back to the ship.
When it's this quiet,
it's best to stay put.
I'm hungry...
It's all clear. Let's go.
Thank you, Uncle.
Look after yourselves.
Look at those clouds!
Beyond those clouds is an island
we've only dreamed of.
Here I come! I know
I'm going to find Laputa!
Pazu...
I haven't told you everything.
My family had a mysterious,
ancient name...
that came with this stone.
My name is Lucita,
Lucita Toelle Ur.... Laputa.
Laputa?
So you mean...
It's the army! Run!
Underground!
Don't move!
How dare you!
Pazu! Let me go!
Pazu! Pazu!
-We've apprehended them.
-Good work.
Open up, open up!
Sheeta...
Company, march!
Use force!
Squeeze the brat, she'll talk.
Spoken like a man in uniform.
In your haste, you risk everything.
If we'd mobilized sooner,
we'd have bagged Dola too.
She managed to decipher
your third-rate code.
What!
My organization will handle this.
Concentrate on mobilizing
the troops when the time is ripe.
Muska! Remember, I command
the search for Laputa!
Of course. But I have my orders
from the government.
That pencil-pushing upstart!
Have a nice rest?
Where's Pazu? Let me see him!
No interest in pretty clothes?
Don't fret about Pazu.
His stubborn head is harder than mine.
Come, I have something to show you.
Enter.
What is it?
A mechanical soldier
with vast destructive power.
Until he fell from the sky,
no one believed Laputa was real.
He's not of this earth.
Our science can't even identify...
what material he's made of.
Look...
Don't be afraid.
He's long dead.
Look at that.
This insignia
was carved on your fireplace.
It's on this stone, too.
The stone works only in your hands.
It protects its owner
and will guide her back to Laputa.
I know nothing of this!
Take it if you like.
Just leave us alone...
Perhaps you imagine that Laputa
is some kind of treasure island.
Fearsome scientific power
thrust Laputa into orbit.
Their dreaded empire once ruled the earth!
Even you can appreciate
that when such an entity roams the skies,
it threatens peace.
I need your cooperation.
You must know how to make
the stone guide us to Laputa.
I really don't know!
Please let me see Pazu!
I intend no harm,
but his fate rests with you.
What?
The boy goes free
if you assist us, Lucita...
Toelle Ur Laputa.
But how...
Ur means ruler. Toelle means True.
You are Princess Lucita,
rightful heir to the Laputan throne.
Out!
Sheeta!
Pazu, are you hurt?
I'm fine. You?
Did they do anything horrible?
My dear Pazu, we misjudged you.
Accept our apologies.
We didn't know how gallantly...
you protected her from the pirates.
Sheeta, what did you...
Pazu, I beg you, forget about Laputa.
What!
Sheeta will aid us
in our search for Laputa.
I understand how you feel,
but forget about her.
Is this true, Sheeta? But we...
Thank you for everything.
I'll never forget you, Pazu.
I don't believe it...
Sheeta, we promised!
Farewell!
Sheeta!
Wait, Sheeta!
Be reasonable. Act like a man.
Sheeta!
Here's a token of our gratitude.
It's yours.
Only you can recall the words
that will waken this stone.
If you keep your promise,
you too shall be free.
Pazu...
Mama, it's Pazu! He's back!
Pazu.
We were so worried. You just disappeared.
-And the girl?
-Forget it.
Pazu!
Let me go! What are you doing?
Put a lid on it!
Nice place you got, kid.
Get out!
This is my house!
Oh, come off it.
Can't even protect a little girl...
-What do you say?
-He's got gold!
Sold her for money, huh?
No! I wouldn't do that!
You let them pay you off?
Sheeta told me to do it.
So...
So you gave in and crawled home.
You call yourself a man?
You talk big, but you're after Sheeta too.
But of course, we're pirates.
Pirates hunt for treasure.
Those guys are strange ones.
What's the girl to them?
You think she'll get out alive?
So, Sheeta told you to leave?
They threatened her,
so she tried to save you.
How do you know, Mama?
I've been a woman for 50 years.
She steels her heart
to save her man. How touching.
Reminds me of my youth.
If you boys want to get married,
look for one like her.
-So that girl will grow up...
-To be like Mama?
What a waste.
I've got all your codes.
Calling the battle cruiser?
They'll pack her up and take off?
We better hurry!
Dinner's over. Move out.
Yes, Mama.
Going after Sheeta?
We want the crystal, not the girl.
The stone's no good without her.
Can't I go with you?
I have to help Sheeta!
Do it on your own, like a man.
You're right,
if I was clever and strong,
I could've defended her.
Please, I don't care about treasure.
-Listen to him...
-Shut up!
Yes!
He could probably help us with her...
You'll be an outcast forever.
-I know.
-You sure?
Yup!
Be ready in 40 seconds.
Take care, you guys.
Tie this to your belt.
You boys wait on the ship.
A magnificent vessel.
Has the girl talked?
I need a little more time.
Forget it! We'll squeeze
it out of her up there.
We depart at dawn, with the girl.
Step on it, it's almost dawn!
Sheeta!
Whatever shall we do?
Sheeta, listen, I'm going to teach you...
a magic spell for trouble.
A magic spell?
Yes.
These are old, old, old secret words.
They mean "help me rekindle the light."
Perfect.
Just as the ancient books described.
This is the sacred light.
Sacred light?
What are the magic words? Tell me.
-Let's go.
-Yeah.
It's moving!
The robot, it's alive!
Hello!
Help!
It's alive! It's the robot!
The robot?
It's coming this way.
Run!
Retreat! Retreat!
Incredible!
I see!
It's the light!
The sacred light broke his seal!
The way to Laputa is open! Come!
No!
It can fly!
It's pointing to the sky...
It's showing the way to Laputa.
Hurry!
Explosives?
Idiot! You'll blow up the fortress!
Hello, hello! What is this!
-Good.
-We're connected.
This is Colonel Muska.
The robot cut communication with the ship.
I've assumed emergency command.
It's after the girl on the tower.
Take it down on sight.
Prepare to fire.
Hurry! Hurry up!
Fire!
Hurry!
-We did it.
-Amazing!
Get the girl.
Is she dead?
Get up!
-She just fainted.
-Stand!
It moved...
What's that? Looks like a war.
-Let's go, Dola!
-That's Captain, to you!
Lower, Charles.
Stop! Stop it!
Please!
Mama, Goliath's pushing off!
We're going directly into
the crossfire. Regroup!
-Look, there's Sheeta!
-Where?
Where?
Straight ahead.
She's on top of that tower!
This is a job for a woman! Cover me.
Sheeta!
I'm coming, Sheeta!
Pazu!
Fly closer!
Let me go!
Sheeta!
Dola!
Pazu!
Pull up!
Last chance! Grab her on the fly!
Pazu!
-Here goes!
-All right!
Move aside! Damn!
Sheeta!
What's Goliath doing?
A smoke screen?
Where's the robot?
Destroyed. The girl went that way.
What!
Put out the fire! Organize a search party!
We haven't lost the sacred stone.
Its light points to Laputa...
Inform the general, we'll depart
for Laputa as planned.
Lucky guy...
I can't believe she'll grow up
to be just like Mama...
There's your valley...
Right back where we started.
Dola, please take us aboard.
Call me Captain!
What use are you without the crystal?
We'll work.
I want to see Laputa for myself.
Don't want any treasure?
You just want to see Laputa?
Suspect motives
for boarding a pirate ship.
Are they coming with us, Mama?
One false move and you're shark bait!
Excellent! No more laundry
or cleaning duty!
Or dish washing!
Or potato peeling!
-Can you make pudding?
-Yes...
I like mincemeat pie.
I eat, uhm... anything!
Enough out of you!
When will those boys ever grow up?
Get off!
Canvas. It's made of cloth.
And don't tear it.
Hurry up, it's crowded in here!
Hurry, this way!
I hate dawdlers.
You're with me!
Pazu!
I don't bite. Come.
You're not here for fun.
What an engine.
Now where'd he go? Pops! Pops!
Look, we got you an assistant.
Don't holler.
I hear you.
He's tougher than Mama. Be careful.
My hand doesn't fit.
This gasket?
-Name?
-Pazu.
The crystal pointed nearly due east...
You sure about that?
I could see the sunrise from the tower.
It's the harvest season now...
so the sun rises just south of due east.
The light pointed to the left
of where the sun rose.
Good answer. Any luck?
Not a peep.
They're maintaining radio silence,
aren't they?
Mama, Goliath's faster. What do we do?
We're upwind of them.
If we get a lift on the trade winds...
My abacus from the Far East.
Windspeed is 10... and...
I think we can catch up.
Okay, listen up!
Goliath's on its way to Laputa.
We're on their tail.
With these winds,
I expect contact tomorrow.
Ten gold pieces
to whoever spots her first!
Ten!
Whatever we find,
I'm sure Laputa has riches enough
for any pirate gang!
Earn your keep, boys!
Now!
Course 98, speed 40.
That getup of yours won't work.
Wear these.
Your station.
Beautiful...
You serve five meals a day.
Go easy on the water.
Get to work, you idiots!
Yes?
I'm sorry, dinner isn't ready yet.
I've never cooked on an airship...
Do you need something?
-Beautiful...
-What?
I thought I'd give you
a hand in my spare time.
Why thank you.
Can you put those dishes away?
Happy to obli...
You said your stomach hurt...
I've got some free time. Can I...
You're in the way.
Some stomachache, jerk!
Hey, can I help...
You've changed, chasing the likes
of Goliath...
But it's pointless.
It's Laputan treasure I'm after.
They're certainly nice kids...
Get to the point, you old goat.
They're too upright and honest
to ever respect you.
What's that!
No, I mean... Check...
Excellent... delicious...
Seconds anyone?
-Okay.
-More! More! More!
Hey, shake a leg.
It's your watch.
Take it, it's cold.
-Watch?
-Yeah.
Darn cold! Go on up.
-My turn.
-Great.
Sheeta!
That was scary!
The sky is beautiful.
Sheeta. Get in.
Can't you sleep?
Nice and warm...
Look aft.
Pazu?
What?
I'm really scared.
I really don't want to go to Laputa.
I hope we never find Goliath.
-You mean--
-No, the light pointed the right way.
But...
You mean the robot?
Poor thing.
I never dreamed
that little spell would work.
I learned lots of other spells.
To help find things, cure the sick.
And one I must never, ever use.
Never, ever use?
A spell of destruction.
I had to learn bad ones
so the good spells had power.
I was so scared, I couldn't sleep.
That stone should be locked away.
They hid it in the fireplace.
It was only worn for weddings.
My mother's and grandmother's
and great-grandmother's.
I should have thrown it away.
You're wrong. We met thanks to the stone.
Throwing it away
won't make Laputa disappear.
Airships are improving.
Someone will find it.
I don't know what to do,
but if Laputa is so dangerous...
it's not for the likes of Muska.
Besides...
If we run now, they'll hunt us forever.
But don't become a pirate for me.
I won't become a pirate.
Dola understands.
She's nicer than she looks.
Once things are settled,
I'll take you to Gondoa.
I want to see where you were born,
the valley, the yaks...
Pazu...
What's that!
Below us, look!
Goliath, right below us!
Come about! Full rudder!
We should go after them.
They'll be trouble if we don't!
We can't catch them in these clouds.
We'll get them. They won't go far.
Steady as she goes.
We're farther north than I thought.
Pazu, listen up! Time's running out.
If we lose Goliath, it's all over.
Your eyes are sharp.
Track them from the crow's nest.
What do I do?
That lookout post is a glider.
See the crank?
Yeah.
-Turn it clockwise.
Once it's locked,
the upper lever unfolds the wings.
Use the wire to stabilize them.
Figure out how to steer as you go!
-Sheeta, you there?
-Yes.
Get back down here.
-Why?
Because you're a girl!
But so are you!
Besides,
I'm a mountain girl with sharp eyes.
-Sheeta!
-Please.
Pazu agrees.
Once you're aloft,
the voice tube won't work.
See the head set?
You mean this, right?
Wow...
Okay. I'll give it a try. Release us.
Here goes.
They're gone.
Slipped into the clouds.
Look sharp! They could be anywhere.
Aye!
Hold on tight.
What's wrong!
We're fine.
Just ran into a gust of wind.
We're keeping watch.
-Scared?
-No.
I'm getting the hang of it.
Rough skies ahead.
Sheeta, get the rope from my bag.
Okay.
-Tie yourself to me.
-Okay.
The mercury's dropping, Mama...
Lousy luck. Storm coming up...
How long 'til dawn?
One more hour.
It's dawn.
Strange that the sun's rising
on that side...
I know! We're supposed
to be heading east. Bridge!
What! We're heading north?
The compass is pointing east.
The shifting winds
must have put us off course.
-Look!
-What is it? Goliath?
It's a cloud. A huge one...
A cloud?
It's headed for us!
A castle in the sky...
We're headed into a low pressure system.
Turn her away, full speed!
It's sucking us in.
Hold tight, we can't help!
The helm won't move!
Where's your brute strength?
Engine's burning up!
Stop whining and figure something out!
We're clearing the clouds!
Sheeta, the ocean!
The Dragon's Lair!
So this is the Dragon's Lair...
Just as Dad said.
The wind's blowing the other way.
Look out, a wall of wind!
Mama! It's sucking us in!
Don't give up! Be a man!
Bridge! It's Laputa!
What was that?
Dad saw Laputa inside the Dragon's Lair.
Don't be ridiculous!
It'll tear you to pieces!
Pazu! Look.
Just what we need.
Let's go for it! Dad did it.
He made it back.
All right, into the Dragon's Lair!
Got 'em!
Our ship's in danger. We must withdraw.
-Stay on course.
-What?
The light's pointing right into the cloud.
Laputa's in there.
Stay on course. We'll find a way in.
-Here we go, Sheeta!
-Okay.
Sheeta, Sheeta! Are you all right?
Look...
Laputa...
I'm sorry.
Wait... I tied it really tight.
My hands are shaking...
We did it!
Birds...
Where is everyone?
Coming to greet you?
But I don't have the stone.
I'll cut the rope.
-What are you doing!
-Wait.
Please don't break that.
We need it to get home.
A flycatcher's nest!
That's why he's here?
See? All your eggs are fine.
The birds aren't afraid.
It says to follow.
-You understand it?
-Just intuition.
It's a city...
What an amazing place...
You can see the sky!
If their science
was so advanced, what happened?
It's a grave.
I wish I could read the writing.
Someone left flowers.
Do you leave the flowers?
-Pazu!
-It's a different robot!
It must've broken down long ago...
Probably a gardener robot.
It protected this place
even after the people went away.
You picked flowers for the grave.
Thank you.
Are you all alone?
Are there any other robots here?
He doesn't seem to be lonely.
He's got friends and birds' nests
to look after...
This way!
This section's been destroyed.
They got the Tiger Moth.
I hope the pirates are okay.
Sheeta, look there!
They're prisoners!
They hang pirates.
-We must help them.
-Let's go!
We found a way in.
Look at this, mountains of treasure.
W... What?
Wow...
Want some?
I'll give you plenty of rope.
Have you reported that we found Laputa?
Just about to.
Make the code good and complicated.
Hey! No looting!
The perfect distraction for those idiots.
What amazing roots.
You can climb trees, can't you?
I see a way.
No better than thieves.
If they reach the garden...!
Sheeta, let's find the stone!
It's the only way to stop them.
I was wondering why the clouds parted.
It was so they could land.
Was it my spell?
Muska was right. The seal's broken.
The kingdom's waking up.
It's welcomed the visitor with the stone.
But Muska will become king.
He's got much worse in mind.
But what do I do
when I get the stone back...
Wait, that spell!
You mean... the destruction spell?
Down and around.
-I'll go first.
-Okay.
It's here somewhere.
Please, God...
This is it!
It's that kid.
No!
Don't shoot! Capture her.
Well, if it isn't the little princess.
Sheeta! Damn!
What is it, Colonel?
The last of the pirates.
There's one right under you.
Yes sir!
Sheeta, wait for me!
Pazu!
Grenades!
Is that Pazu?
What was that?
No, it wasn't.
-What's wrong?
-Over here!
The general is over there.
Militia, fall in on the double.
Dola!
They've got Sheeta.
I'm going after her. I'll cut your ropes.
Get out of here.
Hey, wait!
Take this.
Thanks.
The boy has become a man.
What!
Muska destroyed all the radio equipment?
Yes, while the ship was lightly guarded.
Several guards are badly wounded.
The colonel entered
the inner palace with the girl.
The soldiers saw him.
That upstart's finally showing his colors.
Hunt him down and arrest him!
All units!
Hey! Hurry!
Shoot if he resists!
Find the entrance.
Where are we, Colonel?
Laputa's core.
The castle above is just a trifle.
All of Laputa's knowledge
is crystallized here.
You two wait here.
Colonel!
Only royalty may enter the sacred area.
What is this!
The roots have invaded...
Eventually, we'll burn them all.
Come, this way.
Darn it...
Yes...
This is it!
Here, too!
Screw it...
Found it!
Behold the giant crystal!
Source of Laputa's power.
Fantastic.
It has awaited the king's return
for 700 years.
700 years?
Your family forgot even that?
The black rock! As the epics described!
I can read it. I know what it says!
Just who are you?
I too have an ancient,
secret name, Lucita.
My name is Romuska Palo Ur Laputa.
We are descended
from the same royal family.
Later it split into two branches.
Not even a crack. It's indestructible.
Deploy all our explosives.
Force won't be necessary, Your Excellency.
Muska, where are you!
What are you waiting for, General?
All right, after me!
Forward!
What is this! Muska, where are you?
Silence!
What on earth!
Watch your tongue.
You're in the presence of Laputa's king.
Are you insane?
Let's celebrate Laputa's return
with a demonstration of its power.
Sheeta!
Behold Laputa's thunder!
Sheeta.
It's the heavenly fire that
destroyed Sodom and Gomorrah.
It's the Ramayana's Arrow of Indra.
The world shall bow down
before Laputa once more!
Wonderful, Muska. You're a hero.
A monumental achievement.
What?
I grow tired of your stupid face.
Run, everyone!
Die!
-It's those monsters!
-Look at them...
Run!
Are the Flaptors okay?
Ready to fly!
Let's hurry!
Quiet. Keep your voice down.
What are those two doing?
I'll have to leave them behind.
I advise you not to anger me.
We'll be alone here for a long time.
They should've escaped.
You think you can fight me?
Robots!
Sheeta!
Fantastic!
A marvelous display, no?
Die, you insects!
How dare you!
Damn.
Be a good girl, give it back.
Please, open!
Just where will you go?
Open!
Sheeta!
Pazu!
-Pazu!
-Sheeta!
Sheeta!
-Pazu!
-Sheeta!
I'm coming. Damn.
Get back!
Take this, hurry! Muska's coming, quick!
Throw it into the sea.
Sheeta!
Hold onto that stone.
I'll trade her life for it.
Get up! No more hide and seek.
How delightful that it should end
in the throne room.
Come here!
The throne room?
This will be our grave.
What is a king
when his country lies ruined?
I won't give you the stone.
You'll die, trapped here with me.
There's no escape.
This is why Laputa died out.
There's a song in my valley...
Put down your roots in the soil
Live together with the wind
Pass the winter with the seeds
Sing in the spring with the birds
Your weapons may be powerful.
Your pitiful robots may be numerous.
But you can't survive
away from the earth.
Laputa will not die. It will rise again.
Its power is the stuff
of humanity's dreams.
Next, I shoot off your ears!
Beg for your life.
Make the kid hand over the stone.
Wait!
The stone's hidden.
You can shoot, but you won't get it.
Stay away, Pazu. He'll kill us both.
I'll spare her life if you tell me
where the stone is.
Or do you intend to conquer me
with that cannon of yours?
Let me talk to Sheeta alone.
Run away. Take the stone and run!
Three minutes.
Pazu.
Sheeta, calm down and listen.
Teach me that spell.
I'll say it with you.
Put your hand in mine.
I cut the pirates' ropes.
Time's up. What do you say?
My eyes! My eyes!
I can't see...
Mama, it's collapsing!
All right, let's go. Hurry!
Hurry!
Look, the bottom's falling out!
Sheeta was such a nice girl...
They used the spell of destruction.
Those kids saved Laputa from those idiots.
It's stopping!
A crystal! A humongous one!
It's rising.
The tree... it's carrying it away.
Chase it!
You're heavy, get off.
I can't!
Sheeta!
Pazu...
The roots protected us.
We can still use this.
Here goes.
What are you doing, we're not moving.
Of course not, we're overloaded.
It's Sheeta!
She's alive!
It's the kid!
Dola!
Thank God you're alive!
You guys okay?
Oh, no! My galleon's wrecked...
Oh, stop blubbering.
We'll build a better ship!
You poor child, the worst
is having your hair hacked off...
-I can't breathe!
-Sorry.
Pathetic.
All that work, and only this to show.
We ran out of time!