5 Centimeters Per Second
Episode 1
You know...
I've heard it's 5 centimeters per second.
Huh? What is?
The speed at which cherry
blossom petals fall.
5 centimeters per second.
Hmm...
You sure know a lot about
that stuff, Akari.
Say...
Doesn't it remind you of snow?
You think so?
Hey!
Wait up!
Akari!
Takaki!
I hope we can watch the cherry blossoms
together again next year!
Tale of Cherry Blossoms
Dear Takaki Tono,
It's been a long time.
It gets pretty hot during
the summer here,
In 1900, at the age of thirty-three,
but it's better than
it was in Tokyo.
Looking back, though, I still enjoyed
those muggy Tokyo summers.
Soseki Natsume was sent to Great Britain
for a little over two years to study...
Asphalt hot enough to melt...
Skyscrapers that almost shimmered...
And frigid air conditioning
in the stores and subway.
We last saw each other at our
grade school graduation.
Pick up the pace!
It's been six months.
Shimada!
Run! Faster!
Say, Takaki...
Do you still remember me?
Dear Takaki,
Student Council
Thanks for replying.
I was happy to get your letter.
Summer's over and the autumn
leaves here are gorgeous.
The day before yesterday, I pulled
out my first sweater of the year.
Takaki.
Yeah?
Whatcha got? A love letter?
No.
Sorry to make you do all the work.
No problem. It didn't take that long.
Thanks.
Say, are you really moving?
Oh, yeah.
At the end of the school year.
Where to?
Kagoshima. My parents.
Oh...
I'll miss you.
I have to wake up early
these days for my club,
so I'm writing this letter on the train.
I got my hair cut the other day.
It's so short my ears stick out.
You probably
Friday's forecast calls for cloudy
skies with a chance of sunshine.
wouldn't recognize
me if you saw me now.
Northern Kanto will see...
- I'm home.
- Welcome back.
Dear Akari Shinohara,
I'm sure you're also changing
too, little by little.
Dear Takaki,
How have you been doing
as the weather grows cold?
It's already snowed
here a few times.
Whenever it does, I have to
really bundle up to go to school.
It hasn't snowed in Tokyo yet, has it?
Even though I've moved, I'm still in
the habit of checking Tokyo's weather.
Maybe it'll rain...
Practicing indoors won't
be any better.
Hey, you guys ever
been to Tochigi?
Huh? Where?
Tochigi.
Nope.
Know how to get there?
Beats me...
Bullet train?
It's pretty far...
Rookies!
Yes!
Three laps to go!
Fight-o! Fight-o!
I was surprised to hear that
you're the one moving this time.
Visiting the Sea of Japan in Winter
We' re both used to switching
schools by now,
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
but Kagoshima's a little...
...farther than usual, I guess.
The fact that you'll be so far away that
I can't just hop on a train to go see you...
...makes me a little sad, I have to say.
Iwafune
I wish the very best
for you at your new home.
Dear Takaki,
I'm so glad that we've promised
to meet on March 4th.
It's been a year since
we last saw each other.
I'm getting a little nervous.
There's a giant cherry
tree where I live.
Come spring, its petals...
...will probably fall at
5 centimeters per second.
I hope that spring arrives
the same time you do.
Wanna stop somewhere?
I dunno... It's raining.
The forecast said we'll have
snow by nightfall.
Yeah? No wonder it's so cold.
Gotokuji 3:54 PM Departure
(Odakyu Line - 150 yen)
Shinjuku 4:26 PM Departure
(Saikyo Line)
Omiya 5:04 PM Departure
(Utsunomiya Line)
(Kuki 6:00 PM Arrival)
Oyama 6:23 Departure
(Ryomo Line)
Iwafune 6:45 PM Arrival
Meet at 7 PM
Takaki, let's head to practice.
Sure.
Actually, I'll have to skip out today.
Getting ready to move?
Something like that.
Sorry.
Shinjuku Omiya Oyama Iwafune
Saikyo Line Ryomo Line
Utsunomiya Line
Here!
Chugga-
The Noodle
Chugga
Saitama!
Highway!
So far...
I appreciate you coming all
the way to the station near me.
- Really?
- No doubt about it.
It's a long trip, though,
so please be careful.
I'll be waiting in the station
at seven as planned.
About to arrive...
It began snowing in the afternoon...
...on the day we were supposed to meet.
Oh!
Look, Takaki.
It's Chobi the cat.
He's always hanging out here, huh?
But he's all alone today.
What happened to Mimi?
You must be lonely.
How's that book?
Pretty good.
I read about four billion years'
worth last night.
How far are you?
I'm at the part where
Anomalocaris start showing up.
- The Cambrian Period!
I love the Hallucigenia.
They look like this.
Yeah, I see the resemblance.
What's your favorite?
The Opabinia guess.
Oh, the one with five eyes.
I believed that Akari and
I were kindred spirits.
I would like everyone to meet Takaki Tono.
Takaki
Tono
It was one year after I moved to Tokyo...
that Akari
This is your new classmate,
Akari
Shinohara
joined our class.
Akari Shinohara.
We were both small and prone to illness;
preferring the library to playing outdoors.
Judith Worthy
Le Guin
Garden in the Sky
A Wizard of Earthsea
Lewis
Prince Caspian
Akari Shinonara
Takaki Tono
Akari Shinonara Takaki Tono
Akari Shinonara
It was only natural for us to grow close,
though we were
Akari
Takaki
Just married
Perfect couple
teased by our
classmates as a result.
But...
It didn't bother us, because
we had each other.
Wow.
I thought we'd eventually go
to the same middle school.
I thought we'd always
be together.
For some reason,
I honestly believed that.
Shinjuku. Shinjuku. This is the final stop.
Please take caution...
You can transfer here to the JR line,
Keio line, or the subway.
That was the first time I'd gone to
Shinjuku Station by myself,
and the first time I'd ever
ridden those trains.
My heart wouldn't stop pounding.
I was on my way...
...to see Akari.
How'd it go with that guy?
Who?
Y'know, the one from Nishi-Sho?
Ew. I've got
We'll soon be stopping at
- ...better taste than that.
- What?
Musashi-Urawa.Musashi-Urawa.
At Musashi-Urawa, there will be...
There will be a four-minute delay while
we wait for an express train.
Passengers needing to reach Yonohommachi
and Omiya quickly should transfer...
Um... My name is Akari Shinohara.
Um...
Is Takaki there?
It's Akari.
Huh? You're moving?
What about Nishi Middle?
You were already accepted.
I'm being transferred to a
public school in Tochigi.
I'm sorry.
No, there's no reason
for you to apologize.
I asked if I could stay with
my aunt in Katsushika,
but they said I'm not old enough.
I see.
It's okay.
You don't...
I'm sorry...
I'd pressed the phone
against my ear so hard...
...that I could feel
Akari's pain through it.
But I couldn't do
anything for her.
That was a good restaurant.
- Yeah. See you later.
- Yeah.
The transfer terminal was
filled with people on their way home.
Everybody's shoes were
soaked by the snow.
I could smell the cold, unique
scent of urban snow in the air.
Attention, all passengers.
The Utsonomiya line bound
for Oyama and Utsunomiya...
...has been delayed by snow
by approximately eight minutes.
We apologize for any potential inconvenience,
And request your patience
and understanding at this time.
Until that moment, I hadn't even considered
that the train might be late.
My anxiety suddenly
began to grow.
Due to snowy conditions, this train is
running approximately ten minutes late.
We apologize for any
potential inconvenience.
Shortly after passing Omiya Station,
I began to notice how there
weren't many buildings around.
Next stop, Kuki. Kuki.
We apologize for the
delay in our arrival.
Passengers transferring to the
Tobu-Isesaki line should use Gate 5.
Due to other delays, this train will be
stopping at this station for ten minutes.
We apologize for any
potential inconvenience,
and request your patience
and understanding at this time.
Sorry about that.
Due to other delays, this train will be
stopping at this station for ten minutes.
We apologize for any
potential inconvenience,
and request your patience
and understanding at this time.
Nogi. Nogi.
Once again, we offer
our sincerest apologies.
Due to other delays, this train will be
stopping at this station for the time being.
We apologize for any
potential inconvenience,
I couldn't believe
and request your patience
and understanding at this time.
how far apart the stations were,
and how long the train
stopped at each one.
Nogi
Iwafune
The unfamiliar snowy
plain outside my window,
the agonizingly
slow crawl of time,
and the uncomfortable
hunger pangs,
only made me feel more helpless.
It was past our meeting time.
Akari had probably started to worry.
To Akari
On that day...
The day when Akari called me...
I had no comforting words to offer her,
though she was clearly suffering
more than I was.
I was so ashamed of myself.
As we humbly reflect upon
the efforts
of our teachers...
Well... I guess this is goodbye.
Let's go
- ...somewhere over spring break!
- And do what?
I received the first letter from
Akari six months later,
during my first summer in middle school.
I memorized her every word.
Two weeks before we were to meet,
I began writing a letter to hand to her.
There were so many, many things...
...that I wanted to tell her,
had to tell her...
We apologize for the long wait.
Service to Utsunomiya
will continue momentarily.
Oyama. Oyama.
Passengers for the Tohoku
bullet train must transfer here.
Boarding for the Tohoku bullet train
to Morioka will be at Platform 1.
Passengers bound for Tokyo
should board at Platform 5.
Boarding for the
Mito line
will be at Platform 15.
Attention, all passengers.
The Ryomo line has been
delayed by heavy snowfall.
We apologize for any
potential inconvenience,
and request your patience and
understanding until the train arrives.
The next train
I had no choice but to make my way
bound for Takasaki
is expected to depart at 8:15 PM.
To the station where
Akari was waiting.
The Ashikaga-Maebashi train bound for
Takasaki is now arriving at Platform 8.
Please remain behind the line.
Attention, all passengers.
This train will be stopping due to
delays caused by the snow.
We apologize for any inconvenience.
We are presently unable to determine
when service will resume.
Again.
The train will be stopping due to
scheduling delays caused by the snow.
We apologize for any inconvenience.
We are presently unable to determine
when service will resume.
Dear Takaki,
How are you doing?
I have to wake up early for my club,
so I'm writing this letter on the train.
When I read Akari's letters,
for some reason I always
pictured her alone.
The train ended up parked out there,
in the middle of nowhere,
for two more hours.
Each minute felt like an eternity...
I could sense hovering malice...
...as time slowly crept by.
But I could only grit my teeth...
...and choke back my tears.
Akari...
I hope that...
...you already...
...went home.
The Ashikaga-Maebashi train bound for
Takasaki is now arriving at Platform 3.
This train will be stopping here
briefly due to a snow delay.
Akari...
It's so good.
Really?
It's just roasted green tea.
Roasted green tea?
Never had it.
Liar.
I guarantee that you have.
You sure?
Yep.
And, here.
I made it myself, so I can't
vouch for the taste...
But you can try it, if you want.
Thank you.
I'm starving.
How is it?
The best food I've ever tasted in my life.
Gimme a break.
I'm serious.
It's just because you're hungry.
You sure?
Yep.
But I'll have some too.
You're moving soon, right?
Yeah, next week.
Kagoshima, huh?
It's pretty far away.
Yeah.
Same goes for Tochigi, though.
You're stranded out here now.
We'll be closing up soon.
- There won't be any
more trains coming in.
- Oh, okay.
It's snowing hard. You kids be careful.
We will.
Look, there's the tree.
The one you mentioned in your letter?
Yeah, the cherry tree.
Say...
Doesn't it remind you of snow?
Yeah, it does.
In that moment,
I think I realized where eternity,
the heart, and the soul, truly exist.
It was like I was sharing every experience
from my thirteen years on this planet.
But then, in the next moment...
...I felt unbearably sad.
What was I supposed to do with
Akari's warmth, her soul?
I didn't know the answer.
And that was when it became clear to me...
...that we wouldn't always be together.
We still had our entire
lives before us.
So much time left...
But soon enough,
my worries melted away,
leaving only the sensation
of Akari's soft lips on mine.
We spent that night...
...in a small shed on the
outskirts of a farm.
We wrapped ourselves
up in an old blanket...
...and talked away the hours...
...until we finally fell asleep.
In the morning,
the trains were running again,
and we said our goodbyes.
Um...
Takaki.
Takaki...
I know you'll be just fine.
I know it!
Thanks...
Take care of yourself, Akari!
I'll write!
And call!
I never told Akari
about the letter I lost.
To Takaki Tono
Because a single kiss...
...was enough to make me feel
like my whole world had changed.
I longed for the ability to take
care of her, to keep her safe.
And as thoughts of
her consumed me,
I proceeded to stare
out the window.
Episode 1 - Tale of Cherry Blossoms
End
Episode 2
Kanae, are you going back
there after school?
Yup.
That okay with you?
Sure.
But don't forget to study.
I won't!
Okay.
Morning.
Good morning, Takaki.
You're sure here early.
So are you.
I'm guessing you went
down to the beach?
Yup.
You're so dedicated.
Not really...
See you later, Takaki.
Right.
Listen up.
It's decision-making time, folks.
This is due on Monday.
Make sure you discuss
it with your parents.
Career Plan
Sasaki's going to college in Tokyo.
Wow...
I'm shooting for a junior
college in Kumamoto.
What about you, Kanae?
Huh?
Um...
You gonna look for a job?
You don't think about
anything, do you?
Except your precious Takaki.
I bet he has a girlfriend
back in Tokyo.
Don't say that!
Still having trouble?
Yeah, I don't know what
I'm doing wrong.
Don't stress about it too much.
You'll be back on the waves
before you know it.
I wish I had your positive attitude.
What's the rush?
The way things are going, I won't have
time to tell him before we graduate.
Thanks, sis.
I can take you home.
It's okay. I'll go on my Cub.
Oh, Kanae.
You heading home now?
Yep. And you?
Yeah.
Wanna go together?
If I had a tail like a dog's,
it would've wagged so hard,
my glee would've been plain as day.
But my sigh of relief over
not being a dog...
...was also a sigh of disgust
at how stupid I sounded.
Despite all that,
I was overjoyed to be
riding home with Takaki.
From the moment I met him,
2nd Year, Class 1
I could tell Takaki was
This is Takaki Tono from Tokyo.
Please introduce yourself.
somehow different from the other boys.
Takaki Tono
I'm Takaki Tono.
I'm used to moving around
because of my parents' jobs,
but I'm not used to living
on this island yet.
I hope to get to know everyone.
I fell in love with him the
day he came to our school.
I wanted to go to the same
high school as him...
Okay, let's move on to the next request.
...so I worked my butt off to get accepted.
Every time I saw him,
- There's nothing to do out here.
- It's still better than Tokyo.
I fell deeper in love.
I was so scared...
And every day hurt...
But I was so happy
whenever I saw him...
I couldn't help myself.
You're so predictable.
I love the way it tastes.
You're always so sincere.
Yeah.
I'll wait outside.
Okay...
Just this, please.
That'll be ninety yen.
Here you go.
Thanks for shopping here.
Welcome back.
What'd you get?
Well...
I thought about it, and decided
to stick with this yogurt drink.
I would spot Takaki texting
someone from time to time.
And every single time,
Guard Earth from Space
I'd wish that it was me.
I just couldn't help myself.
Hi, Cub! I'm home!
That's right, Cubbie... I'm back.
We have an announcement
from the town council.
Sakai's will be the next gas
station on weekend duty.
Kanae Sumida from Class 3-1,
Mr. Ito would like to see you.
Please report to the guidance
counselor's office.
That's your girlfriend.
She's not my girlfriend.
Career Plan - Kanae Sumida
You're the only one who
hasn't turned one in.
I'm sorry.
Now look here.
I probably shouldn't say this,
but you don't need to worry
so much about it.
Has Ms. Sumida suggested anything?
No.
If you can't make up your mind,
you could always go to an
in-prefecture junior college.
But...
My sister has nothing
to do with this.
I mean...
I can't even surf, after
I begged her to teach me...
I can't tell the boy
I like how I feel...
I can't do anything...
Thanks for shopping here.
Oh, you're welcome.
Bye.
Whenever I was around Takaki,
I would get a pain in my chest.
Takaki.
Kanae?
What's up?
How'd you find me?
I saw your scooter, so I stopped.
Do you mind?
Nah, it's fine.
I'm happy to see you.
I missed you in the
parking lot today.
Same here.
He's so nice.
So nice it sometimes
makes me want to cry.
Say, are you applying
to any colleges?
Yeah, I'm aiming for one in Tokyo.
Tokyo?
I see...
I'm not surprised.
Why's that?
You just look like you're
dying to get out of here.
What about you?
Well...
I have no idea what tomorrow will hold.
That's probably how
most people feel.
Yeah right!
You included?
Of course.
But you look like you've
got it all figured out.
I wish.
I spend all my time hesitating.
I struggle to do the best I can.
No time to relax.
Really?
I didn't know.
A paper airplane?
Yeah.
Detour
National Space Development Agency ofJapan
Wow...
I've heard it's 5 kilometers per hour.
Huh?
The speed at which it travels
to Minamitane's launch pad.
Oh.
They're going to launch one this
year for the first time in a while.
I know. It's headed for the
edge of the solar system.
The journey will take years.
You should talk to Kanae
about her future.
She can be so indecisive.
She'll be fine.
She's not a kid anymore.
I used to be just like her.
Guess what, Cub.
Takaki doesn't know what
he wants to do either.
He's just like me.
It was a journey more lonely
than I could possibly imagine.
Plunging headlong through
impenetrable darkness,
with next to no chance of spotting
a single atom of hydrogen...
A desperate search of the abyss,
for the secrets of this world...
How far will we go in search
of those answers?
How far are we able to?
Subject: What I dreamt this morning
"I was walking through a field on
another planet with that same girl.
As usual, I couldn't see her face.
But it all felt very familiar."
Save message?
No
When did I start writing messages
I could never send?
Kanae, did you figure out
what you want to do?
No, not yet.
But it's okay.
I've decided something.
I'll just take everything
step-by-step.
I'm off!
After that day, a number
of typhoons passed by,
and the island became
a little cooler each time.
The wind rustling the sugarcane
fields became a little chillier.
The sky felt a little higher.
The outlines of the clouds were softer,
and the students who rode their Cubs to
school began wearing light jackets.
My first successful attempt
to ride a wave in six months...
...came at the end of summer's warmth,
in the middle of October.
This evening's forecast calls for sunny skies,
with winds of up to 8 meters per second.
I heard Yamada asked Sasaki out.
Wow.
Huh?
You seem happy today, Kanae.
Finally make progress with Takaki?
Hehe.
No way!
Make sure you remember this formula.
Today's the day
It'll be on the final.
I tell Takaki how I feel.
If I can't do it on the day I rode a wave,
then it's never going to happen.
Kanae.
Ta...
Takaki...
You heading home now?
Yeah.
I see.
Let's go together.
Oh? You made up your
mind pretty quick today.
Yep.
Um...
What's wrong?
...being so nice to me...
Huh?
Nothing...
Sorry, forget it.
Having trouble?
Yeah.
That's weird.
No good?
Yeah...
The spark plug might be dead.
Was this a hand-me-down?
Yeah, it was my sister's.
Did it sputter when you accelerated?
It might have.
You'll have to leave it here for now.
Ask someone from your
family to pick it up later.
I'll walk you home.
What?
I can walk by myself.
You can go home.
It's not that far from here.
And I feel like walking anyway.
Takaki...
Please...
What's wrong?
I'm sorry...
It's nothing...
Kanae?
Please...
Stop being...
...so nice to me.
We're so desperate to
reach beyond the clouds...
...that we launched these
massive objects...
...while we stared
off into the distance.
I think that was when I realized...
...what made Takaki different
from everybody else.
And that was also when...
...it became painfully clear...
...that he didn't truly see me.
That's why I couldn't bring myself
to tell him how I felt that day.
Takaki was a good guy...
An incredibly nice guy...
But he was always looking
at something beyond me.
Something very far away.
Takaki would never
reciprocate my feelings.
And yet...
And yet I was certain that...
...come tomorrow, the next day,
and every day after that,
I wouldn't be able to keep
myself from loving him.
And as I drowned in thoughts of him,
I proceeded to cry myself to sleep.
Episode 2 - Cosmonaut
End
Episode 3
March 2008
2/14-22 Meeting - Sangen-Jaya
3/2 (Mon)
3/1~4 API Meeting
Specifications Finalized
4/6 API Delivered
(Mon, Tue, Sat)
Ishii
4/14 Shinjuku CG
I couldn't shake the feeling...
...that if I were to turn around,
she would do the same.
Today's last Chuo-Sobu line train
bound for Tokyo has arrived.
You should stay until New Year's.
I know.
But I need to get everything ready.
That's true.
You should cook something
nice for him.
I will.
Let us know if anything
comes up, Akari.
I'll be fine.
We'll see each other at the
wedding next month,
so you don't need
to worry so much.
The train is approaching the platform 2.
It's cold out. You should head home.
Last night, I had a dream
of days gone by.
Of when he and I were still children.
It was probably because of the letter
Dear Takaki Tono
I found yesterday.
"Hello, Takaki.
It's been a while. How are you?
After some thinking, I've decided
there's something I need to tell you."
Ms. Takagi, could you process this for me?
Message sent
Mr. Shirokai, you have a call on line two.
Miss Mizuno.
Ah, yes?
Coming to the meeting?
Yes.
I was just going through
the motions of life.
Sorrow was building
wherever I looked.
On my bedsheets.
On my toothbrush.
In my cell phone history.
"I still love you."
Said a message from the woman I'd
been with for the past three years.
"But after a thousand
message exchanges,
our hearts have only grown
closer by 1 centimeter."
For the past few years,
I had been trying to move on.
I was grasping for something
I couldn't reach.
I didn't even know what it was.
Not knowing the root
of these violent feelings,
I could only slave away at my work.
The next thing I knew,
I felt the pain of watching
my heart go numb.
One morning,
I discovered that I had completely lost...
...those sincere feelings I once had.
I reached the end of my rope...
...and quit my job.
Last night, I had a dream.
A dream of days gone by.
In the dream, we were
still thirteen years old.
We were in the middle of a
large field blanketed by snow.
Faint artificial light shined
from houses in the distance.
"Japan's Deep Space Exploration Probe Elish
Finally Exits Solar System"
Our footprints were all that
blemished the virgin snow.
And...
We believed we would one day watch
the cherry blossoms together again.
Of that, we had no doubt.
Of that, we were certain.
5 Centimeters Per Second
Everywhere I go, I look for you.
I look on platforms,
and in windows from alleys.
Knowing I'll never find you there.
If my wish comes true,
I'd go straight to you.
I'd do everything I ever wanted to do.
I'd hold you with all the power
I have gained in my life.
Anybody can help me forget my loneliness.
But it has to be you...
...because the stars are so bright.
One more time.
I pray for the seasons to stand still.
I want to go back to those carefree days.
Everywhere I go, I look for you.
At the intersection.
In my dreams every night.
Knowing I'd never find you there.
If I could perform a miracle,
I would show you how...
...I am different now,
on this new morning.
I'd tell you "I love you,"
though I never could before.
Memories of summer
spin round and round.
I can't even hear my heartbeat.
Everywhere I go, I look for you.
Every morning.
In the town of Sakuragi-Cho.
Knowing I'd never find you there.
If my wish comes true,
I'd go straight to you.
I'd do everything I'd ever wanted to do.
I'd hold you with all the power
I have gained in my life.
I always look for signs of you.
In the shops on my travels.
Even in newspaper columns.
Knowing I'd never find you there.
If I could perform a miracle,
I would show you how...
...I am different now,
on a new morning.
I'd tell you "I love you,"
though I never could before.
Everywhere I look,
I always look for your smile.
At the crossing,
waiting for the trains to pass.
Knowing I'll never find you there.
If I were born again,
I'd come to you.
For there's nothing I want in this world...
...besides your love.
Nothing else matters.
The End