Adonis?
Thought you got scared.
About to roll without you.
Come on, bro.
Aight.
Hey, yo, Adonis. This way.
Hey, yo,
H should be expecting us.
- Here we go.
It's showtime.
- Mm-hmm.
Hold up. Shh, shh.
About time, young gun.
Back there.
For sure.
- Dame.
- What's the deal, man?
-What, you got me next?
-I got you, champ.
My guy.
-Hey, Dame.
-What's up?
-Who's your friend?
-My name's Donnie.
Nice to meet you.
How y'all doing today?
Boy, come on, man.
Come on. Focus up, man.
We got plenty of time
for that.
Trust.
Ooh. Hello, pot.
Man, you see that ring?
That's easy money.
And I ain't even tell you
who you've got yet.
Come on.
Let's get it.
Michael Fitzbaum.
Orthodox. Solid fighter.
Say he gonna be the first cat
to knock you out.
Hey, but he do got a good jab.
He overreaches though.
He tore his labrum last year
playing football
for Pali, so...
-Make him miss.
-Yeah.
The right gonna be open.
Aight.
On you?
Come on, man.
Yeah.
See you out there.
First round knockout. Damian.
Ladies and gentlemen,
tonight's fighters
for the regional
Golden Gloves title.
6'2'',
from Pacific Palisades,
California,
-Michael Fitzbaum.
6'1'', fighting out of
the Crenshaw District
of Los Angeles,
-"Diamond" Dame Anderson.
- Come on, Dame!
Let's go.
- Yeah.
Yeah!
-Fight.
Show him
what you're made of, boy.
Watch the right.
Hey, watch that jab.
Hey, be patient. Be patient.
Keep that guard up, bro.
Wait for it.
It's gonna come to you.
Watch this. Checkmate.
-Oh, my God! Come on!
And the winner,
by way of knockout,
-new Golden Gloves champion...
-What'd I say, boy?
That's how I do.
..."Diamond" Dame Anderson!
Yeah.
Let's get it, boy.
Let's get it, man.
What did I tell you, huh?
What'd I tell you?
I sat that boy down.
That straight right,
it's clean.
That's the perfect punch.
Bro, but when
you put him to sleep, though,
everybody was--
-What?
He was over there like--
Man, the first thing
I'ma do, man--
The first thing I'ma do,
I'ma get me
one of them big-ass diamonds.
-Hey.
I'ma get you one too,
little homey.
Hey.
Yes, sir.
-Appreciate you.
- No doubt, man.
-For real.
-No doubt.
You know, actually,
I got you something too.
It belonged to my pops.
It's original.
Rumble in the Jungle?
Yeah.
I'ma get there one day.
Yeah, I'ma get there.
I'ma win nationals,
taking home
the gold at the Olympics,
and then I'm turning pro.
Don't trip.
You'll be right there with me.
Shit, someone gotta
carry my bags.
-Bro, why you gotta
play with me like that, bro?
I already know
what I want. What you getting?
- Cherry pie, apple pie.
- Cherry pie?
-Got you. Chili cheese fries?
-Yeah, come on.
-Pineapple soda?
-All that.
All on you, boy. Big money.
Leon?
Huh?
Don't remember me, do you?
Am I supposed to remember you?
-Not so little anymore.
My name's Donnie.
You remember me now?
We're live, round one,
Cape Town, South Africa,
as Adonis Creed
battles his old rival
in what Creed has said
will be his final fight.
Todd Grisham
alongside the champion,
Jessica McCaskill.
And right out of the gate
with an impressive combo.
Is Conlan looking this good
or Creed looking this bad?
If he doesn't
do something fast,
he's going to end
his historic career
with another loss to Conlan.
-There we go.
-Put that jab in his face.
Okay. Same Creed.
Ain't nothing changed.
Conlan stalking his prey,
pushing Creed
towards the corner.
You've got to wonder
if the moment
is getting to Creed here.
Conlan is banging away
with the right hand.
Look to your right.
Seems to be
the same combination
he's throwing over and over,
and Creed can't stop it.
Creed,
getting out of the corner.
Good jab,
but Conlan not fazed at all.
Keep that in his face.
Keep that jab out there.
- Big left
from Conlan.
-Get off that rope.
Oh, he's got him on the ropes.
Clean shots landing.
Creed taking quite a beating.
-And wow.
Conlan almost had him.
Next round's
gonna hurt, champ.
Next round's gonna hurt.
You okay, Donnie?
Come on, Donnie.
You gotta work, baby.
Yo,
what you smiling for, dawg?
He over there
beating you worse
than last time.
Like, is something I miss
that's funny?
Yeah, man. Checkmate.
Checkmate? Oh, okay.
You sure about that?
I ain't never been scared
of a little contact.
I'm going out how I came in.
Man, you're crazy, all right.
-How you feeling?
Looking great.
- I'm just warming up.
He had a good run.
But it's time
to take back what's ours.
Creed's had
a remarkable career,
but you wonder if Father Time
has finally caught up
with the champ.
This is getting dangerous
for Creed.
Ooh, the champ
finally lands one.
Come on, Donnie. Work this.
Show him who's champ.
Beautiful, Ricky.
Beautiful. Just like that.
One more time.
And down goes Conlan!
He goes down!
What a moment!
And I don't think
he's gonna get up, Jessica.
Three, four, five,
six, seven,
eight,
nine,
ten.
Yeah!
And that's it, folks.
-It's over.
What a chess move
from Adonis Creed.
Just incredible.
What a turn. What an ending.
That's how you go out.
Who would expect anything less
from Adonis Creed
as he takes his final bow
on the world stage?
What an exit.
Respect, Conlan.
Hell of a fight.
And that means
we've got a new, undisputed
heavyweight champion
of the world
for the first time
in two decades,
and his name is Adonis Creed.
Okay, okay, okay.
Yes. All right.
♪ Just trying... ♪
♪ And I'm... ♪
♪ And I'm trying my best ♪
♪ Best ♪
This is hot.
-Yeah?
-Yeah, yeah.
This the track you've been
working on for Kehlani?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
We had a good session,
but I don't know.
What you mean you don't know?
Can you send this to me?
-Yes, yes.
-I need this in the car.
How was today?
-It was good. Yeah.
-Yeah?
-Thank you
for holding it down.
-I got you.
Did you get her to bed?
-I did.
-Mmm.
So, I'm not gonna lie.
I had to bribe her
with about six scoops
of ice cream.
I don't even know
how she sleep.
Retirement made you soft,
you know that?
I can't tell that girl no.
I think you had
a couple scoops too
'cause look, you got this.
-Mmm.
-Uh-huh.
-Yeah, that's bad.
- Yeah.
Take that off
before it stains, D.
Oh, I see
what you're trying to do.
What's that?
You're trying to get me naked.
Oh, no, no. I'm definitely
not trying to do that
'cause I'm trying to work.
I see what you were
trying to do.
No, you can just own it.
It's okay.
I know you just wanna
see all this.
- No, no, no.
-Look at that.
No.
-Still hot? Still warm?
-Stop it.
I'm working, D. Please.
I'm working too.
Listen,
I don't get a chance to--
What are you working on?
I don't get no alone time
with you no more
'cause you be hard at work.
I know. Yeah.
-You ain't got no time for me.
-I know.
You ain't got time for--
-I know,
but I don't have time now.
-So come on. You don't?
- No. No.
-Just a little bit.
Just a little bit.
-Mmm.
-Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Don't you miss when...
we used to...
...anywhere.
-Any place?
- Mm-hmm.
Mm-mmm. Okay.
Okay, let's go.
Okay, I just-- I have, like,
about 15 minutes
-because I have to send
these stems.
-Fifteen.
How about 12?
All right.
Twelve will do.
Next stop, Leimert Park.
Body, head. Body, head.
Efficiency over power, baby.
Give it to him.
Technique. Technique, Felix.
You can't just punch
your way through Drago.
We got a plan, so stick to it.
-Come on.
Make him work for it.
- Let's go.
It's not only about power.
It's timing, speed.
-Shit, you're telling me?
Come on now.
-I know, I know.
Keep drilling into him.
Technique. Technique.
-Time.
Hey! Time!
Felix. Get over here.
These guys are trash.
We need a new batch,
and we need it fast.
It's hard.
You've chewed through
most of LA.
You want me to pull back?
You know Drago
ain't taking it easy.
Hey, Felix.
Ven aqui.
What's up, champ?
You wanna help me
with some rounds?
What, and mess up this suit?
I don't think so.
I'm trying
to get you paid, Felix.
We can't get you paid
if you keep knocking out
all these sparring partners,
okay?
You gotta be ready
to fight Drago in four weeks.
You're the champ.
We know you got power.
But it's not always about
how hard you can hit.
-It's about control and focus.
-You're right.
Listen to Duke.
Yes, sir.
See? You play too much.
-Listen to Duke.
- Did you hear that?
"Listen to Duke."
Those three words.
Not "I love you."
Not "take it easy."
None of that.
"Listen to Duke."
I understand
exactly what they're asking.
Drago's got a bigger name,
that's true,
but Felix got the belt.
His split's got to be bigger.
I don't care
if they don't like it.
Tell Drago to call me.
Hey,
let me call you right back.
Hey, my man.
Can I help you?
-Let me get an autograph.
-No, I ain't signing
no autographs.
Would you get off my car?
Oh, homey.
You don't remember me, huh?
You come a long way
from bumming rides
from your mom.
Dame.
- Boy, you had me.
Damian.
Yeah, just got back
to the hood.
Stopped by the old gym,
but, uh...
Yeah, we upgraded
a couple years ago, you know?
I see.
-Damn, it's, uh...
-It's been a minute.
Been a minute.
Hey, I don't wanna take up
your time or nothing, man.
I just wanted to let you know
what's good.
I'm around.
If you wanna catch up,
you know,
you just let me know.
Where you about to head now?
Shit, back to the crib.
You got time to get some grub?
Thank you.
-Thank you.
- Enjoy.
I'm surprised
you still come here
and eat with the common folk.
I mean, when I can.
There's a lot of things
I used to do
that I can't do anymore.
Busy living
that high life, huh?
Yeah.
Guess it comes with the job.
All right.
Yo-- Easy, easy. Damn, bruh.
You know how long it's been
since I had this shit?
How long?
Eighteen years, bro.
You've been down
this whole time?
Had a few years tacked on,
but... yeah.
Just got out last week.
Well, congratulations on that.
Thank you.
Wrote you a few times.
-You did?
Where'd you send 'em?
-Mama Creed's.
She still up in Bel Air?
Yeah, she's still there.
Same house.
But I never got 'em.
You know I watched
every one of your fights
in the pen.
You finally
made it to Africa, huh?
-You seen that?
-Saw that.
Made me proud
how you ended your run.
Look like you still remember
some of them moves
I taught you.
You know what I remember?
You knocking my ass out.
Helping your big ass back up.
Remember that?
-Yeah, you did.
-All right, then.
You got work?
I got plans.
Keep my nose clean.
Keep my PO off my ass.
Mm.
Listen, if there's anything
I can do for you,
if I can help at all,
just ask.
What am I talking about?
You just came home.
Whatever you need. Aight?
Don't hesitate, bruh.
I'm straight, bro.
I'm good.
I got it all situated.
I ain't come to see you
for no handout.
Nah, I didn't mean it
like that. It was...
Respect.
So, what's the plan?
Same program
last time you saw me.
I wanna be champ.
You still wanna box?
Hey, I know I've been
away a long time.
I kept myself in shape.
I got some moves
you ain't seen yet.
Yeah. You...
-You looking diesel.
-I ain't joking.
I'm ready.
I still got gas in the tank.
And I gotta get me that chain.
Can't be "Diamond" Dame
looking bummy.
-"Diamond" Dame.
That's right.
All right.
Come by the gym.
Get you set up with Duke.
-For real?
-Yeah.
For real.
All right, then.
Thank you.
Yo, yo, yo!
-What's so funny?
Oh, nothing. I'm just trying
to convince your mama
to come live with us,
so I can have
my own live-in braider.
Yeah.
Careful what you wish for.
-Oh, I'm not worried.
It's actually not a bad idea.
And how you feeling, Mama?
You good?
I'm good.
- You sure?
- Oh, yeah.
Okay.
I'd be better if my son
showed up on time for dinner.
Ouch. Uh, sorry.
-Mmm.
-I just got caught up.
Mm-hmm.
You're gonna have
your hands full with that one.
We already do.
-No. She's the best.
-Yes, we do.
She is.
-You're the worst.
-Oh, come on, Mama.
- Stop...
You don't mean it.
-Here, Ma.
-Thank you.
B, think that's a good idea?
Baby, not tonight.
But we talked
about this.
- One thing at a time.
- Okay.
Okay. We are not doing this
this evening, okay?
And just so we're straight
and everybody knows,
I am not leaving my house.
Understood?
Mm-hmm.
- Okay.
And I really am fine.
I promise you,
I am not gonna have
another stroke tonight.
Okay?
Have it tomorrow night.
-Mom. That's...
That's not funny.
It's a little funny.
And you're not helping.
You know
that we're worried about you.
-That's it.
We can leave it now.
-I...
And we wanna be careful
after the last one.
I am fine.
Okay?
But what about you?
What's up with you?
Yeah. Where were you, D?
Just ran into
this guy named Dame.
Damian.
Who's he?
Think you might've
checked with me?
This ain't no damn charity.
And homey older than you.
I'm just trying
to give him a break.
Isn't that what we do anyway?
No! This ain't the YMCA.
Look around, Duke.
You see anybody lining up
to get in the ring with Felix?
All I'm saying is,
let him spar.
Felix got a fight coming up,
and we have zero bodies.
I mean, absolutely nobody
wants to get in the ring
with Felix.
I know what you doin', Donnie.
You don't owe this dude shit.
Nothing.
But let's spar.
Let's do it.
Felix, Felix, yo. Listen up.
Adonis brought somebody in
for you to spar.
Hey, hey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
-Huh?
-We on.
Lot of young cats in here.
Young man's game.
Don't worry,
Duke's gonna take care of you.
We back to ground zero.
Champs gotta start somewhere,
right?
All right.
Felix, meet Damian.
He gonna spar with you.
You still remember
how to do that, yeah?
You got this.
Felix, stay focused.
Work on timing.
That's all we need.
Well, I'm just asking.
Mm-hmm.
So, you wanna
teach her how to fight?
That's your advice?
I didn't think I had to,
at a deaf school like that,
-but maybe I was wrong.
-Wait.
What does that mean,
"at a deaf school like that,"
like they're not still kids?
I mean,
what did you expect, Adonis?
Then she should learn
how to defend herself.
Okay, first of all,
I'm not saying that
she shouldn't know
how to defend herself.
I'm just saying
what that means to me
is different
than what it means to you.
What if she's someplace
she's supposed to be safe,
and she's not?
She won't know
how to protect herself.
Where's that coming from?
Nowhere. It's just a fact.
Okay.
Another fact is that,
I think, as parents,
it's actually
our responsibility
to teach her
how to assess her emotions.
So you want Amara, right,
to hold hands with this bully
and start talking
about her feelings?
That's not real life.
Okay, what do you
want her to do?
You want her
to never talk about
her feelings to anyone?
Not even to us,
and all she can do
about them is to hit somebody?
Look,
I know that you think that
that has worked for you,
but now that you don't have
an outlet anymore,
you should think about
maybe talking
about how you feel.
If not to me, to somebody.
Or, I don't know, D.
Get a hobby.
-Okay, I'll get a hobby.
-Oh, yeah?
Yeah, you.
I'ma go down to the studio.
I'ma start
laying tracks with you.
That's not funny, D.
Look,
I know that you think that
you are protecting her, baby,
but she has got to know why
she wants to fight,
not just how to do it.
And the only solution
to every problem
is not a punch in the face.
Yeah, you're right.
And sometimes it is.
All right,
let's just have a good time.
Okay,
I see you made it all right.
Oh, yeah. I just asked him,
"Where the Black family
live at?"
-I'm kidding.
-Yeah.
-What's up, man?
-'Sup?
There's other ones around.
I ain't see none. Here you go.
Thank you.
-Nice to meet you, Ms. Bianca.
-Pleasure.
-You never bought me
no flowers.
-What, you want a kiss?
-Nah. I'm okay.
No, no, it's all right.
-Come here.
-Hey, y'all got
a beautiful home.
- Thank you.
You got
the see-through floors?
Oh.
Whoa. All right.
Amara.
-Amara?
- Mm-hmm.
Nice to meet you.
She says, "You too."
Ah, hell yeah.
Thank you again.
Dawg,
I still can't get over this.
This square
got him a whole mansion.
Married a--
a genuine rock star.
-Yeah, I did.
-Mmm.
How many gold records you got?
-I have a few.
- She bein' modest.
She bein' real modest.
No, but it's mostly
artists I produce,
but, yeah, I got some.
-And she produces?
-She does.
Donnie. You punching up.
So, Ms. Producer,
when's your next show?
I don't really
perform like that these days.
Yeah, I took a break,
'cause I was...
I was having some issues
with my hearing on stage.
Now I'm trying to be careful
and preserve
what I've got left,
so, I'm producing.
Yeah.
Not any time soon.
Still hard
to give that part up, though.
Right?
Yeah. It's not
the only thing I love,
but it takes work.
It's an adjustment...
- Mm-hmm.
...for the both of us.
So, how long
have you known each other?
- I mean...
-We go back. Way back.
We was like...
We was like brothers.
Shared a room for two years
at the Jeff.
Yeah, something like that.
You know how it went.
He went off
and got all Hollywood.
The Jeff, right.
Yeah, the group home.
You remember them bedbugs?
I try to forget 'em.
Yeah.
I can't forget them bugs.
-I'm gonna get her to bed.
- Okay.
-You two stay, catch up.
Oh, invite him
to the label party.
-Definitely will do that.
-Yeah.
I heard that. I'm invited
to the label party.
-You're invited.
- Thank you.
Yeah.
Thank you so much for coming.
-Yeah, no doubt.
My pleasure to meet you.
-Mmm.
I can't believe
you moved back out here
to the boonies.
You used to love
coming out to the hood.
Now you all...
What?
-Domesticated and shit.
-Ah, come on, man.
-See what happens
when you get married.
-Yeah, all right, bro.
-Aight?
-The women run this household.
I just live here.
That's what happens, man.
You get married, a family.
It's crazy.
Pour up.
Can't believe you traded it in
for a monkey suit.
Oh, you know,
a suit has some advantages.
You saying that
like I got soft
or something, like...
-Like I lost this
sneak-attack.
-Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay, I see.
The champ's still got
some pepper in him.
All I'm saying is,
I left boxing,
but boxing didn't leave me.
See,
that's what I'm saying, bro.
I mean, look,
I know you got a ship to run,
and whatnot,
but I ain't keep
my stuff together
just to be some punching bag
for some chump.
You feel me?
Don't sleep on Felix. Aight?
He got it the hard way.
He earned it.
I did 18 years
the hard way, bro.
Maybe I ain't
make myself clear.
I want a title shot.
Dame...
I don't know
what you think,
but it don't work like that.
Felix so cold,
what he got to lose?
What you got to lose?
You think I can snap
my fingers and make you
a contender overnight?
Ain't that
what happened to you?
It's like this, bro.
I respect you...
but my clock tickin'.
It's now or never for me.
And I wanna help you,
like I said I would.
But, man,
what you asking me, it's...
it's kinda impossible.
You don't know
what it's like, bro.
All that time in them...
in them walls.
Impossible?
They take your name.
And they give you a number.
That's how it start.
I was the best, though.
Yeah, you were.
I was, bro.
But I never got a chance
to prove that.
Look,
all I'm saying, bro, if--
If Apollo Creed
could take a chance
on some underdog...
why can't you?
Did you sleep okay?
Mm-hmm.
You were
grinding your teeth.
How was the rest
of last night?
Mm...
-It was, uh... It was good.
-Yeah?
Just catching up.
Hey,
why didn't you ever tell me
about the group home?
There wasn't a lot to say.
Hmm.
How old were you?
Uh, I was around Amara's age.
You don't wanna talk about it?
It's okay.
-No.
-It's okay.
Nah, it's Dame.
You know he asked me
to fight Felix?
-For real?
-Yeah.
Heavyweight champion
of the world,
and he wants a shot.
So what'd you say?
I said no.
It's impossible, you know?
People wait their whole lives
for a shot like that.
-And he's not even a pro.
-Yeah.
Why does it look like
you're still considering it?
Right. All right.
Work him against the ropes.
Work him.
Stay in front of him, baby.
Cut off that ring. Come on.
-Oof.
That's right.
Don't look at me, man.
You on your own in there.
Let's go.
Come on, mijo, stay on him.
Keep fighting. Let's go.
Okay.
Okay, baby, come on. Come on.
Let's go, grandpa.
Not enough.
Stay focused. Jabs, jabs.
Give it to him.
Work yourself out the clinch.
Let's do it.
-Hey! You keep it clean, huh?
-What was that? Hey.
Yo, man.
What you trying to do,
hurt me?
-Walk it off. Little man,
you ain't built like that.
-Who you calling "little man"?
This is my gym, bro.
All right, coz. All right!
Get in there.
Hey, hey, hey.
Nah.
Get back, Damian. Let him go.
Hey!
What's going on down here?
That was intentional.
-You handle this.
-I am gonna handle this.
D, talk to me. What happened?
Me doing my job.
Hey, come here, man.
Come on. Hey, hey, hey.
Use your head. Okay?
Use your head. Leave all that
other mess outside.
I told you what I want, D.
And I told you
it was gonna take some time.
All right.
All right? Go take a walk.
Get some air.
Aight?
Hey, Adonis.
No-- Hey, Duke. Calm down.
-This was a mistake.
-I got it under control.
I told you right away
it was a mistake.
-I got it.
-You don't!
You let him come in here
with a chip on his shoulder.
That's exactly...
-Well,
don't get quiet now, Dukie.
-Man...
It's okay.
Relax. I know, I got you.
I know. Just let it go. Okay?
I got it under control.
He's telling you
who he is, right?
Believe him.
-♪ I can tell ♪
♪ That there's something
Lurking in the dark ♪
♪ The dark, yeah ♪
♪ I can tell ♪
♪ That you're trying
To catch me off guard ♪
♪ And I'm trying my best ♪
♪ My best
To keep from going under ♪
♪ And it's hard
To forget all the rain ♪
♪ When you keep
Hearing the thunder ♪
♪ And it just feels like ♪
♪ Shadows keep following me ♪
Can I get
two scotches on the rocks?
All right, thank you.
'Sup, Donnie?
I would've had you.
Okay, maybe not.
-You look all right.
-You know. You too.
-A sweater.
-I'm... just glad you came.
B invited.
True.
Hey, don't worry about them.
I ain't.
It's a party. Have fun.
So many other things in here
you should be looking at.
It's a fire party, bro. Yeah.
Congrats, boy.
You made it.
Now those two: Chavez, Drago.
I'm gonna make sure
that's the fight of the year.
Hey, you okay?
I don't need
no babysitting, bro.
Aight. I'ma be right back.
Go ahead.
Look at my two killers.
I can't wait
to get this thing...
Are you ready to do this?
You know I'm always ready.
You don't have to ask.
Okay. Save it for fight night.
We got the venue.
We got the money.
We're gonna break records.
Will you send me
the tracks, please?
I can't wait to hear them.
We'll talk next week.
It was so nice to meet you.
Congratulations too.
You made it.
-Yep.
-Thank you for coming.
You having fun?
-Yeah.
-Yeah?
-Good. Me too.
I'm tired of
working the room, but...
It's what you do.
Yeah, sometimes.
-Guess that's what y'all do.
Look at him over there.
Getting his Don King on.
Minus the hair.
-Thank God.
- Yeah.
You know,
that's growth for him.
He used to hate
coming to these things.
So...
-How does it feel?
-What's that?
Having somebody else
sing your song?
Mmm.
It feels good.
I mean,
if it's gotta be anybody,
not bad.
Yeah, I almost believe you.
How about Donnie?
Think he misses boxing?
No. Not that he tells me.
But would he?
Speaking of,
you know, there's something
I wanted to ask you actually.
Curious what happened
with you two.
Oh, you wanna know
how I got locked up.
Yeah.
Boring story really.
Got into a fight.
I had a few priors.
Pulled a gun.
Donnie was there.
He can tell you.
You know.
Donnie pop off...
And I ain't even saying
dude ain't deserve it, but...
Who is "dude"?
-Okay. Uh...
His name was Leon.
The rest of it,
we gonna leave
to Donnie to tell you.
Ain't really my place.
Feel me?
But it's like you say.
You know, it take work
to look at the past.
- Yo, stop him.
- Drago!
Hey, hey, get that guy!
The LAPD took this man,
Luis Camino, into custody...
No.
No, we're not
canceling anything.
He's seeing a specialist
right now.
They're saying...
at least six months.
I know. I know.
But we'll figure it out.
Do not move the date.
All right. All right. Bye.
...high-profile event.
Drago, who's currently
recovering at Cedars-Sinai,
suffered a concussion,
as well as multiple fractures
to his right arm and hand.
And his injuries
now throw into doubt
his participation
in next month's...
...highly-anticipated
title fight
-against Felix Chavez.
-Hello?
Yes,
everything is gonna be fine.
We'll figure it out.
We'll find another fighter.
It's not about just finding
another fighter.
I know, and I understand
your frustrations.
I really do.
So, what are you gonna do?
He wants to fight Drago.
But we can't wait six months
for him to be cleared.
These windows
don't last forever.
We need to get him paid now.
All right, there's one,
maybe two other contenders
outside of Drago.
There's Ortiz,
and then there's Sporino.
And he's recovering
from his last fight.
Okay, so then who?
I got an idea.
It's risky,
but if we pull it off,
it'll be a payday.
What do you have in mind?
He wants you to fight Dame.
Dame?
He's not even a real fighter.
He was real enough
when he was sparring with you.
Hey, Felix, people talk.
Champ, he's older than you.
-Huh?
- You're right.
But Dame
will fight tooth and nail.
Right now,
we gotta think
outside the box.
Oh, you don't like it, huh?
Damian ain't a boxer.
He's fighting the world
and he's trying
to hurt people.
No, I don't like it.
I think it'd be a circus.
What he means is
he's gonna put on a show.
Okay?
We gotta play the cards
that we're dealt.
But the thing here is,
will people come?
Oh, people are gonna show up.
I can promise you that.
Everyone loves
an underdog story.
You know
how many people tuned in
when Apollo gave Rocky a shot?
People are still talking
about that fight today.
Champ, listen.
I know it's not
what we promised, okay?
I understand.
But if it was me, I'd do it.
Let's do it.
Just let your boy know,
I'ma beat his ass
when I'm in that ring.
Felix, all I want you to do
is your job.
-Hmm?
-Let's get it.
Since taking over
the famous Delphi Academy
with his longtime trainer,
and partner,
"Little" Duke Burton,
Adonis Creed
has trained and mentored
the next generation
of boxing legends.
Adonis always looked out.
We family.
But the brightest jewel
in Creed Athletics' crown
is undoubtedly Felix Chavez.
I go in there
like if I'm a warrior.
And until I take you out,
I'm not gonna stop.
Me and my mother,
we wanna build a legacy,
just like they did.
I had my time as a fighter.
Felix is the next generation.
I'm just excited
I get a chance
to see the fireworks up close.
Boy is explosive.
Now, Creed
is staking his reputation
and legacy
on an unlikely new opponent
for Chavez.
Shit, man.
Before I got locked up,
I was
the highest-ranking amateur
in boxing.
Ever.
"Diamond" Damian Anderson
was once a heralded
Golden Gloves champion
from the Crenshaw district
of Los Angeles, California.
But after almost two decades
behind bars,
he's only now making
his professional debut.
It's the longest hiatus
in the history of boxing
'cause I'm back now.
The future of two fighters
hangs in the balance.
Creed Athletics is promoting
the most surprising fight
of the year.
Will it be a Cinderella story,
or another notch
on the champion's belt?
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen,
and welcome
to the Crypto.com Arena
for tonight's main event.
The stars are arriving
for a much hyped
and very unique title match,
brought to you
by Showtime
and Creed Athletics,
between the reigning
WBC heavyweight champion,
Felix Chavez,
and the virtually
unknown challenger,
Damian Anderson.
- All right, let's go.
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Gentlemen.
Creed.
-Give us a minute.
-Yeah.
6'1",
fighting out
of the Crenshaw District
of Los Angeles,
"Diamond" Dame Anderson.
Oh, shit.
See they finally got you
out of those chains.
Mmm.
How do I look?
You look lighter.
Thank you.
You ain't gotta thank me.
Just go out there and put on.
For sure.
And now,
ladies and gentlemen
in attendance,
and boxing fans joining us
around the world,
here we go.
The challenger this evening,
"Diamond" Damian Anderson.
out of
South Central Los Angeles.
♪ All my life
Been grindin' all my life ♪
♪ Sacrificed, hustled
Paid the price ♪
♪ Want a slice
Got to roll the dice ♪
♪ That's why all my life
I been grindin' all my life
Look ♪
♪ All my life
Been grindin' all my life ♪
What is it about this guy
that's so special
that he gets a title shot
his very first fight?
Well, it all hinges
on Adonis Creed.
Creed says Anderson
is more than up to the task.
But we'll find out ourselves
in just a moment.
Will this be a fairy tale
or a massacre?
This guy is a true product
of Creed Athletics.
Chavez made his presence felt
when he stormed onto the scene
with a string
of devastating knockouts.
A proud fighter,
he had one prediction
for this evening's
unlikely main event:
Victory.
From the Crypto.com Arena,
it's time for the main event
of the evening.
-It's showtime!
-It's okay.
I got it. Thank you.
- Introducing
to you first, on my right...
-I'm fine.
...making his
professional debut,
in an unprecedented attempt
at a world title,
here is the former
Golden Gloves champion,
"Diamond" Damian Anderson.
And his opponent
across the ring
is the defending
world champion.
With a record
of 15 wins and one loss,
he has 14 wins
coming by way of knockout.
Introducing
Felix "El Guerrero" Chavez.
Center ring. Center ring.
Gentlemen,
we went over the rules
in the dressing room.
I wanna remind you
to protect yourself
at all times.
Obey my commands.
God bless you both.
Touch up.
Chavez! Chavez!
The bell and the start
of round one,
here at the Crypto.com Arena.
-Chavez starts out aggressive.
On the hunt.
Sending a very clear message
to Anderson
of what he has in store.
But Anderson is keeping
a tight guard.
Come on, champ! Let's go.
Don't lay off. Keep that
pressure there, baby.
Chavez paws
with that jab there
but Anderson's showing
good movement.
Whoo!
Chavez walks him down...
-Oh, wow!
What an awkward punch.
- Mmm.
That looked intentional.
Where all that power go?
It ain't nothing. Let's go.
Hands up, baby. Hands up.
You ain't got nothing
I ain't seen, boy.
Okay, grandpa.
No tienes nada.
You soft. You soft.
Anderson clinches.
Get off the ropes.
Before shelling back up
into that crab guard.
Dame may be new to us,
but he may have
some tricks in his bag.
-Come on, ref.
Didn't you see that?
-Box!
Some dangerous punches
to end the first.
Anderson might need
to freshen up
on the rule book, Al.
Let's go, Felix.
He thinks he's got you.
Stick to the plan.
-I know what I'm doing.
- Listen,
you fight the fighter,
I fight the refs.
Don't let this
turn into no kind of brawl.
That's what he wants.
He's trying to agitate you.
No. Okay?
- I got this.
- Let's get out there.
You stole that round.
Don't get caught up...
-Water.
-...in their stuff.
It's the first round
and you got bruises
on your face.
Come on,
you better than that, champ.
Stick to the script, baby.
You get out there
and fight the fight
that we worked so hard for.
Round two begins,
and Chavez is already
back on the attack.
There we go, champ.
Feels like Chavez
is back in the fight.
Mamma mia!
Anderson swinging to separate
Chavez's head
from his shoulders.
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
-Yo! What is this?
Wow, that looked deliberate.
-You! Time!
- The ref needs
to get control
before this gets out of hand.
-Can you continue?
-Yeah, I'm good. Let's go.
-Stay right here.
- The only
good news for Chavez is that
-that cut
is so far below his eye...
-Come here.
-...but it's still dangerous.
-Two-point deduction.
Intentional elbow.
It's about time, ref.
Two-point deduction.
Intentional elbow.
Listen, you keep this up
and you're gonna
get yourself disqualified.
-Do you understand?
-Right. Right.
-Stay right there.
-You good?
-Yeah, I'm good.
If anyone was wondering...
-Box!
...what kind of fight
this would be,
it seems like
Anderson is out
to make this clear:
This is a fight for your life.
Let's hope Chavez can make it
back to his corner and adjust.
Big right hand
to end the round
and Chavez
sends Anderson to the corner
with something to think about.
Way to finish.
Way to finish strong.
Let me get that mouthpiece.
Keep grinding, champ.
Round after round.
Hey, champ.
You good? Can you still go?
Yeah, I'm good.
Okay, he's good. Let's go.
He said he's good.
Listen, pain is temporary.
-Say it back to me.
Pain is temporary.
-Pain is temporary.
He a bum! Okay?
And you the champ, right?
I'm the champ.
Let's go, champ.
Keep your hands up.
Stay off them ropes.
Bring it in.
- That's good.
Let's go. Vamos.
- Come on.
Two rounds down,
but it's clearly not the fight
any of us expected.
Stay in it, mijo.
Another shot to that left arm.
Things are starting
to get very ugly.
-Chavez is in
some serious trouble.
- Hands free. Stop!
-I gotta take her, D, okay?
-Okay.
There's no such thing
as defeat. Let's go.
This is dangerous.
Anderson swinging
like a wrecking ball...
-Move. Move!
-...and Chavez
is getting demolished.
Oh, what a shot by Anderson.
Down goes Chavez.
Chavez is not getting back up.
Oh, no.
You don't wanna see that.
Chavez is down
-and appears
to be badly hurt.
-No, no, no.
- Felix!
Ladies and gentlemen...
- ¿Que paso?
-...our referee in charge,
-Russell Mora,
stops the contest.
- Call the paramedics!
He is the winner...
-Doc, is he gonna be okay?
...by way
of spectacular knockout
and he is the new unified
heavyweight champion
of the world,
"Diamond" Damian Anderson.
'Sup, bro? 'Sup, bro?
Right? What?
All right, Duke.
We gotta make this right.
-Whatever I can do...
-No.
I told you, dawg, already.
Ain't no making nothing right.
Ain't no "Duke" nothing.
-I can fix it.
-No!
-You can't.
You stay away from the gym.
You do that.
And stay away for a while.
Hey, Ma.
How's Felix?
He's still at the hospital.
He's stable.
I figured I'd get out of there
and give him some space.
Mm-hmm.
May be smart.
What's all this?
They're from Damian.
You kept these from me?
To help you move on,
yes, I did.
Mama, how could you?
I was trying to protect you.
Protect me from what?
Damian was my brother.
No, Donnie.
Not in that facility
where you were caged
like an animal.
Did you think
that I was gonna
let you go back to that?
You made him think
I abandoned him.
Do you know
what we went through?
I know who that man was
the two of you beat up.
You know Leon?
Yeah.
Then you know Damian
had my back before
you even knew who I was.
Dame treated me
more like family
than your two kids
ever did in this house.
And you took that
away from me.
None of this would've happened
if it wasn't for you.
You're absolutely right.
None of it.
You hit hard, Donnie.
And you can't see.
There may have been a time
when Damian had your back.
But that's not
what he's doing now.
Excuse me.
Yo, Dame. Dame.
-Hey, man.
-Get your hands off me.
Get your hands off me!
Hold up.
It's aight. Cool out, bro.
Give me that.
That's what we on?
What's up, Donnie?
You all right?
You look tidy, bro.
Man. Nah, nah,
you tell me, bro.
You've been playing me
this whole time.
Guess you did
get them letters, huh?
Why'd you lie to me?
I vouched for you.
I brought you
into my home, bro.
You met my family.
I put money up for you.
-Put the gloves on your hands
like you asked.
-All right. That's enough.
You feel me?
You put the gloves
on my hands?
Oh, homey.
You must be punchy.
'Cause if memory serves,
you used to carry my gloves.
Get your shit
and get out the gym.
Oh, Donnie, hold on.
Wait, wait, wait.
You think I need you?
No. When I got locked up,
I needed you.
When I came home,
yeah, bro, I needed you.
But look around, bro.
-I'm the champ!
- Yeah!
And I don't need you
for nothing or... or nothing.
Who alone now?
Yeah, that's right. Run away.
Run away.
That's the one thing
you still good at,
Baby Creed.
What was that?
-What'd you call me?
-Oh, you mad?
You mad?
Try spending
half your life in a cell
watching somebody else
live your life.
You turned your back on me,
homey.
Hey, but look, don't trip.
Hey, come here.
Remember this?
This title?
All this?
Hey, I'm just getting started,
little brother.
I'm coming for it all.
And what's that
supposed to mean?
Are you threatening me?
Ain't no threats here, bro.
Just promises here, homey.
Come here. Let's see.
-Get your hands off me.
-Oh, you all right.
Yeah.
Help yourself up for once.
See how it feel.
Aloha!
Where were you all night?
You didn't get
any of my calls then,
or this morning?
What happened to your eye?
Nothing.
Are you okay?
Not today.
I ain't got time
for a therapy session.
Okay. Well, then
what do you have time for?
Let me know.
Because I have been trying
to talk to you for
a really long time, Donnie.
All right?
Please, can you tell me
what is going on.
Is it me?
No.
It's nothing to do with you.
Is it about Leon?
What? Who told you that?
Dame.
Is there something else
you wanna tell me?
D, you have got to
open up at some point.
I don't know what else
to tell you.
I need to understand.
What do you want me to say?
What do you wanna hear?
Some sad story?
You're trying
to feel sorry for me
or something?
I don't wanna
feel sorry for you!
I wanna understand you!
I wanna know
what is going on with you
in my house!
There's nothing to talk about!
I don't wanna
talk about anything!
I've been trying to forget it!
It's dead! Leave it! Leave it!
Let it lie!
I'm not talking
about that shit no more.
You figure out your shit, D.
Because what cannot happen
is her seeing you like this.
Do you understand?
yeah.
Hey, what y'all doing
in there?
Dame! Adonis!
- Stop!
- Come on! Fight me!
Leon, I'm sorry!
Y'all are so tough, huh?
- Leon?
- Huh?
Don't remember me, do you?
Hey, get off him!
Yeah, you know what it is,
homey.
- Dame!
-Step away from the gun.
-It's down.
It's down! It's down.
-Hey, Mama.
- Adonis, baby.
You gotta get here right away.
Mama had another stroke.
They're saying
multiple organ failures.
I don't know, D.
I think it's...
I think it might be time
to say goodbye.
Mama?
Mom, I'm sorry.
-What?
-I didn't mean it.
I didn't mean it.
Mm-mmm.
-The day I met you.
Ooh, that face.
Mmm. You were so mad.
Gonna knock everybody out,
one by one.
Just like your father.
That's why he fought so hard.
You know that, right?
Yeah.
But you-- you don't have
to do that.
You can find another way.
Yeah.
Yeah, another way.
Another way.
I was angry.
I was so angry
when you left me, Apollo.
Why did you leave me alone?
Adonis.
That's his name.
I'm right here.
He saved me, Apollo.
He helped me to forgive you.
Mom, I'm sorry.
Just tell me what to do.
Okay?
Adonis.
Adoni--
I'm sorry.
I know.
It's okay.
No, it's not.
It's just...
when Dame came back...
all this shit came back too.
I didn't know
how to handle it.
But you were always
really good at that.
Feelings.
It comes easy to you.
Doesn't come easy to me.
Doesn't.
I still got a lot of stuff
that I'm trying to figure out,
and I don't always know
how to talk about it either.
You know, Mary-Anne
was the closest thing
I've had to a mom
in a really long time.
I could talk to her.
Now she's gone.
And when I stopped performing,
it was really hard to accept
that my dreams didn't turn out
the way that I imagined
that they would.
And that still hurts me.
A lot.
But I just made a choice
to try to move on
and be happy
about what I do have.
But it's not easy.
I just try.
Leon...
was the dad at the group home
where I lived with Dame.
I'm not saying me
and Dame were angels.
Okay? But...
no kid deserves
to get beat on like we did.
You feel me?
That night
at the liquor store,
I saw Leon.
And I snapped.
And I hit him.
I kept hitting him.
And his boys jumped on me.
So Dame pulled a gun.
Cops pulled up.
We tried to run.
Dame got caught. I got away.
I ran.
You were a kid.
You were scared.
Anybody would've run.
And Dame had a gun, Adonis.
That's not on you.
Yeah, but when he went down,
I didn't reach out.
I never called.
I didn't write.
After a while, it felt easier
to pretend like I forgot.
You know, just...
act like it never happened.
But that doesn't
make you responsible
for how his life turned out.
You are a good man, Adonis.
I don't know anymore.
You have got to try
to forgive yourself,
so that you can begin
to believe that you deserve
the life that you have earned.
Because you do.
Don't let him destroy
everything you've built.
But, B, he's not gonna stop.
Then you make him.
There's only one way
that Dame's gonna listen.
If that's what you gotta do,
then...
all right.
At 26 and one, he's the former
heavyweight champion
of the world.
One of the greatest fighters
in the history of boxing.
The one and only Adonis Creed
is sitting right next to me.
Welcome to the show, my man.
How you doing?
I'm doing okay, man.
Thanks for having me.
Yeah...
...thank you for being here.
You called to be on this show,
which you've never done.
I wanna know why you felt
the need
to come on national television
today to speak.
What's on your mind?
When I walked away
from boxing,
-I walked away
with some unfinished business.
-Mmm.
Gotta be talking about Dame.
Gotta be talking about him.
Let's just get this
out of the way.
You know I believe
you're the best
pound-for-pound fighter
in the world,
three years ago.
It's been a minute
since you've been
out in these streets,
so maybe you haven't heard
what they've been saying
about you.
Conlan.
He was beyond his prime
when you beat him.
Dame.
He's the next king of boxing.
Not you. Okay?
Every time you turn around,
Dame is talking
about you dirty,
and unapologetically.
Hey, turn that up.
To anybody who'll listen,
he questions your manhood,
he talks about your family.
He talks about
how you can't be trusted,
and that you run out
on your boys.
No, no. No.
Wait. Let me just...
Hold on.
We got a call coming in.
We got a call.
Put him on, right now.
Hey, what up, little homey?
You want a tissue?
Want me to come on there
and give you a hug?
Aight, look, I'm just telling
everybody who you really are.
-How you run out on family.
Dame, uh, not like this.
This ain't the way
to handle it.
Oh, bad news, bro.
This is live.
So, I mean, this how
we gonna handle it now.
Little Donnie
ain't got nothin'.
He a coward.
You a coward, bro,
and a fraud.
I know it.
Everybody else know it.
Hey, Apollo Creed
would be ashamed.
Oh, you lost it.
Aight.
I challenge you
for the heavyweight
championship of the world.
You and me?
-Run it.
-Run it!
Oh, hell yes.
Y'all heard it here first.
I know I can't wait for this.
There you go.
What's up, champ?
- What's going on?
- Prime time.
The champ is here!
Y'all better turn it up.
Here we go, folks.
Let's get reacquainted.
Fractured fourth
and fifth metacarpals.
Both hands.
His eye socket broke.
Ruptured kidney.
-His shoulder don't work.
- Torn abductor.
He don't got it no more.
He retired. He probably
won't even make weight.
And remind me,
how many concussions
have you had?
You're old, and you're broken.
We know Dame.
Dame gonna have
this damn list memorized.
He's willing to do anything
to win, so you gotta
be prepared for everything.
We can't turn back the clock,
we can't hide all your flaws,
but we can make 'em strengths.
That's it. Two jabs.
-Come under.
-Slip.
One-one-two.
-I got you.
-Let's go, D.
The higher you get,
the harder it gets.
That's life. That's this run!
-Let's go.
Tug-of-war. Old-school.
Right here. Let's go.
Over and over.
Push.
Push!
What you looking back, boy?
Look forward.
Who slips like this?
Nobody. Bring it in.
Ain't nobody gonna
take it easy on him, right?
Come on. Focus up.
There you go.
Come on, man.
Stop thinking so much, man.
Get your head in the game.
You see that man right there?
Do you remember him?
You gotta block out everything
and be in the moment.
Not the past. Not the future.
Right now.
Let's go. Come on.
Well...
Hey.
-How's the...
-Nah, nah. Don't. Don't.
But you're good?
Good enough to beat you.
Keep your hands up.
Move. Move!
You can go home, dawg.
Maybe we should take a break.
Take a break?
Where you goin'?
I'm just getting started.
I see you, boy.
Whoo! We're out here working
right now!
Where is he? Where is he?
I see you.
Let's do it, baby!
Let's go! Let's go,
let's go, let's go!
There you go! There you go!
Let's go!
Welcome to Los Angeles
for one of
the most highly anticipated
heavyweight bouts in years.
One step.
One punch.
One round at a time.
One step.
One punch.
One round at a time.
One step.
One punch.
One round at a time.
Creed! Creed!
Creed! Creed! Creed!
Creed! Creed! Creed! Creed!
Whoa!
Yeah, boy!
What's up, LA?
Ladies and gentlemen,
good evening,
and welcome
to the Battle of Los Angeles.
The fight starts now!
Introducing first,
the challenger.
Fighting out of the Delphi Gym
and proudly representing
his home
of Los Angeles, California,
here is the former light
heavyweight and heavyweight
champion of the world,
Adonis Creed!
Creed!
And his opponent
across the ring,
he represents
the Crenshaw District
of Los Angeles, California.
Here is the former
Golden Gloves champion
and the reigning,
defending, undefeated
and unified
heavyweight champion
of the world,
"Diamond" Damian Anderson!
Anderson!
Creed retired
a champion, but he's
definitely the underdog.
Yeah, there's no doubt
Dame has the upper hand.
He looks to be
in phenomenal shape.
You both received
your instructions
in your dressing room.
I want a good, clean fight.
Obey my commands at all times.
Above all, protect yourself
at all times.
Let's go.
You on your own now,
little Donnie.
Go to your corners.
The intensity here is
like nothing I've ever seen.
Yeah, you can absolutely feel
the bad blood
between each other
in this Battle of LA.
- And we're off.
And the big question here
in round one, how much
ring rust will Adonis have?
Three years out of the game.
And the way Dame attacks,
this could be over early.
A little bit
of a cautious start
early on here.
Still not clear yet
who's going to be
the one dictating.
Stop holding back, D.
You're giving him
too much respect.
Anderson gets
first blood with a nasty shot
to the arm of Creed.
Both fighters
sizing each other up.
And, boom, a stiff jab
to the face lands,
and Creed is gonna tie him up.
Keep those hands up! Let's go!
You gotta commit, D!
Gotta commit!
Come on. Let's go. Let's go.
Come on, D!
I'd give
that round to Anderson
with an impressive start here.
All right, little Donnie.
I'll see you in a minute.
Don't worry.
I'll be right back.
Way to hang out there.
Wear him out.
Look, the boy a punk.
He see you not scared.
Now it's time for him
to start fighting dirty,
right?
Keep your head on tight.
Let him make mistakes.
He gonna make
a lot of them, all right?
And attack those windows
when they open.
You throwing
power punches, champ.
-Pace yourself.
- I know
what I'm doing.
Don't worry about me.
All that money can't save him.
Believe that.
You gotta wonder
if Creed's regretting
his decision
to get back in the ring.
Retirement sure seems like
it would be a lot more fun.
Round two
underway here
in Los Angeles, live on DAZN.
Let's see if Adonis can find
his championship form
and make a fight out of this.
Stop running, Donnie.
Yes!
Yo, keep 'em up.
What I tell you, huh?
Here he comes.
-Come on, ref.
-Keep 'em up. Keep 'em up.
That cheap shit
all you got, old man?
Can't beat me heads up?
You had enough, boy?
Tie him up, baby. Tie him up.
You thought this shit
was gonna be easy.
What
an exciting close to round two
in the battle of LA.
Both men giving us
some tremendous blows.
That was better.
Stay focused. You take him
where you need to go.
Keep punching through.
Leave him open...
Don't let this chump
control you.
What did we just witness?
An incredible end to round 11.
This fight feels dead even.
You can feel the tension.
This is history spilling
into the ring.
What an emotionally draining
war here in Los Angeles.
Listen...
You out there boxing.
I need you to start fighting.
Go out there
and do what we came to do.
It's your time, champ!
It's your time to shine!
Let go of the fear.
You hear me?
Let go of the guilt.
Let go of it, dawg.
Let go of whatever was
and walk into what is.
Go out there and be ferocious!
Do you hear me?
Be ferocious!
Go out there
and be Adonis Creed!
And we're off in round 12.
Three minutes to decide
the heavyweight championship
of the world.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, baby.
Stay in that zone with him.
Come on, ref!
There you go, baby.
There you go.
And Creed's down!
-Neutral corner.
-Get up, Donnie!
A massive body shot...
-Four!
...and he's down on a knee!
- Five!
-Get up, boy!
Six!
-Get up, boy.
- Seven!
Eight!
Get up, D.
Nine!
And he's up!
-Come to me. You all right?
-Yeah.
-You all right?
-I'm good.
-Wanna continue?
-Yeah. Let's go.
There you go! Yes!
Creed beats the count,
but here comes Dame.
Can he survive?
Let's go! Give it to him!
Break, break!
Creed breaks the clinch.
He fires everything he's got!
-That's it, D.
Walking Anderson down!
It's your time, D!
This is your time!
Anderson is down!
Yeah! Like that!
How about that?
Whoa!
Lights out! What a shot!
Adonis Creed is the new
heavyweight champion
of the world!
Ladies and gentlemen,
this contest comes to an end
at two minutes and 12 seconds
of the 12th and final round,
for your winner by knockout.
The fighting pride
of Los Angeles,
and once again
the heavyweight champion
of the world,
Adonis Creed!
Adonis Creed has done it.
-Yeah!
- A knockout...
-That's what
I'm talking about.
...in the 12th round.
An incredible scene.
Yeah!
If there was ever a question
of who is the king of boxing,
let there be no doubt.
The Creed dynasty
reigns supreme.
Good.
Back training hard,
back getting back focused.
Back for the next phase.
We're back in business.
We'll be in the hall, champ.
Guess you did learn
a few moves without me.
Dame, I'm sorry.
All those years...
I never checked up on you.
That's on me.
We were just...
kids, bro.
It ain't on you.
None of it.
Never was.
Hey, D.
It wasn't on you either.
Aight, go ahead then, man.
Family and everybody
waiting on you.
Champ.
You know where to find me
if you need me.
You know she's been waiting
all night for this, right?
She looks good in there.
-Yeah.
-Hmm?
-You all right?
I'm better now.
Okay.
All right.
All right, all right.
-Ow! Ooh.
-Knock him out.
-Ooh!
Yeah.
No!
Now we have
a new champ!
She's the champ!
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.