Power over Spice is power over all
Enemy.
Down. Right.
They're close.
Do you hear that?
The rats are calling a worm.
Worms!
Unit, climb. Now!
Look for wormsign.
We're okay.
Shields!
No Shields!
I got you, rat.
You're not welcome here.
Jamis! Jamis!
You killed Jamis!
Spies!
Witch!
Stop! Stop!
They don't know what they're saying.
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Mahdi!
I need your guidance
with the two foreigners.
Give them back to the desert.
I saw the signs.
Again.
Stilgar, your faith is
playing tricks on you.
The Lisan al-Gaib has not
shown his face yet!
He killed Jamis in a fair fight.
He speaks our language.
He will quickly learn our ways.
I'm ready to pledge my life for him.
The desert will handle his fate.
What about the woman?
Too spicy for the foreigner?
He'll look pretty with blue eyes.
Don't mock him.
He deserves our respect.
He's a good fighter.
To the well, our water we return.
We bless our brother, Jamis.
Amen.
She'll drink worm piss.
Not funny.
He's about to lose her.
If she's stupid enough to drink poison.
Shut up!
We are praying.
Here is the Water of Life.
It frees the soul.
If you drink...
you shall die.
you may see.
Drink!
What have we done?
She is pregnant.
That was no miracle!
You saw it with your own eyes!
The Mother of the Lisan al-Gaib
shall survive the Holy Poison.
And She did.
As written!
Her people wrote that!
Blasphemy.
The prophecy has been accomplished.
The Mahdi must be Fremen!
Arrakis must be freed
by its own people!
I'm here to learn your ways.
The Mahdi is too humble
to say He is the Mahdi.
Even more reason to know He is!
As written!
Kwisatz Haderach, show us the way.
You will see!
The beauty and the horror!
He doesn't know how to cross.
Stilgar is going to get him killed.
What is he trying to prove?
What do you think?
"The Prophet shall know
the ways of the desert."
I think it's for the best.
What's this?
You care for him now?
He's not like the other strangers.
He's sincere.
You saw what he did.
He saw it coming,
and he saved her life.
He saw it.
He can foresee.
Muad'Dib likes his smell.
Then I'll die.
Maybe you will too.
But the others will keep going.
And they won't stop
until the Fremen are free.
He deserves to be Fedaykin.
He needs names, Stilgar.
He does!
Like Usul.
The base of the pillar.
Don't embarrass us!
Call a big one!
Don't worry.
Stilgar taught him well.
Enough joking.
This is the final test.
Not that big.
As written.
Reverend Mother!
Muad'Dib made peace with Shai-Hulud.
He called a grandfather worm.
The biggest ever seen.
As written!
Shai-Hulud shall bow
to the Boy from the Outer World.
Bless the Maker and His works.
Will not Shai-Hulud know the Mahdi
when He comes?
Then share the Word.
Will you always be with me?
Reverend Mother!
Your palanquin is ready!
Reverend Mother, we have to go!
They're the Guardians of the South.
It's a hard crossing,
but Shai-Hulud is strong.
The rats are travelling fast.
Move!
Under our glorious black sun,
we welcome to these special festivities
our beloved leader
Baron Vladimir Harkonnen.
His presence today, watching over
a spectacle of blood and honor,
marks the Holy Birthday
of our beloved na-Baron, Feyd-Rautha.
In celebration of our
na-Baron Feyd-Rautha,
we present a special treat.
The last three specimens
of House Atreides.
All hail na-Baron Feyd-Rautha!
The new Planetary
Governor of Arrakis!
What do you think of the outsider?
I think he's trouble.
No, I trust Usul.
Only one at a time...
or they fight each other to death.
How old?
Very young.
My daughter asks, how is it done?
The Water of Life.
You question the prophecy?
No man will survive.
They're all dead!
I lost them all in the fire!
The whole of the North has been hit.
There is a call for a war council
in the South.
Every leader must attend.
Muad'Dib, they're waiting for you.
None of these people
will leave without you.
I can't go South.
You're not allowed in here, stranger.
Leave or die.
I should be welcomed...
If you drink, you shall die.
If you drink, you may see.
Who knows about this?
Only you, Reverend Mother.
Good.
Where are the others?
They just arrived from the North.
Because He is the One.
The Lisan al-Gaib should find His way
to where no man has ever been.
You're insane!
He shall come back from the dead
with Desert Spring tears.
Bring me a drop of Water of Life.
As written.
Do you smash a knife
before battle?
There is no one in this room
who can stand against me!
Your mothers warned you
about my coming!
Fear the moment.
But you're afraid.
What if I could be the One?
This could be the moment you've been
praying for, all your life.
You're praying now,
to your grandmother.
She died nine moons ago.
She lost an eye.
A rock smashed her face
as she was crossing the Belt.
She was 12 when it happened.
At that time, this world
had a Fremen name.
In your nightmares,
you give water to the dead,
and it brings joy to your heart!
Mahdi, what do you foresee for us?
Green Paradise.
Lisan al-Gaib, show us the Way!
The Hand of God be my witness!
I am the Voice from the Outer World!
I will lead you to paradise!
As you foresaw, Muad'Dib...
a great-grandmother of a storm.
He brought his whole army.
Long live the fighters.
They speak the truth.
Long live the fighters!
Bring the prisoners to the Residency.
Kill the Sardaukar.
Give the Baron's body to the desert.