[English subtitles are available]
Isn't it like a roller coaster?
Mom.
When Dad first came to Chongqing,
he wasn't used to it, was he?
No, he wasn't.
He "wohuo" every day.
What does "wohuo" mean?
It means he complained every day.
[Nan An District Dongshuimen Bridge]
So many bridges have been built in Chongqing.
It's much easier to cross the river now.
Many of those who built the bridges
were Dad's students.
Then why are the cable cars still in use?
The tourists love it.
Now, it's purely a tourist attraction.
Back then, Dad went to work
and came home by cable car.
But I've never ridden.
Come on.
Let's go.
Is that where your house is?
Yes.
It's right there.
But you can't see it now. It's blocked.
[Safety precautions for Yangtze River ropeway visitors]
It's changed. It looks different.
It's changed so much.
You must try the cold shrimps. Come on.
You know I can't have shrimps.
The cold shrimps aren't real shrimps.
Slow down.
What's that?
Sit here.
[Famous Chongqing Snack Iced Tangyuan]
One of the three things that cool you down in Chongqing.
[Service station]
10 yuan for a set.
[Famous Chongqing Snack Iced Tangyuan]
Just scan the code.
It's 10 yuan, not 4 yuan.
Try it.
One of the three things that cool you down in Chongqing.
10 yuan a set.
Stinky dog, I'll beat you to death!
Stop teasing it.
Whose kid is this?
[Shangyou News]
Excuse me, I'd like to buy something.
Wait.
Batong.
Time to eat.
Batong, time to eat.
Eat.
Good boy, Batong.
[Shangyou News]
Batong.
[HACHIKO]
[15 years ago]
Bring him home.
Your dad keeps asking.
He should mind his own business.
You tell him nothing.
Of course he's worried.
[Domestic calls]
I don't wanna talk to him about it.
Go get your dad.
How much longer do you need?
Hurry up!
You stayed up all night again.
I'm on American time.
Dad.
Mom asked you to play mahjong for her.
Play mahjong for her?
She said so.
Do I know how to play mahjong?
She asked you to.
Go fetch the camera from upstairs.
I'm leaving for my research trip in a bit.
And the tripod too.
Got it.
Xinqiao.
Did you record the game last night?
I forgot.
What can you remember?
Here I am.
Professor.
Professor Chen, play with us.
Let me play on her behalf.
Whose turn is it?
Mine.
Batong, do you want it?
Yes, I do.
Look.
Three three wans.
Four, five, six wan.
Five, six, seven wan.
Five, six, seven tiao.
And we're just missing... Batong.
Thank you all!
You still have that suite on your hand.
What are you doing? You're declaring your own win.
You can't do that.
You still have that suite on your hand.
Why can't I?
You need to the bamboo suit first.
Good for nothing!
Who allowed you to touch my tiles?
Our daughter said
you asked me to play on your behalf.
What's up?
It's been so many years
and you still can't play mahjong.
You call yourself a professor?
Who understands those rules of yours?
I didn't know you couldn't hold that suite.
Make sure you give it to him.
It's just a pack of jerky,
not a local specialty.
Who cares?
Just do as I ask.
Why do you have so much to say?
Come on, let's carry on.
Who says a professor must know how to play mahjong?
I'll count it for you.
I'll count the small points only.
I won with the weakest set.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
Morning, Professor Chen.
Morning.
Two yuan.
[Each person must have a ticket to enter the station]
Hold on to the handrail. Be careful.
[Entrance]
Morning.
Hold on to the handrail.
[Please do not crowd, line up orderly] [Ride civilly, be orderly]
Li.
Have all the locals moved out?
Yes.
Dean.
We nearly hit it.
What happened?
Look, there.
A dog.
It's a dog.
Isn't it scared of dying?
There's a puppy. Look.
Looks like it's not hurt.
It's not hurt.
Didn't you say
all the locals have moved out?
Why is there a puppy here?
There was a dog farm nearby.
It's in shock.
It looks so pitiful.
Maybe it's hungry.
Come here.
I happen
to have some jerky.
Good.
What brand of jerky is this?
A surprise from my wife.
A surprise.
Jerky.
Come out, doggy.
Oh, no! It's stuck.
We've got a problem.
It's stuck.
Come have a look.
The tire is stuck.
It's too big for you.
Come on.
Come.
Li.
Where did you say the dog farm was?
Up there. Just a few steps away.
It's in a huge yard.
Look, it's sunk so deep.
Professor Chen, you're back.
Why didn't you return it?
It's all gone.
No one is there.
You want to return it?
Just keep it.
Li.
Do you know where they moved to?
No. God knows.
Or...
Professor Chen.
You take it home.
My wife doesn't like dogs.
Dean.
Why don't you take it.
I can't.
My wife was born in the Year of the Rooster.
She says we can't have dogs at home,
or else
there will be chaos.
Then, Professor Zhao.
You keep it.
My wife has two cats.
If I bring it home, I'm basically rebelling against her!
I don't dare.
I need to go to my office first.
Be quick!
Morning, Professor Chen.
Morning.
Good morning, Professor.
[Fire extinguisher]
[Cultivate virtuous and capable talent, passion for education]
Professor Chen, it's time for the meeting.
You stay here.
Listen, yes, be good.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Behave.
[Cultivate virtuous and capable talent, passion for education]
[Associate Professor]
[Dean]
Sir,
can I speak first later?
Why?
You're in a hurry?
I have some family business.
There are many professors before you.
How can I do that?
How about this?
Let's do it in alphabetical order.
A, B, C, D...
It's fair.
C...
Fine.
Alright, thanks.
[Meeting on reservoir development and immigration work]
Quiet please.
The meeting is starting.
You.
Mr. Ai.
You speak first.
[Meeting on reservoir development and immigration work]
Thank you, Dean,
for letting me speak first.
Thanks.
Many are coming to the hotpot tonight.
There are...
15 people in total.
15 people.
Ask Professor Chen to come too.
Forget about him.
He has to report back to his wife.
Even northerners live under their wives' thumb?
It's a universal problem
for men all over the world.
[Love students like your own children, have high moral character]
You understand?
Yes.
[Love students like your own children, have high moral character]
Slowly, we'll get rich.
It's the most important
among all our tasks.
Comrades.
This is the end of my presentation.
Thank you all.
The focus of my research is
the innovation of various water conservancy project
behind the reservoir.
I listed several main points
and illustrations too.
We're all experts.
I'm sure you'll understand it.
So, I won't waste your time.
Please pass it around.
Please.
Dean, please collect it for me afterwards.
I'm off. Thanks.
Professor Chen.
Quiet, quiet.
Next,
Professor Bi.
Your turn.
Okay.
Dean, Dean.
Look.
Why did he draw this?
[Cultivate virtuous and capable talent, passion for education]
How did you get here?
You really know how to pick a spot.
This is someone's sand table.
You peed on it.
It took them three years
to build this.
They just had to put in the water.
Yet, you watered it first.
Naughty you.
I bet Professor Chen won't agree.
Beijing is so far away.
Associate Professor Chen.
He'll be a professor soon.
He's just
slow and indecisive.
If he had listened to me,
he would be a professor now.
I bet he won't agree to it.
He doesn't want his son to be so far away.
That's it.
Six tong.
Win!
Give me the money.
You're so lucky.
Let's call it a day.
As soon as you won?
The professor is coming home.
What should we do?
Come.
You're against your own.
Go over.
I told you to go over.
Sit over there.
I'll play then.
Not upright.
Then?
Tilt it a little.
Okay.
Watch your hands.
[Authentic spicy stock]
Professor Chen.
The same? One fifth without chilies?
Yes.
Professor Chen, shall I put chilies in it too?
No, don't.
It's been years.
You still like it so bland.
It's better to keep it bland.
Okay.
See you, Professor Chen.
Dad is home.
Go meet him.
Here I am.
Dad.
You're home.
Take this.
It smells so nice.
Have you told him?
I don't know how to tell him.
Tell him straight.
He's not unreasonable.
Okay.
Stay here.
Don't move.
Wait for me.
I'll get you some water.
There are four people eating.
Don't just get yours.
Dad, let me.
Go get the chopsticks.
How did you get there?
Water.
I usually drink this.
You stay here.
Okay.
Good.
Stay in there.
Don't come out.
Don't come down.
Put more in.
He doesn't eat fish mint anyway.
Add vinegar too.
Dad.
Well...
I've got a job.
Finally had enough time off?
I met a few friends in other provinces online.
They're setting up a website.
They need a front-end developer like me.
I can work from home for now.
I want to give it a try.
If it goes well,
I'll go to Beijing.
The package they offer...
What's that noise?
...is pretty good.
Two meals are included too.
Good, well done.
Our son's made us proud!
Why are you downstairs?
Dad.
I...
Mom.
What did I say before we got married?
What did I say?
Dogs aren't allowed at home.
What's that?
I got bitten by a dog when I was little.
You know it well.
I avoid dogs when walking in the street.
You secretly brought a dog home.
Are you trying to piss me off?
What does "gui mi ri yan" mean?
Unreasonable.
She says you're weird.
I picked it up on my research trip.
All the residents had left.
No one was there.
It looked so pitiful
since it was alone.
It's pitiful
and I'm not?
What does "zao nie" mean?
It means pitiful.
Yes, you're pitiful.
You're pitiful.
You're more pitiful than it.
Stop pretending you can't understand the dialect.
It's okay. It's okay.
Don't be afraid.
Send it away at once.
As soon as I find it a good owner,
I'll send it away.
I promise that you won't feel pitiful.
It's all your fault.
A bottle of soy sauce, please.
You sell dogs too?
The dog with the box was just adopted.
I see.
A tube of toothpaste, please.
Colgate?
Colgate.
-How much? - Three yuan.
Thanks.
Let's go.
It'll bite you.
I want... I want a doggy.
No, no, it bites.
It bites?
Yes, it bites.
It won't get hurt if I stroke it.
[Seeking adoption]
Don't be afraid.
I allow it to stay for a night.
Thank you for your mercy.
[Seeking adoption]
Goddess of Mercy.
So annoying.
Another goal!
Xinqiao, it's 9-1.
That's right. Really.
Right,
they scored a goal.
They scored, so you get a reward.
Bark. Bark!
Come on.
Let's be good.
Be quiet tonight.
Appreciate this hard-earned opportunity.
Look at this.
Is it good?
You like it?
A puppy eating a bear cub.
My goodness!
You're tearing it apart.
Play for a while and go to sleep,
because you're still growing.
You're still growing.
Here is the money.
He didn't accept it?
You still have the cheek to ask?
You hid it from me.
I was afraid he might turn you down.
I didn't give it to him.
Why not?
In front of so many people,
you're not embarrassed but I'd feel ashamed.
Why must you do it before a crowd?
You're such
an embarrassment.
Just give it to him quietly.
Enough, don't interfere in my business.
Your business?
You're still an associate professor.
Those younger than you have got promoted.
Didn't you notice that?
Hmm.
Hmm?
Is that all you can say?
You can't say anything useful.
I told you.
Shy kids get no sweets.
What's the use of just being good?
I'm getting old.
Don't ask me to do something like that.
Turn the light off.
It does no harm to go to bed early.
Did our daughter tell you?
Is she bringing him home tomorrow?
It does no harm to go to bed early.
Here you are.
You're in trouble, you know?
Luckily, it's me who came up.
If it were her,
she'd throw you out of the window.
Be good. Stay here.
You hid a tile in here.
You like this?
You know what it's called?
It's called "batong".
Are you taking a photo of the dog or me?
Don't worry.
3, 2, 1, say cheese!
Okay.
Let me see.
Your camera is rubbish.
It can't do.
It looks so awful.
Use my camera instead.
Taking photos, developing them, scanning them.
It's been days.
I know don't what you're up to.
Just put out the flyer.
It's just a mongrel.
Why are we doing a whole photo shoot?
It'll attract more people if it looks good.
If you put out more flyers,
more people will see it too.
[Seeking help with handsome rewards]
Professor Chen.
Look at these.
Seeking a son-in-law with great wealth.
De-worming wine.
Look, what are these?
Those idiots who pasted the flyers...
They should be glued to the back of the neighborhood.
[Childcare services][Primary and secondary tuition]
A mongrel dog. Male.
[Seeking adoption]
Three-month-old. Very lively and obedient.
Batiao.
[Domestic calls]
I don't want batiao.
Santiao.
[Seeking adoption]
I don't want santiao.
Santiao for me too.
Why are you still drawing?
Discard it already.
Where is the puppy?
I still have santiao.
It got adopted.
Peng.
By whom?
Someone fat.
Man? Woman? Old? Young?
What does he or she do?
What's the family like?
Where do they live?
I don't know.
You didn't ask questions before giving it away?
Great!
How would I know I need to question them for a dog?
Where did they go?
To the market.
[Meat]
[Seafood]
Mister, fresh meat!
[Welcome]
The puppy of yours...
how would you like it?
[Welcome]
Pepper dog meat.
With what?
Radish.
Salty or light?
Salty!
[Welcome]
50 yuan.
That's expensive. Can you give me a discount?
Don't you know the price has gone up for everything?
I know.
Wait, let me cut this meat.
Okay.
[Welcome]
Xinqiao, turn the tap on.
Let's have a bath.
Relax. Relax.
How nice it feels.
You'll be washed clean
and nice.
You never had a bath, eh?
Let's wash your little paws.
Be good.
I've never seen your hubby so cheerful.
Let's have a look.
See, how pretty!
So energetic.
Now you're clean.
Look at your beautiful fur.
Right?
Yeah?
Depending on how active it is,
it could erupt or evolve...
[Engineering Geology Study of Active Faults]
It...
...happens suddenly.
[Engineering Geology Study of Active Faults]
Excuse me.
Someone called. A foreman.
He wants to take the dog to the construction site.
No.
Absolutely no.
Male.
Are you married?
So many questions for adopting a dog?
Yes. Can't I ask?
So strict.
Married?
Jiazhen, are you done? We're waiting.
We're all waiting for you.
Sit.
This adoptive home has a floor area of 19.2 square meters.
And the usable floor area?
Usable floor area...
He didn't specify.
No.
The space is too small.
Professor Chen.
[China Communications Services]
Why didn't I see you this morning?
I kept the morning paper for you.
Thanks.
[China beat Maldives 1-0]
[Convenience Kiosk]
Here.
Thank you, Uncle.
Where are you from?
I'm local, from Chongqing.
Which district in Chongqing?
Chengkou.
Where?
It's in the east.
Chengkou near Hubei?
Broadly speaking,
it's part of Chongqing.
Yes, part of Chongqing.
It's April.
It's not very hot.
You're sweating a lot.
Are you unable to withstand heat?
No.
He's terrified of you.
Someone's terrified of me?
What do you do for a living?
I'm unemployed for now.
His last job got him nowhere,
so he just quit.
The hair of yours...
Were you born with such brown hair
or did you dye it?
I dyed it.
Young man.
I think you should treat your hair seriously
because it directly reflects
your state of mind.
Dad.
I like him.
No.
Absolutely not.
You're not qualified.
Yes, stop.
You goddam dog!
I was winning!
It ruined the game just like that!
So annoying!
I feed it, let it stay and it stops me from winning!
It's such
an ungrateful dog.
Tell me.
When will you send it away?
We haven't found a suitable owner yet.
When you win a game, I have to hear about it all day.
Let alone when there's a puppy's life at stake, right?
No matter what, we should
find him a reliable owner.
More than ten people call every day.
They're officials, businessmen,
and you're saying they're unsuitable.
Even when you get the right tiles,
there's no guarantee you'll win the game,
right?
You have a kind heart.
Surely you can't bear to hand him
to someone unreliable, can you?
Chen Jingxiu.
You're being very unreasonable.
I asked you to give the jerky to the dean
and you fed it to the dog.
How could you?!
No wonder you're still an associate professor.
You can't tell the dean from the dog!
We're talking about the dog, right?
Why do you mention the dean?
They aren't the same species.
Besides,
our Batong is better looking than the dean, right?
Batong?
Yes, Batong.
He likes mahjong too. I bet you'll get along well.
Tell you what.
If you don't send it away tonight, don't come to bed!
Get along well? Get along your ass!
Don't mind my dad.
My dad is so hen-pecked.
Li Jiazhen.
You like playing mahjong.
You play it all day long.
Did you ask for my approval?
Do you need my approval?
No, you don't.
Because I've no right to ask.
Because you like it.
The young man over there.
Your fingers are glued to the keyboard.
Look at your hair.
It looks like a bird's nest.
As soon as you wake up, you sit there.
You never go out.
[Define upload file class]
You're about to be sucked into the computer.
Did you ask for my approval?
Do you need my approval?
No, you don't either.
Why not?
Because you like it.
And you.
The guy you like.
That guy
from Chengkou.
Did you ask for my approval?
We human beings
live for
no more than several decades.
Only when you live for things you like, can you call it living.
So,
I never stop you
because you like these things.
Today,
I'm speaking up for myself for once.
I like this dog.
No one can stop me.
Xiaozhou, come here.
And you too.
Let me formally introduce you.
His name is Batong.
He's your younger brother.
You make me so furious!
Hiding behind a dog, eh?
[1 year later]
Okay, ready.
Get closer. Closer.
You're family.
Ma'am, smile.
It's a family photo.
1, 2, 3.
Another.
Relax.
Another. Another.
Ma'am, smile.
1, 2, 3, good!
Congratulations!
Thank you, thanks.
[Joy]
Mind the steps.
Please take your seats.
Congratulations!
Thank you.
You've got such a good son-in-law. Congratulations.
Please sit.
Off you go.
[Joy]
Jiazhen.
It's from Ruixia and Guo.
We've got spicy chicken.
Pork with red bean.
Alright, get the lighter dishes ready.
Ma'am.
Where would you like the firecrackers?
Up there.
Okay.
Okay, thanks.
Spicy chicken.
Another spicy dish.
This isn't spicy. Try it.
It's not spicy.
Not spicy.
You know what?
In Chongqing, we love telling two lies.
One - it's not spicy.
And the other?
The other is...
My wife always listens to me.
Chen Jingxiu.
We're letting off firecrackers.
Keep him in the house.
Yes.
Batong, let's go.
Let's go inside, Batong.
Okay.
[Joy]
Go upstairs.
Upstairs, go.
Don't be afraid.
Come here.
Human beings
just love getting busy and making a ruckus
so they can cope with hard times.
Am I right?
Batong.
Look at the other side of the river.
They've built so many tall buildings.
In a few years,
[Joy]
they'll build tall buildings on this side too.
By then, when we look over there,
we won't be able to see the river.
You want one too?
Yes?
Good.
Let's have one.
Good?
Professor Chen.
I've told you countless times.
Put your dirty clothes in the basket.
Even a cow gets it after three times.
Come, Batong.
Bring it to her.
It delivers stuff for Mom!
So obedient.
More obedient than you.
Batong.
Come, sit.
Bark.
Good boy.
Batong.
Baby, sit.
Stay home. Guard the door.
I'll play with you when I come back.
Be good.
Morning.
[Public telephone]
[8 yuan]
Morning.
Let me check the ticket. Okay.
[Be safe, please do not lean on the door]
[Line up orderly, proceed orderly]
I'm sorry.
What are you doing here?
It's my dog. I'm sorry.
Let's go. Go home.
[Line up orderly, proceed orderly]
You can't come here. Go.
You chased after Daddy.
You can't go to work with Daddy.
Got it?
Look, he brought a dog in.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
[China Communications Services]
You can't go in there.
Professor Chen, is that your dog?
I found it in Yunyang.
[Mineral water, instant noodles]
Your fellow villager!
Shut up.
You ran out of the house.
What if you get hit by a car?
Go home.
Alright.
[Newsstand]
Come here.
Here.
[Newsstand]
Give this
to Li Jiazhen.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
Don't be afraid, it's good.
It's great.
[Newsstand]
Easy.
Batong.
Peng.
I'm calling for the Batong in your house.
Let's pause.
Come here.
Put it here.
In my house,
you have to follow my rules.
Got it?
Weird.
Here you are.
Thanks.
See you soon.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
[Newsstand]
Professor Chen, you're back.
[Entrance] [Exit]
[China Communications Services]
Batong,
my silly son.
You didn't go home?
He got here just now.
What?
He came only a moment ago.
Kept staring at the station.
Let's go.
Go home.
[China Communications Services]
[Yangtze River ropeway]
You want to read it?
You wanna read it too?
Yes?
1000 g of chicken breast.
And?
Pumpkin, carrot and broccoli.
120 g each.
Chen Jingxiu.
You idiot.
What experiment are you doing?
What a mess!
You can't cook even noodles.
Now you're doing something fancy.
Cook us dinner if you're so capable.
Mom, please help him.
That's for Batong.
I don't think he can make it.
It's taken him ages.
In his dreams!
I feed you two beasts every day.
Now I have to feed his dog too?
It's okay for your mom
to cook for people.
It's not okay for your mom
to cook for a dog.
Actually, it's not hard to cook for a dog.
As long as all the ingredients are fresh.
Oh, yeah?
I've got the fighting spirit.
No problem.
Fighting spirit.
It's time.
Hm, smells nice.
Cool it down.
Okay, it's cooled.
Here.
Yummy?
If it's yummy, have some more.
Come on.
Why did you stop eating?
Eat.
Come on, eat.
It should taste okay.
It's not that bad.
Look at how reluctant you are!
Tell you what. You have to eat it.
Professor, is the collar done?
If you don't stop him from eating,
it’ll upset his tummy again.
See what a mess he'll make!
[Email]
[Buddies, Beijing is waiting for you]
Mom, you gave me a fright.
Go enjoy the sun.
You spend all day indoors.
You'll go blind.
I got an email from Beijing.
You've got the offer?
Yes.
I'm going to Beijing.
Batong.
You have an upset tummy. Stop biting it.
Can't the collar stop you?
Stop! Stop!
Batong.
I give up.
Have what Mom cooked.
Batong.
Come.
[Newsstand]
Our stomachs are fine. Take the collar off.
You love your mom's meat balls.
Traitor.
You lost the mahjong game?
We were even.
Didn't I tell you?
The way
you play the game...
You have a fifty-fifty chance
of winning.
It's like flipping a coin.
The more times you throw,
the ratio of head to tail is closer to 50:50.
It's half and half.
If you continue playing like this,
who is the winner?
Whoever lives the longest wins.
You're talking nonsense.
Xinqiao has something to tell you.
Here.
I'm starting a job.
Which company?
State-owned or private?
The friends I mentioned last year.
The web design company is up and running.
It's in Beijing.
How does a web design company make money?
The air is so dry in Beijing.
So cold in winter.
You're not used to the food there.
Can you adjust to it?
Where will you stay?
Dad.
I'm half-Beijingese, right?
After your grandparents died,
we have no family in Beijing.
I've booked the train ticket for tomorrow morning.
I'm full.
Give him some advice.
When you should speak,
you say nothing.
He's bought the train ticket.
What's the point of me saying anything?
Batong, let's go.
Let's take a stroll.
Come.
So, he loves his dog more than me.
Eat.
Then finish packing.
Just do your best.
I thought you'd left when it started raining.
I'm packing up.
Can you vacuum seal it?
How much do you need?
Yes or no? I'm in a hurry. It's raining.
It's in my place.
Do you want to come back with me?
I'll have all the rest.
Okay.
I'll give you a 10% discount.
Hurry up.
It's raining.
[Authentic spicy marinade]
One fifth with no chilies?
No, all with chilies.
Where have you been?
I'd lock you out if you weren't coming back.
What is he doing?
He's chasing the light.
Is he a dog or a cat?
Dogs are like people.
We always head towards light.
So funny.
You're no longer young and you went out in the rain.
You'll catch your death.
Come, take the pills.
The pills will make me too sleepy
to see Xinqiao off tomorrow morning.
Just take them.
Good.
Your mom is treating you so well
that you're allowed on the bed.
Done. Go play.
So annoying.
Off you go.
Batong.
It's eight.
[For hire]
Excuse me, can my dog get in?
Yes.
Get in.
[For hire]
Mister, it's urgent.
I can't wait.
I'll get off here.
[For hire]
Batong, this way.
Attention, passengers.
The T10 train heading west to Beijing
will soon depart.
Passengers for this train
please board now.
Other guests, please stand behind the white security line.
[Chongqing express train to Beijing]
Batong.
Batong!
[Chongqing express train to Beijing]
[Chongqing Station]
[Half a year later]
[Newsstand]
Batong, bring it to Li Jiazhen.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
[Newsstand]
Chen Jingxiu, did you forget something?
I did. I'll be right back.
Look.
What's he doing?
What's happening in the world?
We can’t keep even our dog.
Shh. She's quite pretty.
Batong takes after me.
He loves pretty girls.
You're so annoying.
[Ice jelly, cold shrimp]
You can't be good for nothing.
Two bowls of cold shrimp.
[Ice jelly, cold shrimp]
You want this too?
What's this?
It's celtuce.
This is green pepper.
You can't have it,
it's very spicy.
[Asian Cup Semi-Final - China vs Iran]
[Yangtze River Ropeway Passenger Terminal]
[Service is suspended today due to maintenance]
Maintenance.
[Yangtze River Ropeway Terminal]
Taxi.
Professor.
Time to eat.
Where is Batong?
I didn't see him.
Batong.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
Come here.
My good boy.
It's closed today.
You've waited for so long.
Daddy forgot you today.
I'm sorry.
Come, let's go home.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
Slow down.
Goal!
Batong.
It's a goal!
Keep calm. Now it's down to our goalie.
Batong.
We won!
We're in the finals, you know?
Go! Go! Go!
When will the power be restored?
It's so hot in Chongqing.
How can you bear it?
I forgot to tell you.
There is power rationing today.
No power for a day in this district.
Your Chongqing...
Chongqing offers you food, a place to live and sunshine.
What more do you want?
Even a dog can be family.
Still can't call Chongqing home?
Calm down and you'll feel cool.
I won!
What the hell!
Not again!
Give me the money.
Batong.
It's cool now, isn't it?
You want to bury it?
Here.
Let's do it together.
Let's dig together.
Let's bury it.
Don't worry.
I won't tell anyone.
Shall we mark it?
You can't find it anymore.
It's gone.
Come, let's sit here.
Sit.
Good, let's take a photo.
Don't look at me,
look that way.
Look.
The ready-made dog food is better.
It's convenient
and he loves it too.
Yes.
I don't have to cook for the dog anymore.
No need to cook for people either.
Don't wind yourself up again.
Look, four of us ate together in the past.
Now, it's just us.
You still cook so much food.
No matter how delicious it is, we can't finish it.
Two slices left.
Finish it.
I really can't eat anymore.
How about this?
Leave it in the fridge.
When I come back from my research trip,
put it in the noodles for me.
I can't live without you.
So annoying.
I'm off.
Batong, stay home.
I won't come home tonight.
Keep an eye on him.
Don't let him go to the station.
You're coming back on Wednesday?
Yes.
Bye bye, Batong.
Why did you come?
[Hot water]
You wanna go on the trip with Daddy?
Go home.
[Mineral water, instant noodles]
[Entrance] [Exit]
[Please do not crowd and line up orderly] [Ride civilly, be orderly]
Around 2009,
the water reached 175m high.
[Water hose box]
The communities moved uphill.
People will have moved out of
the places you're seeing now, by then.
[Depot Development and Migration Work Inspection Team]
[Civil behavior, serving the masses]
[Newsstand]
[Public telephone]
Where is Professor Chen?
[Mineral water, instant noodles]
[Public telephone]
I'm off.
Okay.
[Newsstand]
Don't go home for now.
Stay with Mom for a few days.
Wait for me to come home.
Yeah.
Okay.
Your dad took so many photos of you.
But nobody took photos of him.
Batong.
Where is Batong?
Still waiting?
[Newsstand]
[Yangtze River ropeway]
That day...
He came to see me off at the station, right?
I knew.
I knew everything.
[Newsstand]
Look.
Do you like
this color?
[Demolition Notice]
Don't worry. There is enough room.
I rented a bigger place.
There is an elevator, you can move easily.
If you worry you can't play mahjong,
I'll teach you how to play it online.
Okay?
How about Batong?
Are you allowed to keep a dog?
I'll ask again
but I don't think so.
Ming.
Batong.
Batong, come.
He's had breakfast.
Okay.
We're off.
Bye, Mom.
[6 months later]
What is he looking at?
I'll go get breakfast.
It's been sitting there since last night.
What?
Batong.
What are you looking at?
Batong. Why are you here?
Go, now!
They're having a hotpot with dog meat.
[Demolition notice]
Leave, quick.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
We came here earlier today.
Let's check again.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
He's incredible.
Batong.
[Newsstand]
Why did you come here again?
Let's go home.
Go home.
Batong.
Let's go home.
Go home.
Go, Batong.
Good boy.
Come.
Come on, go home.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
Let's go home.
[Newsstand]
Come on, go home.
Go home.
Good boy.
Quick.
Take this.
Okay.
Come on, Batong.
Batong.
Don't tie him too tightly. He's very obedient.
No problem.
Feed him well.
Okay, don't worry.
You can run around in the countryside.
I'm sure you'll like it.
Be good.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
[Mineral water, instant noodles]
Batong.
He's not coming back tonight.
Go home now.
Okay, Batong.
Go home.
Batong, be good.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
What?
What are you doing?
Go away!
[Newsstand]
Wait.
[Roasted Taiwan sausage]
[Newsstand]
We fellow villagers have to look after each other.
Let me know if you get bullied.
You hear me?
[Yangtze River ropeway]
I don't get much work here either.
I want to find something else to do.
Go home and start a restaurant
or sell fruit.
I'm off.
[Yangtze River Ropeway Passenger Terminal is operating normally]
The Yangtze River Ropeway you see here
was built in 1986.
[Convenience kiosk]
It's stayed here since then.
For ten years.
It waits here every day.
Wait a minute.
Your house isn't completely torn down.
Let it show you.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
Not completely torn down?
Mom.
Let's go have a look.
Yifan.
Wait here with Chuanchuan.
Batong.
[Yangtze River ropeway]
Mom, be careful.
Mom, come down, quick.
Come on!
Batong.
Silly boy.
Everyone is gone and you're still waiting.
I'm sorry.
For keeping you waiting for so long.
I'm really sorry.
[Be safe, please do not lean on the door]
[Directed by Xu Ang]
[This film is dedicated to those who spend their lives with us and waiting for us]
♫Please repeat my name softly♫
[Meeting you in the darkest corner]
♫I'll answer you like an adult♫
♫Glad I didn't run too long♫
♫Still living in the small land♫
[Escaping because of the movie]
♫Thinking that the world is equal to you♫
[A new journey]
[Becoming an actor]
♫Please say my name loud and angry♫
♫I'll run away in anger♫
[Rehearsal]
♫If there were no such sounds♫
[You had your own name for the first time]
♫I wouldn't be able to figure it out♫
♫How far a distance would be considered leaving♫
[Practising earnestly with the actors]
♫There are just a few problems that we struggle with♫
♫I used to hide a bottle of emptiness in my bag♫
[Shoot]
♫To send away the white clouds and uncertainty on earth♫
♫Designing the future that's asleep♫
♫I'm glad the embarrassment hit me right in the face♫
♫Made me doubt my existence♫
♫And laughed at the end♫
[He used to be a stray]
[After being adopted, he acted for 10 years]
[After the film wrapped, he retired]
♫Please repeat my name softly♫
[Adoption]
♫I'll answer you like an adult♫
♫Glad I didn't run too long♫
♫Still living in the small land♫
♫Thinking that the world is equal to you♫
[A new life]
♫I used to hide a bottle of emptiness in my bag♫
♫To send away the white clouds and uncertainty on earth♫
[A new home]
♫Designing the future that's asleep♫
[You'll have a new name]
♫I'm glad the embarrassment hit me right in the face♫
[You'll meet someone you love]
♫Made me doubt my existence♫
♫And laughed at the end♫
[You'll stay with them for your whole life]
[We will remember this journey with you]
[Thank you]
♫I will know to remember♫
♫ You are I am your♫
♫You are I am your♫
♫I will know to remember♫
[Thank you]
♫ You are I am your♫
♫I will know to remember♫
♫Please repeat softly♫